{"1088-FIN-DISTRICT": [{"number": 1, "question": "One reason businesses usually are unable to enter into legally binding contracts with minors is because those under the legal age ", "choices": ["A. do not have sufficient funds to make payments.", "B. may not understand the consequences of their actions.", "C. are unable to make basic decisions.", "D. cannot make promises to do something for others."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "May not understand the consequences of their actions. Businesses usually are prevented from entering into legally binding contracts with certain groups of people because these people are not considered to have the capacity to understand the consequences of their actions. One of these groups includes minors, those people under the legal age. In most cases, minors cannot enter into legally binding contracts because they are not old enough to be responsible for the consequences. Minors often have part-time jobs and may have sufficient funds to make payments. Minors are able to make basic decisions, and can promise to do something for others. Therefore, these are not reasons why businesses usually are unable to enter into legally binding contracts with minors. SOURCE: BL:002 SOURCE: McAdams, T., Neslund, N., & Neslund, K. (2007). Law, business, and society (8th ed.) [pp. 210, 222]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 2, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a voluntary debtor-creditor relationship: ", "choices": ["A. Receiving a monetary gift ", "B. Obtaining a loan from a bank ", "C. Requiring specific information", "D. Owing punitive damages"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Obtaining a loan from a bank. The debtor is the individual or business that owes money to another individual or business, which is the creditor. A business that obtains a loan from a bank is entering into a voluntary debtor-creditor relationship. It is voluntary because the business (debtor) is seeking to obtain funds from the bank (creditor) by going through a loan-application process. A monetary gift is given without expectations of repayment. A monetary gift and a request for information are not examples of debtor-creditor relationships. In tort cases, the court can order one party to pay punitive damages to the other party. This is an example of an involuntary debtor-creditor relationship. SOURCE: BL:071 SOURCE: Business Owners Toolkit. (2012, May 24). Understanding the debtor-creditor relationship. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://www.bizfilings.com/toolkit/sbg/run-abusiness/assets/understanding-debtor-creditor-relationship.aspx "}, {"number": 3, "question": "The Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 is legislation that was passed in response to recent ", "choices": ["A. collection activities. ", "B. investment options. ", "C. tax settlements.", "D. accounting scandals."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Accounting scandals. The Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 is federal legislation that was passed in response to recent major corporate and accounting scandals. These scandals include Enron and WorldCom, which resulted in a loss of public trust in current accounting and reporting procedures. The law established new and improved accounting procedures for public companies and accounting firms. The Sarbanes-Oxley Act was not passed in response to recent investment options, tax settlements, or collection activities. SOURCE: BL:133 SOURCE: Rouse, M. (2007, September). Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX). Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://searchcio.techtarget.com/definition/Sarbanes-Oxley-Act "}, {"number": 4, "question": "Which of the following mutual funds is most likely to be tax inefficient: ", "choices": ["A. A fund with a high portfolio turnover rate", "B. A fund with a low portfolio turnover rate", "C. A fund that concentrates on a specialized sector", "D. A fund that attempts to match a broad market index"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "A fund with a high portfolio turnover rate. Regardless of fund type, a fund with a high portfolio rate replaces a high percentage of its investments every year. Every time that the fund sells one item in its portfolio and purchases another, a capital gain or loss is being realized. Because these capital gains or losses occur so frequently, it is difficult for fund investors to successfully time the realizations and manage their overall tax obligations effectively. Specialized sector funds focus on a certain industry, and index funds attempt to match broad market indices. SOURCE: BL:134 SOURCE: Loth, R. (n.d.). Fund I-Q no..5: Portfolio turnover ratio. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://www.investopedia.com/university/quality-mutual-fund/chp7-fund-activity/fund-iq"}, {"number": 5, "question": "Which of the following quality management approaches is often used in the finance industry to sustain regulatory compliance: ", "choices": ["A. Crisis management ", "B. Just-in-Time ", "C. Reassurance", "D. Six Sigma"], "answer": "sp", "reasoning": " 5. D Six Sigma. Aspects of the Six Sigma approach to quality management are applied in the finance industry to sustain regulatory compliance. Specifically, Six Sigma's closed-loop control principles (definemeasure-analyze-improve-control) are often incorporated in compliance processes and procedures. Justin-Time, reassurance, and crisis management are not quality management approaches. SOURCE: CC:003 SOURCE: Oversight Systems, Inc. (2008, August). Turn SOX compliance into cash: Link SarbanesOxley requirements to business improvement. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from hhttp://productdatamanagement.knowledgestorm.com/ksproductdatamgmt/search/viewabstr act/99003/index.jsp Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 11 "}, {"number": 6, "question": "After identifying a potential compliance issue, a virtual auditor should ", "choices": ["A. manually load questionable transactions into a spreadsheet for analysis.", "B. delete all exceptions and questionable transactions from the system.", "C. enter all questionable transactions into the operational financial system.", "D. link all related questionable transactions for further investigation."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Link all related questionable transactions for further investigation. After detecting a potential compliance issue, compliance technology such as a virtual auditor should identify and link all of the questionable transactions and entities that seem to be related in some way. Then, the data can be further analyzed and investigated. Rather than deleting all exceptions and questionable transactions from the system, a virtual auditor should document and link the data. To maintain the integrity of the compliance system, it must function independently of the operational financial system. Questionable transactions should not be entered in the operational system. In fact, data about the questionable transaction probably came from the operational system. While a human auditor might manually load questionable transactions into a spreadsheet for analysis, a virtual, computerized auditor would not need to do so. SOURCE: CC:004 SOURCE: VMWare. (2008). Achieving compliance in a virtualized environment. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://www.vmware.com/files/pdf/technology/compliance_virtualized_environment_wp.pdf "}, {"number": 7, "question": "Which of the following statements contains the most relevant information to include in a business report about the specific market share of computer manufacturers during a particular time frame: ", "choices": ["A. In 2009, Hewett Packard held 29.1 percent of the market share, followed by Dell, which held 21.9\npercent.", "B. In 2009, Hewett Packard shipped more computers than Dell or Apple.", "C. Hewett Packard, Dell, Acer, Toshiba, and Apple sold more computers in 2009 than other\ncomputer manufacturers.", "D. Apple Computers held the fifth highest share of the computer market in 2009."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "In 2009, Hewett Packard held 29.1 percent of the market share, followed by Dell, which held 21.9 percent. This option provides the most detailed information about market share during a specific time frame because it provides specific percentage amounts in relation to one year. The ability to read information and extract the most important facts is an important skill to possess. Businesspeople often need to extract the most important content from various documents and articles to analysis reports, complete projects, and make business decisions. SOURCE: CO:055 SOURCE: Schall, J. (n.d.). Integrating source material. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from https://www.e-education.psu.edu/styleforstudents/c5_p6.html "}, {"number": 8, "question": "Successful communication depends upon the ", "choices": ["A. listener's knowledge of and comfort with the topic.", "B. speaker's ability to speak loudly and the listener's interest in the topic.", "C. speaker and the listener.", "D. speaker's professional qualifications."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Speaker and the listener. Successful communication depends on active participation of the speaker and the listener, each playing a vital role in the process. Communication can take place even if the speaker is not speaking loudly. Communication is not dependent upon the listener's knowledge of or comfort with the topic, nor is it dependent on the speaker's professional qualifications. SOURCE: CO:017 SOURCE: QS LAP 1\u2014Listen Up "}, {"number": 9, "question": "Strategic management is demonstrated in which of the following phrases: ", "choices": ["A. Obtaining funds for business projects ", "B. Recruiting appropriate employees ", "C. Planning and organizing for the future", "D. Regularly updating business processes"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Planning and organizing for the future. Strategic management involves planning and organizing for the future. It does not involve obtaining funds. That is part of financial analysis. Recruiting appropriate employees is part of human-resources management and regularly updating business processes is part of operations. SOURCE: EC:071 SOURCE: EC LAP 19\u2014Strictly Business (Business Activities) "}, {"number": 10, "question": "Which of the following is a legitimate response for an employee to provide to a customer regarding an inquiry about product pricing: ", "choices": ["A. If you can wait a moment, I'll check for the price in the computer.", "B. I'm not sure what the pricing is.", "C. You'll need to contact the appropriate person to get the price.", "D. I'm pretty sure that the item costs $39.65."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "If you can wait a moment, I'll check for the price in the computer. Businesses receive inquiries from customers on a regular basis. In some situations, an employee may not know the answer to a customer's question. To provide good customer service, the employee should take the appropriate steps to obtain the requested information. This may involve verifying the price in the computer system or transferring a customer's telephone call to the sales department. Guessing the price, stating that s/he does not know the price, and telling the customer to contact another person are not legitimate responses to inquiries and do not provide customers with good customer service. SOURCE: CO:060 SOURCE: Lesikar, R.V., & Flatley, M.E. (2005). Basic business communication: Skills for empowering the Internet generation (10th ed.) [pp. 119-121]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 12 "}, {"number": 11, "question": "An effective technique to use to clarify information when giving verbal directions involves ", "choices": ["A. speaking in a loud voice. ", "B. taking notes. ", "C. demonstrating a procedure.", "D. limiting questions."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Demonstrating a procedure. If possible, it is always useful to demonstrate a procedure when giving verbal directions. The visual demonstration reinforces the verbal explanation and makes it easier for employees to understand. This might include an actual demonstration, a video of a demonstration, or diagrams that explain the procedure. The goal is to increase understanding, particularly if the directions are detailed, or the procedure is new or complicated. Taking notes often helps employees to understand and follow directions. Speaking in a loud voice will not help to clarify information. It is effective to encourage questions rather than to limit them. SOURCE: CO:083 SOURCE: Bock, W. (2006, September 20). How to give better instructions. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://ezinearticles.com/?How-to-Give-Better-Instructions&id=305933 "}, {"number": 12, "question": "What is the main form of written communication between companies? ", "choices": ["A. Telephone calls ", "B. Memorandums ", "C. Meetings", "D. Business letters"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Business letters. Business letters are the most common form of written communication used by businesses to exchange information with other organizations or with customers. Memorandums are informal letters or notes between a company's employees. They are the main form of written communication within a business. Telephone calls and meetings are not forms of written communication. SOURCE: CO:016 SOURCE: Leskiar, R.V., & Flatley, M.E. (2005). Basic business communication: Skills for empowering the Internet generation (10th ed.) [pp. 94-95]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 13, "question": "Anna, a new employee with Turbo Electronics, must write a letter to a customer. Because Anna does not know which letter format to use, she should ", "choices": ["A. develop the letter in several formats and send the letter that her supervisor likes best.", "B. select the block format because it is the mostly widely used.", "C. select the simplified format because it is impersonal.", "D. ask her supervisor which letter format the company uses."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Ask her supervisor which letter format the company uses. Companies may prefer that their employees format business correspondence in a specific way to ensure consistency within the organization. To save time and effort, Ann should ask her supervisor which letter format the company uses, such as the block format or simplified format. Developing the letter in a variety of formats is an inefficient use of time. SOURCE: CO:088 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. A-10 - A-12]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 14, "question": "Because Caroline does not have enough time to read an entire 400-page business report, what section of the report should she review to obtain an overview of the most important content? ", "choices": ["A. Table of contents ", "B. Executive summary ", "C. Appendices", "D. Conclusions"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Executive summary. The executive summary provides an overview of the entire report and contains the most important information included in the body of the report. When businesspeople have time constraints, they often read the executive summary of a lengthy report. The table of contents is the portion of the report in which the various report sections are listed with their page numbers for easy access. The appendices are segments that are added to the end of the report and provide supporting information. The conclusion section of the report summarizes results and in some reports, this section includes recommendations for a certain course of action. SOURCE: CO:091 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. 456, 461, 474]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 15, "question": "Employees who always keep their commitments to customers are building positive relationships with those customers by being ", "choices": ["A. dependable. ", "B. assertive. ", "C. creative.", "D. sociable."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Dependable. Employees who are dependable do what they say they will do and keep their commitments to customers. When employees offer to do something for customers, they must live up to the terms of the commitment in order to build positive relationships. Customers appreciate dependable employees and often return to a specific business because of them. Assertive employees stand up for their rights. Sociable employees are friendly. Creative employees develop unique ideas and solutions to problems. These are good characteristics for employees to have, but they do not involve keeping commitments. SOURCE: CR:003 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (p. 258). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 13 "}, {"number": 16, "question": "One way to show respect for foreign clients' cultural and social differences is to ", "choices": ["A. always speak in your native language. ", "B. pronounce their names correctly. ", "C. use slang and idioms frequently.", "D. embrace cultural stereotypes."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Pronounce their names correctly. One way to show respect for foreign clients, their families, and their cultures is to learn to say their names properly. If you mispronounce a client's name, you might insult the person or hurt his/her feelings. If you can speak a client's native tongue, converse with that client in her/his language, rather than always speaking in your own native language. Especially if your clients' knowledge of the English language is limited, you should avoid using slang and idioms\u2014your clients may not understand what you really mean by such words and phrases. When communicating with clients of different cultures, do not base your actions on cultural stereotypes. SOURCE: CR:019 SOURCE: Ngomsi, E. (2003-2009). Factors that affect cross-cultural interactions in the workplace. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://www.yan-koloba.com/articles.html "}, {"number": 17, "question": "Whatever action must be taken in handling a customer complaint, the salesperson should respond in a(n) __________ manner. ", "choices": ["A. abrupt ", "B. skeptical ", "C. formal", "D. concerned"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Concerned. The salesperson's concerned attitude should put the customer in a good frame of mind. If a customer complaint is handled improperly, a valuable customer may be lost. If the salesperson is skeptical or abrupt, this may alienate the customer. It is not necessary to respond in a formal manner; however, professionalism is important. SOURCE: CR:010 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 241-242). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 18, "question": "Jonathan, an insurance agent, explains both the pros and cons of his products to all of his customers to help them decide which policies to purchase. Hank, also an insurance agent, explains to his customers why they should purchase his products, but he doesn't talk about anything negative before making a sale. Based on this information, which agent is more likely to retain and grow his client base? ", "choices": ["A. Jonathan, because he gives his customers too much information.", "B. Jonathan, because his customers feel that they can trust him.", "C. Hank, because he doesn't scare his customers away.", "D. Hank, because he is a very optimistic, upbeat person."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Jonathan, because his customers feel that they can trust him. Jonathan educates his customers about his products, explaining the positives as well as the negatives. By doing so, Jonathan presents himself as a truthful, trustworthy individual. Customers are much more likely to return to Jonathan and refer others to him because they see him as a person they can trust. There is no indication that Jonathan provides his customers with too much information. Hank is not likely to retain and grow his client base simply because he is optimistic. And, while customers appreciate an upbeat salesperson, they are likely to get angry with Hank if something goes wrong that Hank could have warned them about. Angry, displeased customers are unlikely to return to Hank or refer others to him in the future. SOURCE: CR:012 SOURCE: Hoffman, K.D., & Bateson, J. (2006). Services marketing: Concepts, strategies, & cases (3rd ed.) [p. 400]. Mason, OH: Thomson South-Western. "}, {"number": 19, "question": "What customer-relationship-management analytic would be most suitable for sorting clients based on how likely they are to repurchase a particular product? ", "choices": ["A. Profitability analysis ", "B. Account personalization ", "C. Event monitoring", "D. Customer segmentation"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Customer segmentation. Customer-relationship-management (CRM) analytics can be used to analyze and evaluate customer data in many different ways. For example, a business can use CRM technology to segment its customers into groupings based on each client's likelihood of purchasing or repurchasing a particular product. Personalization allows a business to market to specific customers based on data in the CRM system. Event monitoring helps businesses to identify when a customer reaches a specific dollar amount of purchasing or requests an excessive number of refunds. Profitability analysis helps businesses to identify their most profitable customers. SOURCE: CR:024 SOURCE: TechTarget. (2007, June 27). CRM analytics. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://searchcrm.techtarget.com/definition/CRM-analytics "}, {"number": 20, "question": "Items that are used to produce goods and services are ", "choices": ["A. economic resources. ", "B. natural resources. ", "C. capital goods.", "D. human resources."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Economic resources. An item becomes an economic resource when it is used to produce a good or a service. Economic resources include natural resources, human resources, and capital goods. SOURCE: EC:003 SOURCE: EC LAP 14\u2014Be Resourceful (Economic Resources) Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 14 "}, {"number": 21, "question": "Which of the following is a component of verbal communication between individuals: ", "choices": ["A. Body posture ", "B. Listening ", "C. Facial expression", "D. Eye contact"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Listening. Listening involves not only hearing what the speaker is saying but making appropriate verbal responses. It is an essential component or part of verbal communication. Facial expressions, eye contact, and body posture are examples of nonverbal communications. SOURCE: CO:147 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 192-193). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 22, "question": "Which of the following elements of a business is not structured by organizational design: ", "choices": ["A. Competitors ", "B. People ", "C. Information", "D. Technology"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Competitors. Organizational design (also called organizational structure) is the process of structuring a business's people, information, and technology to enable the business to achieve its goals and to be successful. A business isn't able to structure its competitors. SOURCE: EC:103 SOURCE: EC LAP 23\u2014Designed to Work (Organizational Design) "}, {"number": 23, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about breaking the law: ", "choices": ["A. It is acceptable in most industries.", "B. It will make a company more popular.", "C. It is necessary for business success.", "D. It may have different consequences than breaching ethics."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "It may have different consequences than breaching ethics. Breaching business ethics and breaking the law may have different consequences. For example, breaching business ethics alone could result in loss of customers, while breaking the law could result in fines or jail time. Both breaching business ethics and breaking the law are unacceptable practices in most industries, are not necessary for business success, and will not make a company more popular. In fact, doing so will hurt a company's public image. SOURCE: EC:106 SOURCE: EC LAP 21\u2014On the Up and Up (Business Ethics) "}, {"number": 24, "question": "A country that has a socialistic command economic system is ", "choices": ["A. Great Britain. ", "B. the United States. ", "C. Switzerland.", "D. Japan."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Great Britain. Socialism is a modified command economic system in which government owns the basic means of production but there is private ownership of businesses as well. Socialism is characterized by freedom of choice, limited competition, high taxes, some government control, and welfare programs for citizens. Japan, Switzerland, and the United States have capitalistic economic systems. SOURCE: EC:007 SOURCE: EC LAP 17\u2014Who's the Boss? (Economic Systems) "}, {"number": 25, "question": "Which of the following is most likely to reduce risk: ", "choices": ["A. Dividends ", "B. Bonds ", "C. Insurance", "D. Stocks"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Insurance. Businesses transfer the risk factor to some other person or business when they purchase insurance. An insurance policy is a contract between a business and an insurance company in which the insurance company agrees to provide protection against insurable losses which may occur. Stocks are shares of ownership in a business. Municipal bonds are sold by municipalities to raise funds for their use. Dividends are monies paid to individuals or companies which own stock in a business. SOURCE: EC:011 SOURCE: EC LAP 3\u2014Lose, Win, or Draw (Business Risk) "}, {"number": 26, "question": "If each citizen in the United States increased the amount s/he spent on U.S. consumer goods, the gross domestic product (GDP) would probably ", "choices": ["A. increase. ", "B. decrease. ", "C. stay the same.", "D. not be affected."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Increase. Personal consumption expenditures, a GDP component, represent all of the consumer goods sold during the year. An increase in the sale of consumer goods will result in an increase in GDP unless there is a drop in one of the other GDP components such as government purchases, private investment, or net exports. SOURCE: EC:017 SOURCE: Pride, W. M., Hughes, R. J., & Kapoor, J. R. (2008). Business (9th ed.) [pp. 19-20]. Boston: Houghton Mifflin. Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15 "}, {"number": 27, "question": "Which of the following is a factor that often enables certain countries to trade successfully with each other: ", "choices": ["A. Equal governmental systems ", "B. Same religious institutions ", "C. Similar business subcultures", "D. Identical language traits"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Similar business subcultures. The business subculture of each country has its own unique beliefs, values, and ways of conducting business. The business subcultures of some countries are very similar to those of other countries. For example, the United States and the United Kingdom have similar business subcultures, which means that the businesspeople in these countries understand each other and conduct business in similar ways. Because of this, they trade successfully with each other. Countries that have different business subcultures may not be able to trade as successfully with each other because their businesspeople have different ways of doing business and may not understand each other as well. Different countries have different language traits, religious institutions, and governmental systems which may make it difficult for them to trade with each other. SOURCE: EC:045 SOURCE: EC LAP 24\u2014On Top of the World (Impact of Culture on the Global Environment) "}, {"number": 28, "question": "Which of the following is a benefit to you as an individual of setting high personal standards for honesty and fairness: ", "choices": ["A. You will not need to be bonded by your employer.", "B. The business will have a good image.", "C. The number of mistakes you make will decrease.", "D. You will have increased self-respect."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "You will have increased self-respect. Knowing that you always try to be honest and fair bolsters your selfrespect. When you respect yourself, it is easier to respect others as well. Having high standards for honesty and fairness will not decrease the number of mistakes you make. If your job involves handling money, the business might choose to bond you to protect itself from possible loss, even though you are honest. Improving the business's image is a benefit to the business. SOURCE: EI:019 SOURCE: EI LAP 3\u2014Opt for Optimism "}, {"number": 29, "question": "How does self-control help you to think clearly? ", "choices": ["A. By helping you to deal with criticism ", "B. By helping you to be defensive ", "C. By helping you to be objective", "D. By helping you to deal with coworkers"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "By helping you to be objective. Self-control helps you to think clearly by enabling you to keep your emotions under control. This helps you to be open-minded and objective. Self-control helps you to deal with criticism without becoming defensive, but that is not part of clear thinking. Self-control helps you to deal with coworkers by helping you to think before you speak. SOURCE: EI:025 SOURCE: EI LAP 14\u2014Control Yourself! (Demonstrating Self-Control) "}, {"number": 30, "question": "Negative feedback makes many individuals uncomfortable because it ", "choices": ["A. is so rare. ", "B. involves so many people. ", "C. points out their shortcomings.", "D. occurs so regularly."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Points out their shortcomings. Negative feedback makes many individuals uncomfortable because it points out their weaknesses, faults, and shortcomings. The frequency of the feedback\u2014whether it occurs regularly or is rare\u2014has little to do with making individuals uncomfortable. Negative feedback should not involve a lot of people. In fact, constructive criticism is best shared in private. SOURCE: EI:003 SOURCE: EI LAP 15\u2014Grin and Bear It (Using Feedback for Personal Growth) "}, {"number": 31, "question": "One of the ways that empathy benefits a business's employees directly is by helping them to ", "choices": ["A. get along with their coworkers. ", "B. focus on people's differences. ", "C. plan effectively for the future.", "D. move quickly up the career ladder."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Get along with their coworkers. Today's workplace is more diversified than ever before. We may not fully understand our coworkers because of the differences in our backgrounds. Empathy helps in this situation because it motivates us to look for similarities instead of focusing on differences. Empathy is not a factor in effective planning or career advancement. SOURCE: EI:030 SOURCE: EI LAP 12\u2014Have a Heart (Empathy) "}, {"number": 32, "question": "Managers are more likely to be able to persuade employees to follow new procedures if the managers have ", "choices": ["A. self-motivation. ", "B. organizational skills. ", "C. enthusiasm.", "D. credibility."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Credibility. Credibility is believability. If employees believe what managers are saying, they are more likely to be persuaded to do what the managers want them to do. Managers develop credibility by always being truthful with employees. As a result, employees often like and trust managers who are credible and, therefore, are willing to follow their instructions. Having organizational skills, enthusiasm, or selfmotivation does not necessarily mean that managers will be able to persuade employees. SOURCE: EI:012 SOURCE: QS LAP 10\u2014Win Them Over Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16 "}, {"number": 33, "question": "Why might group members prefer to use an informal method of consensus building? ", "choices": ["A. Group members wish to avoid arguing. ", "B. The subject matter is controversial. ", "C. It allows for face-to-face interaction.", "D. There is more paperwork involved."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "It allows for face-to-face interaction. Group members might prefer to use an informal method of consensus building because it allows for face-to-face interaction. Some people consider this kind of give and take to be an essential ingredient in successful consensus building. When the subject matter is controversial or when group members wish to avoid arguing, a formal consensus-building method is more appropriate. A formal method also involves more paperwork. SOURCE: EI:011 SOURCE: EI LAP 19\u2014It's a Group Thing (Consensus Building) "}, {"number": 34, "question": "When determining if a personal vision is realistic, a person must determine if the vision will have ", "choices": ["A. permanent results. ", "B. limited resources. ", "C. few setbacks.", "D. measurable goals."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Permanent results. Personal vision is the future that you want to create. It involves creating positive change through hard work over the long term. For example, Martin Luther King, Jr. had a vision in which his children would have equal rights with all Americans. His vision was to end racism, and he took many steps to make his vision come true. Due to his efforts, peoples' attitudes changed and laws were established to protect and ensure all peoples' rights, which created permanent results from his vision. When working toward a personal vision, a person may experience setbacks and challenges, such as limited resources. Not all of the results of visions can be measured because they often affect others on a personal and intangible level. SOURCE: EI:063 SOURCE: QS LAP 11\u2014Picture This! "}, {"number": 35, "question": "Which of the following is the first step in the coaching process: ", "choices": ["A. Identify the problem. ", "B. Get a response. ", "C. Agree on goals.", "D. Plan for improvement."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Identify the problem. Identifying the problem is the first step in the coaching process. You must identify the problem before you can get a response from your coachee, agree on goals, or form a plan for improvement. SOURCE: EI:041 SOURCE: QS LAP 7\u2014Bring Out the Best "}, {"number": 36, "question": "Jeremy is basically healthy, but he works with another employee who suffers from various chronic illnesses. Jeremy and his coworker differ in what way? ", "choices": ["A. Age ", "B. Physical condition ", "C. Ethnic heritage", "D. Education"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Physical condition. Jeremy and his coworker differ in physical condition (their basic health). They may or may not differ in age (the number of years lived), ethnic heritage (cultural background), or education (amount of learning acquired). SOURCE: EI:036 SOURCE: EI LAP 20\u2014Fair and Square (Treat Others Fairly at Work) "}, {"number": 37, "question": "Which of the following is an example of legal tender issued by the federal government: ", "choices": ["A. Bank notes ", "B. Corporate bonds ", "C. Mutual funds", "D. Municipal bonds"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Bank notes. Bank notes are currency. Currency is the paper or metal (coin) money that individuals and businesses use to buy and sell goods and services. Paper money and coins are issued by a country's government. Corporate bonds are bonds issued by corporations to fund operating expenses. A mutual fund is a collection of shareholders' money that is invested by professional fund managers in an assortment of different securities, such as stocks and bonds. A bond is a piece of paper (real or virtual) that says the governing body or corporation will borrow your money at a particular interest rate for a particular period of time. Municipal bonds are issued by local governments. SOURCE: FI:059 SOURCE: McMahon, M. & Harris, B. (2003-2012). What is a bank note? Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://www.wisegeek.com/what-is-a-bank-note.htm "}, {"number": 38, "question": "An amount of money borrowed by an individual or a business simply by signing a promissory note is obtaining a(n) ", "choices": ["A. secured loan. ", "B. regular credit account. ", "C. unsecured loan.", "D. travel and entertainment card."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Unsecured loan. To obtain an unsecured loan, the borrower does not pledge anything s/he owns as security to guarantee that the loan will be repaid. Instead, the borrower signs a written promise to repay the loan. Secured loans require borrowers to guarantee repayment by pledging collateral. Regular credit accounts and travel and entertainment cards are used to purchase goods and services rather than to borrow money. In addition, these credit users agree to the terms for payment, credit limits, and interest as specified by the credit provider. SOURCE: FI:002 SOURCE: FI LAP 2\u2014Give Credit Where Credit is Due (Credit and Its Importance) Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17 "}, {"number": 39, "question": "Brandon is developing a financial plan, and one of his goals is to save enough money to buy a new car in two years. Has Brandon set a SMART goal? ", "choices": ["A. Yes, his goal is time-bounded and measureable.", "B. No, his goal is not attainable or results-oriented.", "C. No, his goal is not specific or measurable.", "D. Yes, his goal is attainable and specific."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "No, his goal is not specific or measurable. A financial goal is a short- or long-term objective that is measured in terms of money. Effective financial goals are SMART goals\u2014specific, measurable, attainable, results-oriented, and time-bounded. The goal is time-bounded because Brandon wants to save money to buy a car two years from now. It is results-oriented because Brandon will have something to show for his effort in two years\u2014a car. However, the goal is not specific or measurable because Brandon has not indicated how much he wants to save for the car. Also, Brandon has not indicated how he plans to save for the car, such as placing 15% of his weekly paycheck in a special savings account. There is not enough information to determine if the goal is attainable because it is not specific. SOURCE: FI:065 SOURCE: QS LAP 31\u2014Set Yourself Up "}, {"number": 40, "question": "When you use money to make money, you are ", "choices": ["A. investing. ", "B. saving. ", "C. rationing.", "D. reimbursing."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Investing. Using money to make money is called investing. Saving is setting aside part of your current income for future use. Rationing is a function of relative prices that determines who gets the goods and services produced\u2014it is determining how scarce resources will be distributed. Reimbursing involves paying back or refunding money that someone has spent. SOURCE: FI:270 SOURCE: QS LAP 30\u2014Supersize Your Money "}, {"number": 41, "question": "Incorrect information on an individual's credit report may hinder his/her ability to ", "choices": ["A. withdraw money from a savings account. ", "B. obtain a bank loan. ", "C. pay monthly credit-card balances.", "D. earn interest on stock holdings."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Obtain a bank loan. Banks obtain credit reports to make decisions about providing loans; therefore, it is important for individuals to periodically review the accuracy of their credit reports. By obtaining copies of their credit reports from an authorized credit agency, individuals can identify problems and take corrective action. Information presented in a credit report does not affect an individual's ability to withdraw money from a savings account, pay monthly credit-card balances, or earn interest on stock holdings. SOURCE: FI:072 SOURCE: Nolo. (2013). Your credit report can make or break your application. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/free-books/renters-rightsbook/chapter1-3.html "}, {"number": 42, "question": "How do finance companies commonly raise capital? ", "choices": ["A. Issuing notes, bonds, and other obligations", "B. Investing funds from premium payments", "C. Investing deposits from savers", "D. Establishing mutual funds and investment banks"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Issuing notes, bonds, and other obligations. Finance companies, also known as credit companies, are a type of financial institution. Finance companies raise capital by issuing notes, bonds, and other obligations. They use this capital to provide loans to businesses and consumers. Insurance companies raise capital by investing funds from premiums and offering loans to clients. Deposit-taking institutions accept funds from savers and use those funds to offer loans to borrowers. Investment institutions, not finance companies, establish mutual funds and investment banks. SOURCE: FI:336 SOURCE: MBA Research and Curriculum Center. (2009). Introduction to finance course guide (pp. 5-19). Columbus, OH: Author. "}, {"number": 43, "question": "Debt markets buy and sell ___________, and equity markets buy and sell _________. ", "choices": ["A. grain, gold ", "B. corporate stock, certificates of deposit ", "C. government bonds, corporate stock", "D. gold, government bonds"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Government bonds, corporate stock. Investors buy debt securities, such as government bonds and certificates of deposit, through debt markets. The issuers of debt securities pay investors at a certain time (maturity date) and at a specific interest rate. All levels of government sell debt securities to fund various projects and initiatives. Equity markets trade financial instruments such as corporate stock through exchanges or over-the-counter markets. The stock does not have a maturity date, and can be bought or sold at any time for a gain or loss. Grain and gold are sold through commodities markets. SOURCE: FI:337 SOURCE: The Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco. (2005, October). What are the differences between debt and equity markets? Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.frbsf.org/education/publications/doctor-econ/2005/october/debt-equity-market Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18 "}, {"number": 44, "question": "A primary advantage to consumers of convergence and consolidation in the finance industry is ", "choices": ["A. guaranteed earnings. ", "B. easier decision making. ", "C. one-stop shopping.", "D. liquid capital."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "One-stop shopping. Convergence is the merging of financial providers from different financial sectors, and consolidation is the merging of financial providers within the same institutional category. An advantage to consumers of the convergence and consolidation in the finance industry is the creation of \"one-stop\" shopping, which reduces the need to go to different financial providers for different financial products. Convergence and consolidation do not always make decision making easier for consumers, nor do they guarantee earnings on their investments. Convergence and consolidation usually provide more liquid capital for the financial institutions rather than for consumers. SOURCE: FI:573 SOURCE: MBAResearch and Curriculum Center. (2009). Introduction to finance course guide (pp. 5-106, 5-107). Columbus, Ohio: Author. "}, {"number": 45, "question": "Which of the following is most likely to have a negative effect on financial markets: ", "choices": ["A. Interest rates fluctuate daily. ", "B. Business expansion slows quickly. ", "C. Unemployment rates stabilize steadily.", "D. Consumer spending increases consistently."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Business expansion slows quickly. Slower business expansion is one factor that indicates an economic recession. When business productivity slows, there is less work for laborers. When there is less work for laborers, businesses tend to lay off employees, causing unemployment rates to rise. Unemployment leads to less consumer spending because the displaced workers do not have income available to buy goods and services, including financial products. Fluctuating interest rates do not always indicate problems with financial markets because slight daily fluctuations are normal. Increased consumer spending usually indicates that the economy is rebounding, that people are working, and that people have more money to invest in the financial markets. SOURCE: FI:574 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 220). South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 46, "question": "Which of the following has accelerated the globalization of financial markets: ", "choices": ["A. A decrease in foreign access to domestic markets", "B. An expansion of protectionism practices", "C. The movement toward fixed exchange rates", "D. The reduction of government regulations"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "The reduction of government regulations. Liberalization and deregulation have enabled capital to flow more freely across national borders. Reducing the limits (e.g., quotas, tariffs) on foreigners' access to domestic markets encourages international investment and trade. Globalization has encouraged the movement toward floating exchange rates. Protectionism refers to government policies that are designed to protect domestic industries and businesses against foreign competition. SOURCE: FI:575 SOURCE: MBAResearch and Curriculum Center. (2009). Introduction to finance course guide (pp. 5-156-5-158). Columbus, OH: Author. "}, {"number": 47, "question": "Marcus wants to invest a portion of his money in long-term securities to finance his son's college education and his own retirement. To help him make the best investment decisions, Marcus should obtain the services of a ", "choices": ["A. credit-union representative. ", "B. loan officer. ", "C. licensed tax accountant.", "D. certified financial planner."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Certified financial planner. Financial planners help clients develop investment plans and prepare for the future. Financial planners recommend and sell financial products such as mutual funds, stocks and bonds, insurance, etc. When selecting a financial planner, it is important to make sure that s/he has the appropriate training and certification to provide financial services. Tax accountants, loan officers, and credit-union representatives do not usually have the credentials to provide in-depth financial advice and select appropriate investments for clients. SOURCE: FI:075 SOURCE: Ryan, J.S. (2010). Managing your personal finances (6th ed.) [p. 251]. Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 48, "question": "What does an income statement show about a company over a period of time? ", "choices": ["A. Liabilities ", "B. Reliability ", "C. Equity", "D. Profitability"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Profitability. The income statement shows a company's profitability over a period of time. Reliability, equity, and liabilities are not part of the income statement. SOURCE: FI:274 SOURCE: QS LAP 36\u2014The Source Is With You Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19 "}, {"number": 49, "question": "While Chase was reviewing his stock performance, he saw that his commodities investment dropped .002 points from Monday's close to Tuesday's close. This drop is called the ", "choices": ["A. net change. ", "B. true value. ", "C. net worth.", "D. true yield."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Net change. Newspapers, business publications, and websites publish a securities or stock table, which is a format used to list stock quotes. The table helps investors monitor the performance of their stocks. The net change is a column in the table that indicates the difference between a stock's closing price and the previous day's price, which may increase or decrease (drop). True value, net worth, and true yield are not terms that describe the difference between a stock's closing price and the previous day's price. SOURCE: FI:275 SOURCE: QS LAP 37\u2014Table Talk (Reading Stock Tables) "}, {"number": 50, "question": "The stock table column that tells you how many shares were traded that day is labeled ", "choices": ["A. DIV. ", "B. NET CHG. ", "C. YLD %.", "D. VOL."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "VOL. VOL is short for Volume (sometimes called Sales). It records how many shares were traded that day. NET CHG stands for Net Change, or the difference between the closing price and the previous day's price. DIV is short for dividend, which is a portion of a company's profits, paid to shareholders each year. YLD% stands for Yield Percentage, which is determined by dividing the dividend into the current stock price. SOURCE: FI:275 SOURCE: QS LAP 37\u2014Table Talk "}, {"number": 51, "question": "An example of an internal financial risk is ", "choices": ["A. consumer buying power. ", "B. foreign exchange rate changes. ", "C. improper budgeting practices.", "D. credit downgrades."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Improper budgeting practices. Financial risks are possible events or situations that directly impact a company's cash flow. In some cases, financial risks prevent a company from having sufficient funds to meet its financial obligations. Improper budgeting practices are an example of an internal financial risk. External financial risks include foreign exchange rate change, consumer buying power, and credit downgrades. SOURCE: FI:084 SOURCE: FI LAP 8\u2014Prepare for the Worst; Expect the Best (Nature of Risk Management) "}, {"number": 52, "question": "Why would a bank examine a business's balance sheet? ", "choices": ["A. To determine whether the company qualifies for additional credit", "B. To determine whether to declare the company bankrupt", "C. To meet its oversight responsibilities of the business community", "D. To recognize its most profitable customers"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "To determine whether the company qualifies for additional credit. By examining the balance sheet, banks determine what a business owns as well as what it owes. If the business does not have sufficient assets, the bank will probably avoid loaning it money. Businesses, not banks, declare themselves in bankruptcy. Banks do not have oversight responsibilities of the business community. A bank would examine a company's income statement to determine profitability. SOURCE: FI:093 SOURCE: AccountingCoach.com (n.d.). Balance sheet. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.accountingcoach.com/online-accounting-course/05Xpg01.html "}, {"number": 53, "question": "What do many businesses develop to encourage ethical behavior in finance? ", "choices": ["A. Penalties ", "B. Punishments ", "C. Sanctions", "D. Standards"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Standards. Ethical standards are unwritten rules that govern your behavior. Many businesses develop ethical standards that they expect employees to follow, particularly in finance. Finance is the process of obtaining funds and using them to achieve the goals of the business. Ethical issues may arise in the process of managing money, and having ethical standards to follow helps employees make the right decisions. There may be consequences for failing to abide by ethical standards, but businesses usually do not develop specific punishments, sanctions, or penalties. SOURCE: FI:355 SOURCE: Megginson, W.L. & Smart, S.B. (2006). Introduction to corporate finance (pp. 31-32). Mason, OH: Thomson South-Western. "}, {"number": 54, "question": "Why it is important for businesses to keep accurate accounts-receivable information? ", "choices": ["A. To evaluate interest rates ", "B. To forecast sales ", "C. To classify stocks", "D. To monitor aging accounts"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To monitor aging accounts. The accounts receivable\u2014all the monies owed to a firm by its customers\u2014 should be monitored carefully because they affect the business's cash flow and its ability to pay its employees and creditors. To collect the monies owed to them, the business should implement follow-up procedures to contact customers with delinquent or aging accounts. Businesses do not monitor accountsreceivable information to forecast sales, classify stocks, or evaluate interest rates. SOURCE: FM:002 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 342). South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20 "}, {"number": 55, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a businessperson exhibiting unethical behavior in relation to a business's financial information: ", "choices": ["A. An auditor verifies the accuracy of a corporation's financial statements.", "B. An unauthorized employee reviews a client's financial information.", "C. A banker requests financial information from a business to process a loan.", "D. A manager examines the business's financial records to develop a budget."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "An unauthorized employee reviews a client's financial information. Businesses have an ethical duty to protect their clients' financial information. Businesses must develop and implement procedures that reduce the risk of theft or unauthorized access to confidential financial information by internal and external sources. Verifying the accuracy of financial statements, requesting financial information to process a loan, and examining financial records to develop a budget are necessary and ethical practices. SOURCE: FM:003 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 339). Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 56, "question": "Why has online technology's use increased in financial-information management? ", "choices": ["A. Recognition that the security of transactions is no longer an issue", "B. Removal of electronic information exchange procedures", "C. Passage of laws that recognize electronic documents as legally binding", "D. Protection of customers' right to privacy"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Passage of laws that recognize electronic documents as legally binding. As businesses have become more comfortable with the use of electronic information, their willingness to accept electronic documents as legally binding contracts has also increased. This has been buoyed by the passage of laws recognizing electronic documents and signatures as legally binding. Electronic information exchange procedures have not been removed. These procedures provide a way for people to exchange information electronically. Security remains an issue for online financial-information management. Although the customers' right to privacy is an issue, it has not contributed to the increased use of online technology in financial-information management. SOURCE: FM:011 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 338-339). South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 57, "question": "What must a business do before deciding which data-mining technique to use? ", "choices": ["A. Filter the raw data ", "B. Acquire the desired results ", "C. Determine the research question", "D. Analyze product usage patterns"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Determine the research question. Data mining is the process of searching computer databases to look for patterns and relationships among data. Businesses use data mining to find answers to questions. For example, a bank might ask the question, \u201cWhich customers tend to visit the bank between noon and 5 p.m. on Tuesdays?\u201d Before the bank can answer this question, it must identify what types of data it will need to answer the question, and then set appropriate computer queries to obtain the data. After determining the research question, the business can filter the data and analyze the results, which may or may not include product usage patterns. The data may or may not provide the results that the business desired. SOURCE: FM:012 SOURCE: Hair, J.F., Bush, R.P., & Ortinau, D.J. (2009). Marketing research in a digital information environment (4th ed.) [pp. 98-100]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. "}, {"number": 58, "question": "Which of the following questions would be the least difficult to answer using data mining techniques: ", "choices": ["A. What makes some customers a better credit risk than others?", "B. When will this customer place his/her next order?", "C. Why did this customer move her/his checking account to another bank?", "D. What product will a particular customer order next?"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "What makes some customers a better credit risk than others? Data mining is frequently used to classify groups of people or things. For example, data mining could help us to understand what makes customers who are a better credit risk different from the customers who are not. However, data mining is not as effective when trying to pinpoint information about one particular customer. Because a customer's decisions are based on many factors that a database cannot capture, it is difficult to determine that specific person's actions. Therefore, a database would not be an efficient tool to use to predict when the customer will place his/her next order, to learn why s/he moved a checking account to another bank, or to determine what product s/he will order next. Probability models are more successful in predicting what a customer will do and why. SOURCE: FM:012 SOURCE: Alter, A. (2007, June 13). What data mining can and can't do. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.cioinsight.com/c/a/Past-News/What-Data-Mining-Can-and-Cant-Do/ "}, {"number": 59, "question": "If you were using a computer spreadsheet to track your small-business's budget, which of the following should you categorize as investment income: ", "choices": ["A. Dividends ", "B. Cash sales ", "C. Credit sales", "D. Interest on debt"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Dividends. A budget is an estimate of income and expense for a specific period of time. Income is the money received by a business from outside sources. Businesses generate income from product sales (cash and credit), interest earned, and investments. Dividends are income earned on stock investments. Interest on debt (e.g., a bank loan) is a business expense. SOURCE: FM:013 SOURCE: Peavler, R. (2009). Business budget worksheet. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://bizfinance.about.com/od/businessbudgeting/a/budget_wksheet.htm Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21 "}, {"number": 60, "question": "Which of the following questions should the user of financial analysis applications be able to answer: ", "choices": ["A. Why are products being added to the company's product mix?", "B. Which projects are business priorities?", "C. What will the company's actual amount of profit margin be next year?", "D. What is the change in the company's liquidity?"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "What is the change in the company's liquidity? By using financial analysis applications, a business gains insight into its financial health, such as the company's liquidity. These applications also are useful in helping to identify trends. The applications cannot accurately forecast a business's actual amount of profit margin; however, they help to identify trends impacting the profit margin. These applications cannot identify project priorities or tell why products are being added to the product mix. They report financial data. SOURCE: FM:014 SOURCE: MicroStrategy.com. (n.d.). Financial analysis. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://latam.microstrategy.com/financial-analysis/ "}, {"number": 61, "question": "The purpose of using the locking function for a database is to ", "choices": ["A. set queries to retrieve data from specific data fields.", "B. allow users to import data from external programs.", "C. develop reports and summarize various data.", "D. ensure that only one person can edit data fields."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Ensure that only one person can edit data fields. Many databases allow users to view the same information at the same time. The locking function prevents more than one person at a time from making changes to the database. The import function allows users to import data from external programs. The primary purpose of the locking function is not to develop reports, summarize data, or set queries. SOURCE: FM:015 SOURCE: Berry, D. (2000-2013). Concurrency control and locking. Retrieved October 30, 2009, from http://www.service-architecture.com/database/articles/concurrency_control_and_locking.html "}, {"number": 62, "question": "Investment firms must accurately report their financial position because ", "choices": ["A. they are trusted to maintain an accurate accounting of people's revenue and expenses.", "B. others rely on the information when making credit and/or investment decisions.", "C. they maintain both brick-and-mortar and virtual businesses for trading.", "D. people know that investment firms would not take advantage of them."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Others rely on the information when making credit and/or investment decisions. It's important for investment firms to share their actual financial situation rather than manipulate the numbers to present the most desired financial situation. Accountants, rather than investment firms, maintain an accurate accounting of people's revenue and expenses. Having both brick-and-mortar and virtual businesses would not impact the accuracy of investment firms' reporting. Unfortunately, most people understand that not all people are honest. Therefore, they need to know enough about investing to make good choices. SOURCE: FM:004 SOURCE: Accounting and Compliance International. (n.d.). Accurate accounting for broker-dealers. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.finraexamsupport.com/accurate-accounting "}, {"number": 63, "question": "Which of the following establishes the guidelines for the way that a publicly owned company reports its financial position: ", "choices": ["A. The federal government ", "B. The board of directors ", "C. The accounting department", "D. The stockholders"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The federal government. Governments require businesses to provide certain types of financial information to regulatory agencies and shareholders. Public corporations are required to provide financial information that has been verified by an independent auditor to shareholders (owners of the company) and prospective investors. The board of directors and the accounting department perform activities to ensure that the corporation is in compliance. SOURCE: FM:004 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 114-115). South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 64, "question": "Which of the following statements regarding accounting and finance is correct: ", "choices": ["A. Accounting is much broader than finance, which focuses on investments.", "B. Accounting focuses on the past, while finance focuses on the future.", "C. Financial managers typically report to the vice president of accounting.", "D. The finance department focuses on assets, while accountants track liabilities."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Accounting focuses on the past, while finance focuses on the future. Accountants are responsible for tracking and analyzing financial transactions to determine a client's or business's financial performance. Individuals in finance use the information that accountants prepare to predict and plan for the future. Finance, which focuses on money and capital markets, investments, and financial management, is broader than accounting. Private accountants typically report to a controller who reports to an executive within the finance department, such as the vice president of finance or chief financial officer. Financial managers and accountants focus on both assets and liabilities, not one or the other. SOURCE: FM:005 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 102-103). South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22 "}, {"number": 65, "question": "What type of accounting system is used for internal decision making, is not governed by generally accepted accounting principles, and emphasizes the future? ", "choices": ["A. Managerial ", "B. Tax ", "C. Financial", "D. Double entry"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Managerial. Managerial accounting systems are used primarily to aid managers with their decision making, planning, and controlling. Businesses are not required by law to have managerial accounting systems; therefore, there is less emphasis on the precision of data. These systems also do not have to meet generally accepted accounting principles. Tax and financial accounting are governed by generally accepted accounting principles, and they emphasize the business's past financial performance. These systems are designed to provide financial information to external audiences. A double entry accounting system is an accounting concept requiring every accounting transaction to be recorded in two accounts: in one, the transaction is a debit, while in the other account, the transaction is a credit. SOURCE: FM:006 SOURCE: Shanker, S. (n.d.). Objectives of internal managerial accounting systems. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/objectives-internal-managerialaccounting-systems-20945.html "}, {"number": 66, "question": "If a trend indicates that a business is making more money, the business is most likely to have identified the trend by comparing its __________ from previous time periods. ", "choices": ["A. advertising budgets ", "B. profitability ratios ", "C. interest rates", "D. payroll records"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Profitability ratios. Profitability ratios measure the business's ability to generate profit. By comparing the profitability ratios from consecutive time periods (e.g., quarterly), the business can determine if it is generating profits. If profits tend to increase, then it is likely that the business is generating more revenue or making money. Advertising budgets, interest rates, and payroll records do not provide information about the business's profitability. SOURCE: FM:008 SOURCE: Peavler, R. (n.d.). What are the five categories of financial ratios and what do they measure? Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://bizfinance.about.com/od/financialratios/f/finratioanal2.htm "}, {"number": 67, "question": "Before approving a loan application, a bank is likely to analyze the applicant's ", "choices": ["A. brand preferences. ", "B. inflation rate. ", "C. debt ratio.", "D. performance goals."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Debt ratio. To reduce the risk of nonpayment or default on a loan, a bank reviews the loan applicant's debt ratio before approving the loan. The debt ratio indicates the applicant's current level of debt in relation to his/her current assets (e.g., income, home). If the applicant has a high level of outstanding debt and few liquid assets, the applicant is more likely to default on the loan. In this situation, the applicant would most likely be denied the loan. The bank may consider the economy's inflation rate in relation to the applicant's debt ratio when evaluating the loan application. The bank is not likely to consider the applicant's brand preferences or performance goals. SOURCE: FM:009 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 266-270). South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 68, "question": "An automotive parts supplier must decide whether to extend a credit line to a new business customer. Before approving or denying credit for the new customer, what should the supplier do? ", "choices": ["A. Analyze the customer's credit application, credit report, bank information, and financial\nstatements", "B. Contact company shareholders and ask for permission to extend credit to the customer", "C. Discuss the customer's request for credit with the supplier's financial accountants", "D. Evaluate the qualifications and work histories of the customer's management team"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Analyze the customer's credit application, credit report, bank information, and financial statements. Businesses commonly analyze their customers' financial information when determining whether or not to extend credit to these customers. At the very least, a business such as the automotive parts supplier should analyze a customer's credit application, credit report, bank information, and financial statements before approving or denying credit for the customer. It is not feasible for the supplier to contact its shareholders and ask for permission to extend credit to its customers. The supplier's financial accountants are not likely to discuss the customer's request for credit; the company's credit analyst(s) would make the decision. While learning the qualifications and work histories of the customer's management team could be helpful, it is much more important to analyze the customer's financial information prior to approving or denying credit for the customer. SOURCE: FM:009 SOURCE: Dennis, M.C. (2011). Evaluating financial health. Retrieved March 7, 2012, from http://www.encyclopediaofcredit.com/Evaluating-Financial-Health Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23 "}, {"number": 69, "question": "Which of the following sources of financial data might a manager use to analyze expense variances: ", "choices": ["A. Cash receipts ", "B. Customer invoices ", "C. Payroll reports", "D. Productivity reports"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Payroll reports. A variance is a discrepancy or difference between what was planned and what actually occurred. Financial managers often use financial data to analyze variances\u2014to determine what caused actual results to differ from the projected results. A manager might analyze expense variances to determine why a business's expenses were either higher or lower than budgeted. Payroll reports indicate the flow of funds out of a firm to its employees. Therefore, payroll reports provide information about a business expense. Customer invoices and cash receipts, on the other hand, focus on company revenue, not expenses. Productivity reports are often used to analyze operational results, but they are seldom used in expense variance analysis. SOURCE: FM:010 SOURCE: Microsoft. (2013). Analyze variance effectively. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://office.microsoft.com/en-us/excel/HA011562881033.aspx "}, {"number": 70, "question": "Making sure a company follows laws and regulations describes the HR management activity of ", "choices": ["A. staffing. ", "B. compliance. ", "C. compensation and benefits.", "D. employee relations."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Compliance. Compliance is an HR management activity that ensures a company is following all applicable laws and regulations. Staffing is an HR management activity that ensures a company has appropriate employees available and ready to work. Compensation and benefits is an HR management activity that ensures a company's employees are paid. Employee relations is an HR management activity that ensures a company's employees have positive working relationships. SOURCE: HR:410 SOURCE: HR LAP 35\u2014People Pusher (Nature of Human Resources Management) "}, {"number": 71, "question": "Businesses should keep promises to customers in both personal interactions with employees and ", "choices": ["A. advertising. ", "B. newspaper articles. ", "C. coworker interactions.", "D. future products."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Advertising. Keeping promises to customers involves both personal interactions and advertising. Companies must make good on their promises, no matter what method they use to make them to their customers. These promises don't usually come from newspaper articles, coworker interactions, or future products. SOURCE: MK:015 SOURCE: MK LAP 2\u2014Act Now (Employee Actions) "}, {"number": 72, "question": "While researching information for a business report, Tara reads the following statement in an online newspaper article: \"Although unemployment has dropped slightly over the past few months, many politicians have indicated that they believe the government has done enough to get our country out of this recession.\" This is an example of information that contains ", "choices": ["A. statistics. ", "B. historical facts. ", "C. criticism.", "D. poll data."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Criticism. When assessing information, it is important to discern fact from opinion and criticism. The example is a statement of disapproval, which is criticism. It is based on opinion or beliefs rather than facts. Facts contain information or data that are indisputable and true. SOURCE: NF:077 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J. V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 17]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 73, "question": "ChemTech International plans to build a new research facility, which is to be completed in two years. As an employee with ChemTech, your supervisor has requested that you produce a detailed document to send to potential vendors and contractors that outlines how they should submit bids to perform work for the new facility. The document is to contain instructions about the type of information the potential vendors should provide in their bids, and the format in which the information should be presented. What type of document are you preparing? ", "choices": ["A. Summary of qualifications ", "B. Request for proposal ", "C. Executive summary", "D. Business plan"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Request for proposal. Complex projects often require the expertise of external resources. Building a new facility requires skills from architects, construction companies, electricians, etc. And because these types of projects are expensive, companies want to obtain bids from the potential vendors or contractors to determine which one is best suited to perform the work. A request for proposal (RFP) is an invitation for potential vendors to present bids to obtain a contract and perform the work. Because the work is complex, the RFP must include specific information and provide detailed instructions about the way the proposal should be written. Often, an RFP will require potential vendors to provide a summary of qualifications as a section of the proposal. A business plan is a company's blueprint for success\u2014its business model. An executive summary is an element of a business plan and provides an overview of the most important information. SOURCE: NF:080 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. 413-414]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24 "}, {"number": 74, "question": "If a company is managing its information effectively, the data should be accurate and ", "choices": ["A. encrypted. ", "B. relevant. ", "C. anonymous.", "D. positive."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Relevant. In order to make business decisions, companies access, store, maintain, and evaluate a variety of information (facts, data). To make appropriate decisions, companies need to make sure the information that they are basing their decisions upon is accurate and relevant. For example, information from an employee's performance review will not help the business determine how to price its products. Information from an anonymous source may be incorrect and could lead to poor decisions and undesirable outcomes. Encryption is the process of transforming information into a secret code so that only the recipient can read it. Not all information needs to be encrypted. While positive information about the company is nice, it is more important that the information is honest, accurate, and relevant. SOURCE: NF:110 SOURCE: Ivancevich, J.M., & Duening, T.N. (2007). Business principles, guidelines, and practices (2nd ed.) [pp. 483-484]. Mason, OH: Thomson. "}, {"number": 75, "question": "JavaScript, BETA, AppleScript, and Ubercode are examples of computer ", "choices": ["A. service providers. ", "B. search engines. ", "C. programming languages.", "D. disk drives."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Programming languages. A computer programming language is the language or code that instructs a computer to carry out specific actions in relation to certain keystrokes. Computer programmers use various types of computer programming languages to develop computer hardware and software programs. Search engines are computer programs that crawl the Web looking for information. Service providers provide access to a service, such as the Internet. A disk drive is a component of a computer that reads data from and writes data to removable computer disks. SOURCE: NF:084 SOURCE: Answers.com. (2013). Programming language. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.answers.com/topic/programming-language# "}, {"number": 76, "question": "An upscale department store tracks customer purchases made with store credit cards and then tailors promotional messages and merchandise offers to specific clients based on their purchases. What software allows the retailer to manage this strategy? ", "choices": ["A. Spreadsheet ", "B. Word processing ", "C. Database", "D. Systems tools"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Database. Database software allows companies to collect, store, and organize customer information. This information can be used to maintain, analyze, and combine customer information in order to send certain messages to specific customers. Spreadsheet and word-processing software do not perform the functions required by the retailer. Systems tools are used to maintain the computer. SOURCE: NF:009 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 658). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 77, "question": "How long are businesses required to keep their records? ", "choices": ["A. On a seasonal basis ", "B. Varies greatly ", "C. Indefinitely", "D. One year"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Varies greatly. The length of time that businesses use and store their records can vary greatly. Some businesses will use certain records indefinitely, while other businesses might maintain information on a seasonal basis or for only one year. The law often determines how long certain records must be maintained. SOURCE: NF:001 SOURCE: Burrow, J.L. (2012). Marketing (3rd ed.) [p. 349]. Mason, OH: South-Western, Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 78, "question": "What type of information should a company's marketing department review to make sure that enough products are available to meet customer demand for an upcoming sales promotion? ", "choices": ["A. Performance ", "B. Financial ", "C. Operations", "D. Inventory"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Inventory. Companies keep many types of records about their various business activities. Management and employees use the records to make decisions about day-to-day and future actions. The goal of a sales promotion is to stimulate short-term sales. A company that is planning a sales promotion featuring specific products needs to make sure that there are enough products available at the right time to meet the anticipated increases in customer demand. By reviewing inventory reports, employees can see how much stock is available and how much they need to order to ensure stock is available during the sales promotion. Accounting, operations, and performance data do not provide enough information to make an informed decision about inventory issues. SOURCE: NF:014 SOURCE: Burrow, J.L. (2006). Marketing (2nd ed.) [pp. 120-121]. Mason, OH: South-Western. Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25 "}, {"number": 79, "question": "Warehousing and shipping methods are operations considerations related to ", "choices": ["A. scheduling. ", "B. logistics. ", "C. maintenance needs.", "D. expense control."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Logistics. Operations are the day-to-day activities for continued business functioning. Logistics refers to the function of operations that manages the flow of goods and services from production to consumption. Logistics includes all the people, information, and processes involved in storing (e.g., type of warehouse) and transporting goods (e.g., shipping method). Scheduling is the production activity that establishes the timetable to be followed in production. Maintenance needs refer to the routine maintenance and repair of business facilities and equipment. The operations function controls many activities within the business, which means that this function encounters a lot of expenses incurred by the business. Therefore, expense control is an important operations activity because it focuses on efficiency and keeping the business's costs low for its day-to-day activities. SOURCE: OP:189 SOURCE: OP LAP 3\u2014Smooth Operations (Nature of Operations) "}, {"number": 80, "question": "What does the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) require all companies to have available for use? ", "choices": ["A. Emergency generator units ", "B. Replacement office equipment ", "C. Adequate first-aid supplies", "D. Back-up power sources"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Adequate first-aid supplies. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) requires companies of all sizes to have adequate first-aid supplies available for use. Employees should find out where these supplies are located before an accident has the chance to happen. It would also be beneficial for employees to know how to use the first-aid supplies. OSHA does not require companies to have back-up power sources, replacement office equipment, or emergency generator units. SOURCE: OP:009 SOURCE: University of Wyoming. (2010, April). First Aid Kit Basics: OSHA 1910.51. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.uwyo.edu/ehs/_files/docs/factsheets/firstaidkitbasics.pdf "}, {"number": 81, "question": "What do you need to identify if there are complicated jobs that members of the group are unable to perform? ", "choices": ["A. Support services ", "B. Alternative tasks ", "C. Technical equipment", "D. Replacement items"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Support services. Support services are the technical or complicated activities that project members cannot do themselves. After you decide what type of additional help you might need to complete the project, you should identify the other people, organizations, and businesses that need to be involved in the project. Maybe you need the help of trained professionals to use complex equipment or different types of transportation. While determining the type of work that needs to be done, you might identify technical equipment. However, it is possible that a member of the group knows how to use this equipment. In many cases, it will not be possible to identify alternative tasks or replacement items. Then, it will be necessary to locate support services. SOURCE: OP:003 SOURCE: QS LAP 19\u2014Get What You Need "}, {"number": 82, "question": "What is an important activity that businesses should include in project planning to improve the chances of the project being successful? ", "choices": ["A. Orientation ", "B. Communication ", "C. Negotiation", "D. Compensation"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Communication. Communication is an exchange of information, which is an important part of project planning. In order for a project to succeed, everyone involved in developing and carrying out the project needs to know the goals, strategies, and expected outcomes of the project. Sufficient information needs to be communicated during all phases of planning in order for those involved to be able to provide input and to perform their assigned tasks. Orientation is job preparation or induction training for new employees. Compensation is wages, incentives, and benefits offered to an employee. Negotiation involves compromise in order to resolve a problem or dispute. SOURCE: OP:001 SOURCE: Portny, S., Mantel, S. J., Meredith, J. R., Shafer, S. M., & Sutton, M. M. (2008). Project management: Planning, scheduling, and controlling projects (p. 357). Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley & Sons. Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26 "}, {"number": 83, "question": "What do managers often use to evaluate project results? ", "choices": ["A. Standards ", "B. Techniques ", "C. Resources", "D. Activities"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Standards. Standards are specifications or statements that are used as a basis for making comparisons or judgments. Managers often use standards as the basis for evaluating project results. For example, one standard might be financial, such as to increase sales by a certain amount. Then, the manager compares the results with the standard to determine if the project was effective. Techniques are methods or activities that might be used to carry out the project. Resources are items that are needed to complete a project. SOURCE: OP:159 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 258). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 84, "question": "An important aspect of a quality culture in the workplace is the belief that ", "choices": ["A. change is unnecessary. ", "B. management has the best ideas. ", "C. there are ways to improve.", "D. individual performance is most important."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "There are ways to improve. When a business has a quality culture, its employees share the common belief that all functions of the business must consistently achieve the established standards of excellence and that employees must continuously look for ways to improve those standards. Employees with a quality-culture mindset are always looking for ways to increase personal work efficiency, streamline processes, maximize creativity, and improve products and customer-service levels. A business with a quality culture believes that each employee has valuable ideas, that changes are necessary for improvement, and that teamwork and cooperation are important for achieving the business's goals. SOURCE: OP:019 SOURCE: Burrow, J.L., & Kleindl, B. (2012). Business management (13th ed.) [p. 99]. Mason, OH: South-Western, Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 85, "question": "Why is it important for a business to keep its selling area neat and clean? ", "choices": ["A. To please vendors ", "B. To satisfy inspectors ", "C. To attract customers", "D. To interest employees"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To attract customers. Customers usually prefer to shop at businesses that are clean and neat. Keeping the selling area in good condition promotes an image that appeals to customers and encourages them to buy. Customers are more likely to be attracted to clean businesses, which often leads to an increase in sales. Businesses do not keep their selling areas neat and clean in order to satisfy inspectors, please vendors, or interest employees. SOURCE: OP:032 SOURCE: Berman, B., & Evans, J.R. (2013). Retail management: A strategic approach (12th ed.) [p. 328]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Education, Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 86, "question": "A man comes to pick up his order at the office where Courtney works. When she tells him his order hasn't arrived yet, he seems a little upset. She asks for his order number again so she can double-check it and find out where it is. Which step of the seven-step problem-solving method does this situation illustrate? ", "choices": ["A. State and check assumptions ", "B. Collect information ", "C. Define the problem", "D. Evaluate the solution"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Collect information. Courtney is collecting information about the man's order so she can find out why it hasn't arrived on time. The problem has already been defined\u2014the man's order is missing. Courtney isn't stating assumptions by asking for this information. And she can't evaluate the solution yet because she hasn't chosen one at this point. SOURCE: PD:077 SOURCE: PD LAP 17\u2014No Problem (Problem Solving) "}, {"number": 87, "question": "To allow your ideas to flow freely when trying to be creative, you should avoid being ", "choices": ["A. determined. ", "B. independent. ", "C. self-critical.", "D. curious."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Self-critical. Few things stop creativity like criticism. Censoring your ideas limits the number of ideas you have and often limits the quality of those that do appear. Independence, curiosity, and determination are traits that creative people often have in common. SOURCE: PD:012 SOURCE: Rieck, D. (n.d.). 8 bad habits that crush your creativity and stifle your success. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.copyblogger.com/creativity-killers/ "}, {"number": 88, "question": "Which of the following items might show up on a daily \"to-do\" list: ", "choices": ["A. Marketing department meeting at 1:30 ", "B. Research at least five career paths ", "C. Move to New York City", "D. Read 20 articles in BusinessWeek"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Marketing department meeting at 1:30. A marketing department meeting at 1:30 is an item that belongs on a daily \"to-do\" list. Researching five career paths and reading 20 articles from BusinessWeek are items that belong on a weekly or monthly \"to-do\" list. Moving to New York City is a goal, not an item for a \"to-do\" list. SOURCE: PD:019 SOURCE: PD LAP 1\u2014About Time (Time Management) Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27 "}, {"number": 89, "question": "Which of the following is a technique for effectively beginning an employment interview: ", "choices": ["A. Give name clearly ", "B. Tell a joke ", "C. Speak loudly", "D. Take the initiative"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Give name clearly. Effectively beginning the interview is very important because first impressions are often long-lasting. One technique for getting off to a good start is to smile and give your name clearly when you greet the interviewer. This sends a positive signal to the interviewer and creates a good impression. It is inappropriate to tell jokes because the applicant probably does not know the interviewer personally. Interviewees should speak in a normal tone of voice. The interviewer should take the initiative. SOURCE: PD:028 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 136-137). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 90, "question": "Under which of the following circumstances is it appropriate for applicants to prepare interview follow-up letters: ", "choices": ["A. Before they agree to pre-employment testing", "B. When they are no longer interested in the job", "C. After they have submitted application forms", "D. In order to send information with r\u00e9sum\u00e9s"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "When they are no longer interested in the job. One of the reasons for sending follow-up letters is to be courteous and thank interviewers for their time. Applicants who have interviewed with a business should send follow-up letters even if they are no longer interested in the job, because that will help to build a positive relationship. At some point in the future, applicants may want to be considered for other positions with that company, and their courteous behavior in the past will be remembered. Follow-up letters are not submitted with application forms, sent with r\u00e9sum\u00e9s, or before agreeing to pre-employment testing. SOURCE: PD:029 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed) [pp. 71-72]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 91, "question": "Which of the following is usually the most effective way of developing career opportunities: ", "choices": ["A. Interviewing ", "B. Networking ", "C. Mentoring", "D. Counseling"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Networking. Networking involves communicating with all of the people an individual knows who might be able to help with career opportunities. Research indicates that more people get jobs and advance in their careers through networking than through any other way of finding employment. Individuals who network regularly often are able to obtain the positions they want and move up the career ladder. Counseling is an oral communication method in which a supervisor and an employee discuss the employee's problem, and the supervisor tries to motivate the employee to find a solution. Interviewing involves meeting with a prospective employer in the anticipation of being offered a position. Mentoring involves an experienced worker acting as a guide to new employees. SOURCE: PD:037 SOURCE: Wallace, H.R., & Masters, L.A. (2006). Personal development for life & work (9th ed.) [p. 419]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 92, "question": "Which of the following jobs involves determining the value of property: ", "choices": ["A. Real estate appraiser ", "B. Underwriter ", "C. Real estate agent", "D. Actuary"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Real estate appraiser. A real estate appraiser determines the value of a specific property. A real estate agent or broker assists buyers and sellers in the process of purchasing or selling property. An underwriter works in the insurance industry and calculates the risk of loss, establishes premium rates, and designs policies to cover risk. An actuary assesses risk using statistical analysis. SOURCE: PD:152 SOURCE: QS LAP 51\u2014Careers in the Money (Careers in Financial Services) "}, {"number": 93, "question": "If you wanted to pursue a career that specializes in helping corporations and governments issue securities, you would work in ", "choices": ["A. a brokerage house. ", "B. a stock exchange. ", "C. investment banking.", "D. financial planning."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Investment banking. Investment banks trade securities, help businesses and governments issue securities, and handle the financial side of mergers and acquisitions. Financial planners help individuals make financial and investment decisions. They may also buy and sell certain financial products, such as securities, retirement plans, and insurance policies. A brokerage house is the most common type of firm that specializes in trading securities for clients. A stock exchange is where security trading is conducted by professional stockbrokers. SOURCE: PD:152 SOURCE: QS LAP 51\u2014Careers in the Money Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28 "}, {"number": 94, "question": "A primary aspect of Bridget's job is to evaluate her company's internal financial information and the external factors that affect the company's financial well-being. Bridget synthesizes her findings and makes financial recommendations to the company's officers. Which of the following certifications is Bridget most likely to have: ", "choices": ["A. Chartered Life Underwriter (CLU) ", "B. Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) ", "C. Certified Loan Officer (CLO)", "D. Certified Annuity Specialist (CAS)"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA). Finance professionals can enhance their professional standing and career-advancement opportunities by obtaining various certifications and licensures. The CFA certification is a comprehensive certification that requires participants to pass three levels of exams. The CFA certification is beneficial to finance professionals who focus on the long-range financial well-being of businesses and organizations. Insurance underwriters obtain the Chartered Life Underwriter (CLU) certification. Loan officers obtain a CLO certification. Finance professionals who specialize in annuities obtain the Certified Annuity Specialist (CAS) certification. SOURCE: PD:082 SOURCE: Kolakowski, M. (n.d.). CFA: Chartered Financial Analyst. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://financecareers.about.com/od/cfa/a/cfa.htm "}, {"number": 95, "question": "Which of the following provides an opportunity for building professional, finance-oriented relationships: ", "choices": ["A. Market segmentation ", "B. Product development ", "C. Brainstorming", "D. Networking"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Networking. Networking is the exchange of information with others for the purpose of professional or business development or advancement. Because the financial-services marketplace is very competitive, financial-services professionals and businesses need to communicate with other individuals and businesses to build clientele and promote their products. By participating in groups and speaking with other professionals, financial-services professionals can build new business relationships, obtain referrals, and acquire leads to increase clientele. Product development is the process of creating new goods and services. Brainstorming is a creative-thinking technique. Market segmentation is dividing a large market into small markets. SOURCE: PD:153 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Entering the world of work (p. 186). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 96, "question": "How do ethics relate to risk management? ", "choices": ["A. Risk management is insurance for lapses in business ethics.", "B. Risk management is all about the ethical treatment of customers.", "C. The best form of risk management is adherence to business ethics.", "D. The best form of business ethics is risk management."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "The best form of risk management is adherence to business ethics. Every breach of business ethics represents a potential risk for businesses. The best thing businesses can do to overcome most risks is to do the right thing\u2014practice business ethics. Risk management includes the ethical treatment of customers as well as a variety of other factors. Insurance is one way to overcome business risks; however, risk management is much more than insurance. SOURCE: RM:041 SOURCE: Lawrence, M. (n.d.). Business ethics as risk management. Retrieved November 14, 2011, from http://www.allbusiness.com/finance/insurance-risk-management/577644-1.html "}, {"number": 97, "question": "Which of the following is a method that businesses use to reduce the risk of unauthorized access to confidential computer data: ", "choices": ["A. Groupware applications ", "B. Decryption software ", "C. Passwords", "D. Spooling"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Passwords. Businesses must take precautions to secure their confidential information. To reduce the risk of unauthorized access to confidential information, businesses often assign computer passwords to allow authorized employees to view secured information. This reduces the risk of confidential information getting into the wrong hands. Encryption, rather than decryption, is a way to protect information. Encryption is the process of transforming information into a secret code so that unauthorized users are not able to read it. Groupware applications are software programs that allow several computer users to access the same information from different locations. Spooling is the process of transferring computer data to a temporary location so the data can be retrieved and processed through a different computer program. SOURCE: RM:042 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 358-359). South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1088 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29 "}, {"number": 98, "question": "Which of the following is a risk associated with management's failure to follow business regulations: ", "choices": ["A. Effective reporting methods ", "B. Lower insurance premiums ", "C. Expected customer-satisfaction levels", "D. Financial losses in relation to lawsuits"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Financial losses in relation to lawsuits. Risk management is a business activity that involves the planning, controlling, preventing, and procedures to limit business losses. An important aspect of risk management involves complying with laws. If a business does not comply with laws, then it may face a lawsuit. If the business loses the lawsuit, it may be required to pay money to the plaintiff. For example, if an employee is severely injured on the job, s/he might decide to file a lawsuit against the business for negligent behavior. If the court finds that the business acted negligently because it didn't follow safety regulations, then the business may be required to pay the employee, which is costly to the business. Acquiring insurance that offers lower premiums saves the business money and is not always related to business regulations. Customer-satisfaction levels are not always related to the business's compliance issues. Businesses that develop and implement effective reporting methods can minimize their risk in relation to compliance. SOURCE: RM:043 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., Thill, J. V., & Mescon, M.H. (2007). Excellence in business (3rd ed.) [pp. 524-526, A-13]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 99, "question": "What can businesses do to reduce risks associated with noncompliance? ", "choices": ["A. Allocate operating funds ", "B. Evaluate competitors ", "C. Obtain customer feedback", "D. Monitor regulations"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Monitor regulations. Risk management is a business activity that involves the planning, controlling, preventing, and procedures to limit business losses. If a business does not comply with laws, the government may fine the business, which could result in substantial financial losses. Therefore, it is important for a business to continuously monitor government regulations to ensure that it is in compliance, and make changes, if necessary, to become compliant. Evaluating competitors, obtaining customer feedback and allocating operating funds are not actions that will reduce risks associated with noncompliance. SOURCE: RM:043 SOURCE: BankersOnline.com. (n.d.). Compliance risk. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.bankersonline.com/tools/riskmgt_compliancerisk.doc "}, {"number": 100, "question": "Why is the choice of a risk measure for internal and external risk of great practical importance? ", "choices": ["A. It determines the minimum reserve requirements in financial trading.", "B. It determines the maximum number of clients that can be served effectively by a financial\ninstitution.", "C. It identifies the types of risks that the financial institution will encounter.", "D. It designates the audience that will receive the resulting financial reports."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "It determines the minimum reserve requirements in financial trading. Different measures can result in a lower or higher minimum reserve requirement, which results in a lower or higher profit for the financial institution. Although it does not designate the audience that will receive the resulting financial reports, some financial measures should be used for internal purposes while other measures are more appropriate for external audiences. The number of clients to serve and the types of risks to be encountered are not aspects of selecting a risk measure. SOURCE: RM:058 SOURCE: Eling, M. & Tibiletti, L. (2008, August 20). Internal vs. external risk measures: How capital requirements differ in practice. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://web.econ.unito.it/tibiletti/docs/TCM-TCE%202008-08-20.pd"}], "1123-FIN": [{"number": 1, "question": "Which of the following is a type of intangible business property that is protected by law: ", "choices": ["A. Equipment", "B. Inventory", "C. Acreage", "D. Trademark"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Trademark. A trademark is a symbol, design, or word used by a business to identify a good or service and is registered with the government to prevent its use by others. A trademark is an example of intangible business property. Federal law protects a business's intangible property from being used by competitors. A business's inventory, acreage, and equipment are types of tangible property. SOURCE: BL:001 SOURCE: Beatty, J.F., & Samuelson, S.S. (2008). Essentials of business law (3rd ed.) [pp. 797-799]. Mason, OH: Thomson/South-Western. "}, {"number": 2, "question": "When filing a tort against a business, the plaintiff must establish that the defendant ", "choices": ["A. damaged property intentionally.", "B. breached the duty of care.", "C. conspired with a competitor.", "D. violated the doctrine of sovereign immunity."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Breached the duty of care. The duty of care is the basic principle that expects all individuals and businesses to exhibit socially responsible behavior by using caution to prevent harm and by watching out for one another. A tort is a private wrongdoing that potentially harms another person or entity. If a business or one of its employees breaches the duty of care, the business may be held liable for the tort. However, the plaintiff must have grounds or proof that establishes that the business or its employee (defendant) has committed a wrongful act, thereby breaching the duty of care. Intentional damage and conspiring with a competitor (collusion) are types of torts. The doctrine of sovereign immunity is the universally accepted principle that each nation has the right to manage its own government and develop its own laws. SOURCE: BL:069 SOURCE: McAdams, T., Neslund, N., & Neslund, K. (2007). Law, business, and society (8th ed.) [pp. 259-260]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 3, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a voluntary debtor-creditor relationship: ", "choices": ["A. Requiring specific information", "B. Receiving a monetary gift", "C. Obtaining a loan from a bank", "D. Owing punitive damages"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Obtaining a loan from a bank. The debtor is the individual or business that owes money to another individual or business, which is the creditor. A business that obtains a loan from a bank is entering into a voluntary debtor-creditor relationship. It is voluntary because the business (debtor) is seeking to obtain funds from the bank (creditor) by going through a loan-application process. A monetary gift is given without expectations of repayment. A monetary gift and a request for information are not examples of debtor-creditor relationships. In tort cases, the court can order one party to pay punitive damages to the other party. This is an example of an involuntary debtor-creditor relationship. SOURCE: BL:071 SOURCE: Business Owners Toolkit. (2012, May 24). Understanding the debtor-creditor relationship. Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://www.bizfilings.com/toolkit/sbg/run-abusiness/assets/understanding-debtor-creditor-relationship.aspx "}, {"number": 4, "question": "Chris purchased 500 shares of microcap HRR stock. Then, he posted false information about HRR on several investment websites to hype up the stock. After driving up the price of HRR stock, Chris quickly sold all of his stock in the company and earned a large profit. The price of the stock then fell, leaving HRR investors with worthless stock. What type of investment scam did Chris commit? ", "choices": ["A. Phishing", "B. Pyramid scheme", "C. Ponzi scheme", "D. Pump and dump"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Pump and dump. Pump and dump is an investment scam that takes place mostly online. It typically involves scammers who buy a small stock and then hype it up to other investors, causing its price to rise. The scammers sell when the price is high, leaving the victims to deal with the rapid price decline afterwards. A pyramid scheme is an illegal form of multi-level marketing in which emphasis is placed on collecting initial fees from as many people as possible. A Ponzi scheme is an investment scam that lures in new investors by promising high rates of return with little to no risk. Phishing is an online identity-theft scam that fools its victims into believing they are submitting sensitive, personal information (such as credit card numbers or bank passwords) to a legitimate website. SOURCE: BL:133 SOURCE: QS LAP 50\u2014Play by the Rules (Legal and Ethical Aspects of the Stock Market) "}, {"number": 5, "question": "Which of the following statements best describes the taxation of Roth IRAs: ", "choices": ["A. Contributions and withdrawals during retirement are both taxed.", "B. Contributions are tax deductible, but withdrawals during retirement are taxed.", "C. Contributions are taxed, but withdrawals during retirement are not.", "D. Contributions and withdrawals during retirement are tax deductible."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Contributions are taxed, but withdrawals during retirement are not. Contributions paid into Roth Individual Retirement Accounts (IRAs) are taxed. But, earnings on the growing funds in the account and withdrawals during retirement are tax-free. Unlike Roth IRAs, contributions to traditional IRAs are tax deductible, but investors must pay taxes on the withdrawals they make from these accounts during retirement. SOURCE: BL:134 SOURCE: CNN Money. (2015). How is a Roth IRA different from a regular IRA? Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://money.cnn.com/retirement/guide/IRA_Roth.moneymag/index2.htm Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15 "}, {"number": 6, "question": "Compliance in the finance industry involves financial institutions operating within ", "choices": ["A. specific territories.", "B. regulatory guidelines.", "C. organizational plans.", "D. different relationships."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Regulatory guidelines. Financial institutions are required to follow governmental rules and regulations. Following these regulatory guidelines is the process of compliance. The purpose of compliance is to make the industry safe for consumers and to maintain the stability of the financial system. Compliance does not involve operating within specific territories, organization plans, or different relationships. SOURCE: BL:148 SOURCE: Adshead, A. (2014, May). Principles of compliance in the financial services. Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://www.computerweekly.com/feature/Principles-of-compliancein-the-financial-services-industry "}, {"number": 7, "question": "In general, a governance, risk, and compliance (GRC) software system identifies and measures risk; monitors the risk-management system; routinely checks adherence to company-wide policies; and ensures compliance with ", "choices": ["A. reporting requirements.", "B. union demands.", "C. product standards.", "D. contingency plans."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Reporting requirements. Demand for governance, risk, and compliance (GRC) software systems has grown significantly in recent years. Although GRC software can be customized to better meet individual business needs, it serves four basic functions. It identifies and measures corporate risk levels; monitors the risk-management system; checks to see that employees are adhering to company-wide policies; and ensures compliance with reporting requirements enforced by federal and state government agencies and other regulatory commissions. It is not designed to ensure compliance with union demands, product standards, or contingency plans. SOURCE: BL:149 SOURCE: Bamberger, K.A. (2010, March). Technologies of compliance: Risk and regulation in a digital age. Texas Law Review, 88(4), 669-739. Retrieved from http://scholarship.law.berkeley.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2665&context=facpubs "}, {"number": 8, "question": "While conducting a staff meeting, the speaker noticed that Colin was texting on his smartphone. Colin's nonverbal behavior indicates that he was ", "choices": ["A. distracted.", "B. annoyed.", "C. listening to the speaker.", "D. interested in the topic."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Distracted. Nonverbal cues are the elements of communication that involve gestures and facial expressions rather than words. Nonverbal cues often express what the senders and recipients think about their messages. If Colin was interested in the meeting topic or was listening to the speaker, he would be directing his attention to the speaker. Since Colin was looking at his phone and texting, he was distracted and was probably not paying attention to what the speaker was saying. The speaker likely felt that Colin's nonverbal behavior was rude and inconsiderate. There is not enough information to determine if Colin was annoyed. SOURCE: CO:059 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. 54-57]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 9, "question": "Before DiAnn presents her new idea to her boss, she searches the Internet and jots down two statistics that reinforce the idea. This is an example of ", "choices": ["A. obtaining primary information.", "B. supporting ideas with evidence.", "C. giving alternative ideas.", "D. clarifying a new idea."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Supporting ideas with evidence. Ideas that are evidence-based are more easily accepted than those that are not. Primary information is new information collected for the issue at hand. DiAnn is collecting secondary information, which involves obtaining information that has already been collected by others. The evidence does not create alternative ideas. It is meant to add validation to the original idea. Clarifying an idea involves explaining it in more detail. SOURCE: CO:061 SOURCE: The Writing Center, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. (2000-2014). Evidence. Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://writingcenter.unc.edu/handouts/evidence/ "}, {"number": 10, "question": "At work, Bob is assigned to be on a team of five people that will create a new product. Which action can Bob take to participate in the team in a useful way? ", "choices": ["A. Keep the group on track by stopping others from offering unusual ideas", "B. Encourage the team to avoid setting ground rules", "C. Find out what other people in the group know about the product", "D. Walk around the room during discussions to keep energy in the group"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Find out what other people in the group know about the product. Starting a meeting by learning about others' knowledge of the subject identifies what your team knows\u2014as well as areas where more work will be needed. Some ground rules are needed to let everyone know how the group operates. Otherwise, unacceptable behavior may occur. Unusual ideas should not be avoided. Often these are the breakthroughs that lead to success. Bob should use good listening skills, including making eye contact and using other nonverbal cues, to let others in the group know he is listening. SOURCE: CO:053 SOURCE: QS LAP 29\u2014Put in Your Two Cents (Participating in Group Discussion) Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16 "}, {"number": 11, "question": "Alma is preparing a presentation about her department's budget to make to the company president. She wants to use a visual representation of the budget that shows parts in relation to the whole. Alma should consider using a ", "choices": ["A. table.", "B. pie chart.", "C. line graph.", "D. bar graph."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Pie chart. If Alma wants to illustrate her budget by showing parts in relation to the whole, she should use a pie chart. A table is a visual way of displaying information in rows and columns. A bar graph shows values across categories. Line graphs usually depict information over time. Although Alma might want to use these types of graphics for other parts of her presentation, the pie chart is the best way to show how the parts of her budget add up to form the whole. SOURCE: CO:087 SOURCE: Cothran, H.M. (n.d.). Business retention and expansion (BRE) programs: Preparing a written report of survey findings and recommendations (FE657). Gainesville: University of Florida Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences. Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://edis.ifas.ufl.edu/fe657 "}, {"number": 12, "question": "What type of letter should a business include when sending copies of a contract to a vendor? ", "choices": ["A. Request", "B. Acknowledgment", "C. Claim", "D. Transmittal"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Transmittal. A transmittal letter should always accompany important business papers, such as contracts, that are sent by mail. The purpose of the transmittal letter is to let the recipient know exactly what should be contained in the package and if the recipient needs to take any action. A transmittal letter accompanying contracts should indicate how many copies are included and if the recipient needs to sign and return a copy. An acknowledgment letter acknowledges the receipt of business papers. A claim letter requests a solution to a problem. A request letter asks for information. SOURCE: CO:133 SOURCE: Sessoms, G. (2015). What is a letter of transmittal? Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://work.chron.com/letter-transmittal-6249.html "}, {"number": 13, "question": "Identify the type of appeal used in the following persuasive message: \"This new book is written by Dr. Juliet Browne, who holds a doctorate from the Harvard School of Medicine and is the Chair of the World Health Organization.\" ", "choices": ["A. Emotions", "B. Reason", "C. Credibility", "D. Shock value"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Credibility. Credibility is achieved when the audience has confidence in the persuader. In this case, Dr. Browne's prestigious job title and degree lead the audience to believe she is a credible source. Reason is when logic is used to persuade someone to do something. It often involves solid facts and statistics. An emotional appeal affects the audience's feelings, such as sympathy or love. An appeal that uses shock value is a form of an emotional appeal that includes information that the audience would find shocking. SOURCE: CO:031 SOURCE: McIntyre, M. & McKee, J. (n.d.). Ethos. Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://writingcommons.org/index.php/open-text/information-literacy/rhetoricalanalysis/rhetorical-appeals/585-ethos "}, {"number": 14, "question": "What is a type of informal communication that coworkers often use to communicate with each other? ", "choices": ["A. Network", "B. Feedback", "C. Grapevine", "D. Structured"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Grapevine. Grapevine is an oral communication method in which information is passed around the company but not formally announced or verified. Coworkers frequently discuss company issues and pass on information from one department to another through the grapevine. Employees often obtain information and communicate it to others through the grapevine before management makes an official announcement. Feedback is evaluative information given by supervisors to employees. Network is a system of contacts within and outside the organization. Structured is formal communication. SOURCE: CO:014 SOURCE: DuBrin, A. (2009). Essentials of management: Instructor's edition (8th ed.) [pp. 416-417]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 15, "question": "What is one of the benefits to a business of reinforcing service orientation through communication? ", "choices": ["A. Rewards customers for their support", "B. Promotes the sale of new products", "C. Builds positive relationships with customers", "D. Encourages employees to be aggressive"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Builds positive relationships with customers. A service orientation is the business philosophy of providing quality service. One way to do this is to communicate effectively with customers so they trust the business. The benefit of creating trust by providing accurate and credible information is that it tends to build positive relationships with customers. Customers often remain loyal to a business if they have confidence that the business will treat them well and provide quality service. The purpose of reinforcing service orientation through communication is not to promote the sale of new products, reward customers for their support, or encourage employees to be aggressive. SOURCE: CR:005 SOURCE: Weitz, B.A., Castleberry, S.B., & Tanner, J.F. (2007). Selling: Building partnerships (6th ed.) [pp. 40-41]. New York: McGraw-Hill. Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17 "}, {"number": 16, "question": "When Mr. Schwarz's order did not arrive at the expected time, he called Karl, the salesperson with whom he had placed his order. Karl apologized for the delay and told Mr. Schwarz that he would check into the issue. After Karl talked with the transportation company, he immediately called Mr. Schwarz to let him know where the order was and when to expect delivery. Mr. Schwarz thanked Karl for getting back with him so quickly. In this situation, Karl reinforced the company's image by ", "choices": ["A. delegating work tasks.", "B. giving vague answers.", "C. providing efficient follow-up.", "D. complimenting the customer."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Providing efficient follow-up. Customers often base their impressions of a business on the interactions they have with the business's employees. In the situation provided, Karl worked quickly to find out the status of the order and immediately called Mr. Schwarz with specific information about where the order was and when to expect delivery. This is an example of efficient follow-up. By providing efficient service, Karl is building favorable relationships with customers. There is not enough information provided to determine if Karl delegated work tasks to facilitate his follow-up activities or if he complimented Mr. Schwarz. SOURCE: CR:002 SOURCE: Kotler, P., & Armstrong, G. (2008). Principles of marketing (12th ed.) [pp. 244-245]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall. "}, {"number": 17, "question": "What is an important aspect of a customer-centric business? ", "choices": ["A. Reducing the number of touch points with customers", "B. Limiting the employees' decision making", "C. Being satisfied with the status quo", "D. Aligning business activities with customer needs"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Aligning business activities with customer needs. A customer-centric business focuses on customer needs and wants. To focus on the customers' needs and wants, the business must ensure that its business objectives and activities align with its customers' needs and wants. A customer-centric business must continuously improve its processes and products to accommodate its customers' changing needs and wants. The business cannot be satisfied with the status quo. A customer-centric business allows its employees to provide input and make decisions in relation to customer relationships. Touch points are all of the opportunities that businesses have to connect with customers and reinforce their brand value. A customer-centric business is not likely to reduce the number of customer touch points. SOURCE: CR:016 SOURCE: CR LAP 2\u2014Know When to Hold 'Em (Nature of Customer Relationship Management) "}, {"number": 18, "question": "When providing product information to clients, finance professionals should use ", "choices": ["A. standard responses.", "B. technical terms.", "C. financial acronyms.", "D. simple explanations."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Simple explanations. When providing product information to clients, finance professionals should keep the clients' point of view in mind. Clients may not be familiar with finance industry jargon, technical terms, or acronyms. Therefore, finance professionals should use simple, clear language that clients understand. While standard responses are sometimes helpful to finance professionals, it is usually better to keep individual clients in mind when providing product information since different clients are likely to have different knowledge bases. SOURCE: CR:012 SOURCE: Financial Planning Association. (n.d.). A financial professional's guide to working with older clients. Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://assets.aarp.org/www.aarp.org_/articles/money/financial_planning/financial_professiona l.pdf "}, {"number": 19, "question": "Beverly, the new office manager, just completed a review of the last two years of accounts receivable data. In doing so, she discovered that there are erroneous duplicate entries totaling $25,628 in the system. Unfortunately, due to these duplicate entries, collection letters were sent to many customers who had already paid in full\u2014customers who are angry with the company for sending them the letters. What should Beverly do to try to save these customer relationships and ensure that these customers are not bothered in the future? ", "choices": ["A. Contact each customer by phone and apologize", "B. Complete an accounting software update", "C. Complete a data cleansing of the erroneous entries", "D. Use funds from the accounts payable account to pay the debt"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Complete a data cleansing of the erroneous entries. One of the quickest ways for a business to upset its customers is to accuse them of failing to pay their bills\u2014especially when the business has already received payment from them. To ensure that these customers do not receive more erroneous collection letters in the future, Beverly should complete a data cleansing of the erroneous entries, removing them from the system. Completing an accounting software update isn't likely to have an effect on the erroneous entries. While it might be helpful to contact each customer by phone and apologize, Beverly needs to do more than that to ensure that the customers are not bothered in the future. The $25,628 is not a debt. It is the sum total of all the erroneous duplicate entries in the accounts receivable account. SOURCE: CR:024 SOURCE: Cook, R. (n.d). Six steps to improved data quality and more effective marketing. Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://www.crmsearch.com/marketing-data-quality.php "}, {"number": 20, "question": "The process or activity of using goods is called ", "choices": ["A. production.", "B. consumption.", "C. exchange.", "D. distribution."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Consumption. Everyone consumes goods and services to satisfy unlimited wants. Production, exchange, and distribution are other economic activities. Production is the making or producing of goods and services. Exchange involves the exchange of money payments between producers and the owners of resources. Distribution examines how money payments are divided or distributed between resource owners and producers. SOURCE: EC:001 SOURCE: EC LAP 6\u2014Are You Satisfied? (Economics and Economic Activities) Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18 "}, {"number": 21, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a change in the relative price ratio when the original price of red apples is $0.60 per pound and the original price of green apples is $0.80 per pound: ", "choices": ["A. Red apples @ $0.30 per pound; green apples @ $0.40 per pound", "B. Red apples @ $0.90 per pound; green apples @ $0.80 per pound", "C. Red apples @ $0.45 per pound; green apples @ $0.60 per pound", "D. Red apples @ $1.20 per pound; green apples @ $1.60 per pound"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Red apples @ $0.90 per pound; green apples @ $0.80 per pound. This is the only combination that resulted in a change in the relative price ratio. When red apples sold for $0.30 per pound and green apples for $0.40 per pound, the price of each was cut in half, and the ratio remained the same. When red apples sold for $1.20 per pound and green apples for $1.60 per pound, the price of each was doubled and the ratio remained the same. When red apples sold for $0.45 per pound and green apples for $0.60, the price of each was cut one-fourth, and the ratio remained the same. SOURCE: EC:006 SOURCE: EC LAP 12\u2014When More is Less (Functions of Prices) "}, {"number": 22, "question": "Determining what consumers want in order to promote and sell those goods and services is a function of the business activity of ", "choices": ["A. risk management.", "B. quality management.", "C. production.", "D. marketing."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Marketing. Marketing is a primary business activity that involves creating, communicating, and delivering value to customers and managing customer relationships in ways that benefit the organization and its stakeholders. Marketing is an important business activity because it identifies what consumers want and plans how to promote and sell those goods and services to the consumers. Management is the process of planning, organizing, directing, and controlling business activities to achieve objectives. Production is the process or activity of producing goods and services wanted by consumers. Risk management is the business activity that involves the planning, controlling, preventing, and procedures involved in limiting business losses. It optimizes the relationship of potential loss to gain. SOURCE: EC:071 SOURCE: EC LAP 19\u2014Strictly Business (Business Activities) "}, {"number": 23, "question": "Which of the following describes the matrix organizational structure: ", "choices": ["A. It is a combination of two other organizational structures.", "B. It includes only traditional departments, such as sales and marketing.", "C. It is separated by product lines.", "D. It is the oldest organizational structure being used."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "It is a combination of two other organizational structures. The matrix organizational structure is a combination of the functional structure and the divisional structure. It includes traditional departments, but it is also broken down by division (including, but not limited to, product lines). As organizational design goes, it is a newer, rather than older, structure. SOURCE: EC:103 SOURCE: EC LAP 23\u2014Designed to Work (Organizational Design of Businesses) "}, {"number": 24, "question": "Seeing the big picture instead of smaller, individual parts is an organizational learning concept known as ", "choices": ["A. systems thinking.", "B. team learning.", "C. shared organizational vision.", "D. personal mastery."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Systems thinking. Systems thinking is an organizational learning concept that focuses on the big picture rather than seeing smaller, individual parts. Team learning means thinking and working together as a group. Shared organizational vision refers to sharing a mutual commitment to the future the firm seeks to create. Personal mastery is striving for individual learning as a means of advancing the organization. SOURCE: EC:107 SOURCE: EC LAP 25\u2014Keep the Change (Adapting to Markets) "}, {"number": 25, "question": "The general economic growth of a country is supported by its ", "choices": ["A. level of productivity.", "B. standard of living.", "C. gross domestic product.", "D. wealth of goods and services."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Level of productivity. The general economic growth of a country depends upon its level of productivity. For example, the level of productivity in the United States has given the country a wealth of goods and services which allows its citizens to reach a certain standard of living. Gross domestic product is the final, total value of all goods and services produced within a country's geographic boundaries during a year's time. GDP serves as a measure of economic growth. SOURCE: EC:013 SOURCE: EC LAP 18\u2014Make the Most of It (Productivity) "}, {"number": 26, "question": "Colleen will vote next week on the new contract that her union has negotiated with management. Union and management are in the __________ stage of the collective-bargaining process. ", "choices": ["A. contract settlement", "B. ratification of contract", "C. preparation and research", "D. tentative agreement"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Tentative agreement. Tentative agreement is the stage at which union and management have agreed on the terms of a contract but still need union members to approve or reject the contract. Preparation and research occur before labor negotiations begin. A ratified contract is one that union members have approved. Contract settlement occurs when a ratified contract has been signed by union and management. SOURCE: EC:015 SOURCE: Human Resources Department, University of California, Santa Barbara. (2012). What is a tentative agreement or \"T.A.\" in contract negotiations? Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://www.hr.ucsb.edu/what-tentative-agreement-or-ta-contract-negotiations Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19 "}, {"number": 27, "question": "An economy with a high unemployment level tends to have ", "choices": ["A. rapid GDP growth.", "B. a high supply of money.", "C. fewer monetary policies.", "D. a lower rate of inflation."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "A lower rate of inflation. When a lot of people are out of work, they lose their buying power, which means less money is in circulation. Because unemployed people have less disposable income, the demand for goods and services is low, which tends to slow or lower the rate of inflation (rise in prices). The amount of monetary policies that the government establishes does not affect unemployment rates. When the GDP grows, an economic expansion is occurring, which indicates that people and businesses are spending money and the unemployment levels are low. SOURCE: EC:082 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 64-67). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 28, "question": "Jon decided to promote Bill instead of Maggie to regional manager because he thinks that women aren't assertive enough in business situations. Jon is stereotyping on the basis of ", "choices": ["A. age.", "B. ethnicity.", "C. religion.", "D. gender."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Gender. A stereotype is a set image or assumption about a person or thing. When people stereotype others, they tend to classify certain people as a group that possesses certain characteristics. These characteristics are often based on distorted beliefs or unreliable information. A person who stereotypes others often fails to see an individual who possesses unique skills, values, and attitudes. Gender is one characteristic by which people often stereotype others. Assuming men are more assertive than women in business situations is a distorted belief. In fact, many women are very assertive in business situations. Ethnic stereotyping involves having false beliefs about a person on the basis of his/her race or culture. Stereotypes about religion involve having distorted beliefs about a person's spiritual practices. An individual who stereotypes by age might feel that younger people do not possess needed knowledge or that older people are feeble and lack adaptability. SOURCE: EI:017 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed.) [pp. 108-109]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 29, "question": "One way that individuals exhibit self-confidence is by being ", "choices": ["A. creative.", "B. enthusiastic.", "C. emotional.", "D. reserved."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Enthusiastic. Self-confidence is a positive belief in your own talents, skills, and objectives. When people are positive and believe in themselves, they usually are enthusiastic and display great interest or excitement in what they do. Confident people have a good attitude and display that attitude by being enthusiastic. Individuals do not necessarily exhibit self-confidence by being creative, emotional, or reserved. SOURCE: EI:023 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G. (2012). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 127-128). Columbus, OH: McGrawHill Education. "}, {"number": 30, "question": "Maureen becomes angry and defensive whenever her supervisor asks Maureen to correct mistakes. Maureen's attitude is not a good response to criticism because ", "choices": ["A. it indicates that Maureen wants to call attention to herself.", "B. there is no reason to be angry about criticism.", "C. Maureen has no right to be angry on the job.", "D. it prevents Maureen from hearing the criticism clearly."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "It prevents Maureen from hearing the criticism clearly. Defensiveness raises a barrier between you and the speaker. Most of us feel angry or resentful when we are criticized, especially when the criticism is unjust. However, we cannot afford to exhibit this kind of attitude on the job. If Maureen listened with an open mind to the supervisor, she might learn not only how to correct her mistakes but how to avoid the mistakes in the future. Maureen's attitude indicates immaturity rather than a desire to call attention to herself. SOURCE: EI:003 SOURCE: EI LAP 15\u2014Grin and Bear It (Using Feedback for Personal Growth) "}, {"number": 31, "question": "Which of the following is an example of an employee respecting the privacy of a coworker: ", "choices": ["A. Speaking up for a coworker who is being unfairly criticized", "B. Leaving the room when a salesperson takes a telephone call", "C. Giving feedback about a project to a coworker or manager", "D. Answering a coworker's telephone when s/he is at lunch"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Leaving the room when a salesperson takes a telephone call. Successful employees realize the importance of respecting others' privacy in the workplace. When employees respect others' privacy, they are likely to gain the trust and respect of coworkers and managers. An employee who respects others' privacy would leave the room when a coworker (e.g., salesperson) takes a telephone call. Speaking up for a coworker, providing feedback, and answering a coworker's phone call are not necessarily situations in which privacy is being violated; there is not enough information provided to determine if intervention was requested. SOURCE: EI:029 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G. (2012). Succeeding in the world of work (p. 170). Columbus, OH: McGraw-Hill Education. Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20 "}, {"number": 32, "question": "Barry's family is originally from Ireland. Their customs, habits, and traditions are known as their ", "choices": ["A. stereotype.", "B. culture.", "C. diversity.", "D. religion."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Culture. The customs, habits, and traditions of a particular group of people are known as their culture. Stereotypes are set images or assumptions about people or things. Diversity is all the ways in which people differ. Religion is a fundamental set of beliefs. SOURCE: EI:033 SOURCE: EI LAP 11\u2014Getting to Know You (Cultural Sensitivity) "}, {"number": 33, "question": "Insecure people are often afraid to become assertive because they think they will ", "choices": ["A. damage their relationships.", "B. have to please others.", "C. be considered childish.", "D. lose their independence."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Damage their relationships. Insecure people are often anxious about their interpersonal relationships. They are afraid if they become assertive, they may ruin a friendship or end a relationship. Assertiveness is a risk they are unwilling to take. These people are dependent rather than independent and may already be considered childish because of their passive behavior that focuses on pleasing others. SOURCE: EI:008 SOURCE: EI LAP 18\u2014Assert Yourself (Assertiveness) "}, {"number": 34, "question": "Keeping the end goal in mind refers to which standard of excellence that achievement-oriented people set? ", "choices": ["A. Results", "B. Improvement", "C. Trying something new", "D. Competition"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Results. Keeping the end goal in mind refers to being results-oriented, a characteristic of achievementoriented people. They like being able to objectively evaluate their successes. They also value improvement, trying something new, and competition; however, these standards don't necessarily relate to keeping the end goal in mind. SOURCE: EI:027 SOURCE: EI LAP 10\u2014High Hopes (Developing an Achievement Orientation) "}, {"number": 35, "question": "One way a leader can encourage others to work toward a shared vision is by ", "choices": ["A. guaranteeing a profit for the business.", "B. describing the objective.", "C. reviewing the new assignment.", "D. explaining how they will benefit."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Explaining how they will benefit. People tend to work harder to achieve a vision or goal if they understand how they will benefit. Therefore, a leader should explain the benefits they will receive so employees will be encouraged to work toward a shared vision. Simply describing the objective or reviewing the new assignment will not encourage employees to work unless they also understand how they will benefit. Generating a profit is a benefit to the business that will not necessarily encourage employees to work unless they will share in the profit. SOURCE: EI:060 SOURCE: EI LAP 60\u2014Vision Quest (Enlisting Others in Vision) "}, {"number": 36, "question": "Coaching is mostly about ", "choices": ["A. talking.", "B. organizing.", "C. instructing.", "D. listening."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Listening. Coaching is mostly about listening. It isn't really about talking or instructing. Listening is important because coaches must truly understand what the other person is saying and where s/he's coming from. Although organization is certainly helpful, it is not the most important skill in coaching. SOURCE: EI:041 SOURCE: EI LAP 24\u2014Bring Out the Best (Coaching Others) "}, {"number": 37, "question": "Which of the following people would make the best entrepreneur: ", "choices": ["A. A risk-averse person who wants to work 9-to-5", "B. A person who lacks self-confidence", "C. A risk-taker who has a strong work ethic", "D. A person who often works so hard she makes herself sick"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "A risk-taker who has a strong work ethic. Entrepreneurship requires risk-taking, a strong work ethic, and self-confidence. It often requires working much longer hours than 9-to-5. Entrepreneurs must work hard, but they are also in charge of protecting their own health. Getting sick means missing work and losing money. SOURCE: EN:040 SOURCE: Miranda, K. (2015). What do I need to become an entrepreneur? Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/need-become-entrepreneur-2291.html "}, {"number": 38, "question": "When the U.S. federal government owes money to a contracted employee or business, the government must pay the employee or business according to the ", "choices": ["A. Early Bird Act.", "B. Prompt Payment Act.", "C. Secure Contracting Act.", "D. Government Guidelines Act."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Prompt Payment Act. When the U.S. federal government owes money to a contracted employee or business, the government must pay the employee or business according to the Prompt Payment Act. There are no U.S. legal requirements for financial exchange called \"Early Bird,\" \"Secure Contracting,\" or \"Government Guidelines.\" SOURCE: FI:063 SOURCE: Financial Management Service. (n.d.). Prompt payment: Regulations and guidelines. Retrieved September 15, 2015 from http://www.fms.treas.gov/prompt/index.html Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21 "}, {"number": 39, "question": "Financial planning can be described as a way to ", "choices": ["A. retire with a substantial amount of money in the bank.", "B. stop all impulsive purchases.", "C. achieve your professional goals.", "D. realize what it takes to get the things you really want."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Realize what it takes to get the things you really want. Financial planning is a good way to realize what it takes to get the things you really want. It is not a method for stopping all impulsive purchases nor is it a way to achieve your professional goals. And, even the best financial planning can't guarantee you'll retire with a substantial amount of money in the bank. SOURCE: FI:065 SOURCE: QS LAP 31\u2014Set Yourself Up (Setting Financial Goals) "}, {"number": 40, "question": "The key factors involved in compounding growth are the amount of money you invest, how much your investment grows each year, and ", "choices": ["A. your educational background and career.", "B. how you earn the money that you invest.", "C. how long your money is invested.", "D. your mutual fund manager's education."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "How long your money is invested. The most important factors to consider in compounding growth are how much money you invest, how much your investment grows each year, and how long your money is invested. Investing is using money to make money, which means that if you invest money in the stock market, for example, you are likely to make an average of 10 percent each year. As the years pass, your investment will grow tremendously because you will be earning interest on interest. So, it is beneficial to invest for as long as possible to earn the largest amount of compound interest as possible. How you earn the money that you invest, your educational background and career, and your mutual fund manager's education have a much smaller impact on compounding growth than time does. SOURCE: FI:270 SOURCE: QS LAP 30\u2014Supersize Your Money (Need to Save and Invest) "}, {"number": 41, "question": "What is the first step Cameron should take to protect himself from identity theft after he loses his wallet? ", "choices": ["A. Advise the proper law enforcement authorities about the loss", "B. Contact the appropriate government agency to replace the credit cards", "C. Cancel all of his credit and debit cards", "D. Change the passwords for his online banking accounts"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Cancel all of his credit and debit cards. Identity theft occurs when somebody uses another individual's name and personal information (e.g. credit cards) for fraudulent purposes. The first thing Cameron should do when he realizes he has lost his wallet is to cancel his credit cards. By canceling the credit cards, Cameron will protect himself in the event that someone finds his wallet and attempts to use the credit cards. Financial institutions and businesses (e.g., retailers) issue credit cards, not government agencies. Cameron should contact the proper law enforcement authorities (e.g., police) if he thinks his wallet is stolen. He can report a lost wallet, and he can also change the passwords for his online banking accounts. However, the first thing he should do is to cancel his credit and debit cards. SOURCE: FI:073 SOURCE: Federal Trade Commission. (n.d.). Recovering from identity theft is easier with a plan. Retrieved September 10, 2015, from https://www.identitytheft.gov "}, {"number": 42, "question": "Which of the following are examples of deposit-taking financial institutions: ", "choices": ["A. Commercial banks, corporations, and mutual savings banks", "B. Credit unions, savings and loan associations, and commercial banks", "C. Savings and loan associations, mutual savings banks, and insurance firms", "D. Commercial banks, credit unions, and brokerages"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Credit unions, savings and loan associations, and commercial banks. Deposit-taking financial institutions accept funds from customers (depositors) and pay interest on the funds. Credit unions, commercial banks, savings and loan associations (banks), and mutual savings banks are types of deposit-taking financial institutions. A corporation is a form of business ownership that is owned by stockholders who have purchased units or shares of the company. Brokerages are financial intermediaries that sell securities. Insurance firms sell insurance and securities. Corporations, brokerages, and insurance firms are not types of deposit-taking financial institutions. SOURCE: FI:336 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2015). Introduction\u2014types of financial institutions and their roles. Retrieved September 22, 2015, from http://www.investopedia.com/walkthrough/corporatefinance/1/financial-institutions.aspx "}, {"number": 43, "question": "If Hannah wants to invest in the capital markets, what types of securities should she purchase? ", "choices": ["A. Corporate bonds and treasury bills", "B. Common stock and certificates of deposit", "C. Treasury bills and certificates of deposit", "D. Corporate bonds and preferred stock"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Corporate bonds and preferred stock. Capital markets buy and sell long-term securities. Corporate bonds, common and preferred stock, and treasury bonds are examples of securities that are sold on capital markets. Treasury bills and certificates of deposit are money market securities, which are shortterm securities. SOURCE: FI:337 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 7). Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22 "}, {"number": 44, "question": "Supervised by the Federal Reserve Board, The DAB Company provides investment advisory services, insurance underwriting, securities underwriting, and merchant banking services. What does the DAB Company exemplify? ", "choices": ["A. An accounting firm", "B. A financial holding company", "C. A central bank", "D. A commodities investor"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "A financial holding company. Because financial holding companies provide a wide variety of financial services and related products, the Federal Reserve Board supervises their activities. The primary services that an accounting firm provides include accounting, tax preparation, auditing, and bookkeeping services. Some financial holding companies may offer accounting services. Commodities investors invest their funds in goods (futures) such as grains, livestock, raw materials, etc. A central bank is often responsible for determining interest rates, controlling the nation's money supply, and regulating the banking industry. The Federal Reserve is an example of a central bank. SOURCE: FI:573 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2015). Financial holding company (FHC). Retrieved September 10, 2015, from www.investopedia.com/terms/f/financial-holding-company-fhc.asp "}, {"number": 45, "question": "According to most analysts, the three economic indicators that stock market investors and traders should pay the closest attention to are ", "choices": ["A. inflation, unemployment, and bonds rates.", "B. interest rates, overhead expenses, and inflation.", "C. Gross Domestic Product, overhead expenses, and unemployment.", "D. Gross Domestic Product, unemployment, and inflation."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Gross Domestic Product, unemployment, and inflation. According to most analysts, the three economic indicators that impact the stock market the most (and, therefore, the three that stock market investors and traders should pay the closest attention to) are the Gross Domestic Product, unemployment, and inflation. The Gross Domestic Product (GDP) is the final market value of the total output of all goods and services produced within a country's geographic boundaries during a year's time. The stock market mirrors the GDP\u2014if the GDP goes up, the stock market usually goes up with it. The unemployment rate is the percentage of the workforce that is unemployed. The stock market is inversely related to the unemployment rate\u2014if the unemployment rate goes up, stock prices usually go down. Inflation is a rapid rise in prices that may occur when demand exceeds supply or when productivity declines and costs of labor go up. If inflation and interest rates both rise, the stock market will suffer. However, if inflation goes up while interest rates stay low, the stock market is likely to benefit. Overhead expenses and bond rates are not economic indicators. SOURCE: FI:574 SOURCE: Levitt, A. (2013, April 3). Economic indicators that affect the U.S. stock market. Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/031413/economicindicatiors-affect-us-stock-market.asp "}, {"number": 46, "question": "What do some investors use to hedge the risk of investing in the foreign exchange market? ", "choices": ["A. No-load funds", "B. Emerging markets", "C. Venture capital", "D. Derivatives"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Derivatives. Derivatives are financial instruments whose value depends upon the value of other financial instruments or market indices. Investors frequently use derivatives to hedge or reduce the risk of investing in the foreign exchange market, which is sometimes volatile. The derivatives help to reduce the impact of significant fluctuations in foreign exchange markets. Emerging markets are financial markets in countries with developing economies. Emerging markets are usually receptive to foreign investment, but they are also more volatile and risky than financial markets in developed countries. Venture capital is invested money that is used for new business opportunities. No-load mutual funds have no up-front sales charges. SOURCE: FI:575 SOURCE: MBA Research and Curriculum Center. (2009). Introduction to finance course guide (pp. 5- 156 - 5-157). Columbus, OH: Author. "}, {"number": 47, "question": "What type of financial statement includes an accounting of the shareholders' equity for a company? ", "choices": ["A. Annual report", "B. Income statement", "C. Cash flow statement", "D. Balance sheet"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Balance sheet. The balance sheet gives a summary of a company's financial health at a specific point in time. It contains two major sections: a listing of the company's assets and a listing of its liabilities. The liabilities section also indicates the shareholders' equity, which is the value of all the outstanding stock owned by shareholders. Shareholders' equity is determined by subtracting the liabilities from the assets. The income statement, also known as the profit-and-loss statement, shows a company's profitability over a specific period of time. The cash flow statement tracks the money that comes into and flows out of a company. An annual report is not a type of financial statement, but it does contain financial statements, along with a good deal of other information about the company. SOURCE: FI:274 SOURCE: QS LAP 36\u2014The Source Is With You (Finding and Evaluating Securities Information) Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23 "}, {"number": 48, "question": "The most common headings on a stock table include the 52-week high and low, the stock symbol, the estimated dividend per share, the yield percentage/rate of return, the volume/sales for the day, the closing price for the day, the net change and the ", "choices": ["A. net income.", "B. earnings per share.", "C. price-earnings ratio.", "D. stockholder's equity."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Price-earnings ratio. Most stock tables include the price-earnings ratio, or PE ratio for short. The priceearnings ratio is determined by dividing the last closing price of the stock by the earnings per share. Investors often study the PE ratio to get an idea of whether the stock is overvalued or undervalued, compared to competitors. The earnings per share (EPS), net income, and stockholder's equity are not typically found on the stock table. The earnings per share tells investors how much profit goes to each share of common stock. The net income is the money remaining after operating expenses are subtracted from gross profit. The stockholders' equity is equal to the assets minus liabilities. SOURCE: FI:275 SOURCE: QS LAP 37\u2014Table Talk (Reading Stock Tables) "}, {"number": 49, "question": "Businesses usually invest in ", "choices": ["A. bonds.", "B. themselves.", "C. stocks.", "D. real estate."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Themselves. Businesses invest money just as individuals do, with the hope for a healthy return. Often, businesses invest back into themselves by researching and developing new products, purchasing the latest and most efficient technologies, expanding into new markets, etc. They may also invest in stocks, bonds, or real estate, but putting money back into the company is the most common form of business investment. SOURCE: FI:077 SOURCE: FI LAP 77\u2014Invest for Success (Types of Investments) "}, {"number": 50, "question": "One advantage to businesses of using electronic funds transfer technology to collect accounts receivable is that it eliminates ", "choices": ["A. check processing.", "B. liquidity reporting.", "C. sales discounting.", "D. payee outsourcing."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Check processing. The technology of electronic funds transfer makes it possible for customers to pay invoices electronically so the cash is transferred from their bank account to the business's bank account. This eliminates the need for the business to handle checks, fill out deposit slips, and send the checks to the bank for processing. The cash is available immediately, and the business does not need to wait for a check to be processed before it can access the funds. The use of electronic funds transfer to collect accounts receivable does not eliminate liquidity reporting, sales discounting, or payee outsourcing. SOURCE: FI:352 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 242-245). Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 51, "question": "A business's balance sheet lists $3,800 in cash, $15,125 in accounts payable, $2,775 in taxes, $10,350 in machinery and equipment, and $6,280 in salaries. Calculate the business's total liabilities. ", "choices": ["A. $27,030", "B. $18,470", "C. $15,225", "D. $24,180"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "$24,180. A business's balance sheet shows the business's financial condition at a certain point in time. It includes all assets, liabilities, and the owner's equity. Total liabilities\u2014the debts the business owes\u2014 include items such as accounts payable, salaries, taxes, and long-term notes such as mortgages. Total liabilities do not include cash or machinery and equipment, which are considered assets. To calculate the business's total liabilities, add the figures for accounts payable, taxes, and salaries ($15,125 + $2,775 + $6,280 = $24,180). SOURCE: FI:093 SOURCE: FI LAP 10\u2014The Right Balance (The Nature of Balance Sheets) "}, {"number": 52, "question": "When preparing a statement of equity, what does a business deduct from its total net income to obtain its retained earnings? ", "choices": ["A. Bad debt", "B. Depreciation of assets", "C. Sales tax payable", "D. Dividends paid"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Dividends paid. Retained earnings are the income that a corporation keeps after paying dividends to its stockholders. This amount, which includes any forwarding balance of retained earnings from the previous accounting period, is reported on the company's statement of equity, which is also called the statement of retained earnings. The depreciation of assets, sales tax payable, and bad or uncollectible debt are not included on the statement of equity. SOURCE: FI:630 SOURCE: Peavler, R. (n.d.). Statement of retained earnings. Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://bizfinance.about.com/od/yourfinancialposition/tp/Statement_Retained_Earnings.htm Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24 "}, {"number": 53, "question": "A characteristic of managerial accounting is that it focuses on ", "choices": ["A. reporting the business's long-term investment goals.", "B. capturing the business's day-to-day financial activities.", "C. developing the business's annual report.", "D. preparing and submitting the business's tax forms."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Capturing the business's day-to-day financial activities. Accounting is the process of keeping and interpreting financial records. Managerial accounting primarily focuses on capturing, maintaining, and interpreting the business's accounting information for internal use and decision making. Managerial accounting often summarizes information about the business's day-to-day financial activities, such as sales transactions (accounts receivable) and the monies the business owes others (accounts payable). Financial accounting focuses on capturing, maintaining, preparing, and reporting financial information to external audiences. Examples of financial accounting activities include preparing tax data for the government and developing the annual report for the business's stakeholders. The annual report usually contains information about the business's long-term investment goals. SOURCE: FI:657 SOURCE: BusinessDictionary.com. (2015). Management accounting. Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://www.businessdictionary.com/definition/management-accounting.html "}, {"number": 54, "question": "A company purchases an expensive new software system and divides the cost of it between the two departments that will use the system. This is an example of cost ", "choices": ["A. allocation.", "B. accumulation.", "C. dividing.", "D. precision."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Allocation. Cost allocation is the assignment of costs to cost objects, such as a project, a department, a customer, etc. The company in this example allocates the cost of its new software system to two departments. This is not considered cost accumulation, dividing, or precision. SOURCE: FI:663 SOURCE: Averkamp, H. (2004-2015). What is cost allocation? Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://www.accountingcoach.com/blog/what-is-cost-allocation "}, {"number": 55, "question": "When a business has been running successfully for several years, what would be a probable next financial step? ", "choices": ["A. Acquiring start-up funds", "B. Purchasing a second location", "C. Deciding on financial goals", "D. Determining product prices"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Purchasing a second location. If a business has been running successfully for several years, it may be in the expansion stage of its lifecycle. This could mean that the company would consider purchasing a second location. The company would acquire start-up funds, decide on financial goals, and determine product prices at a much earlier stage in development. SOURCE: FI:339 SOURCE: Ryan, K. (2015, March 23). The 4 stages of the business lifecycle and how to recognize what you need next. Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://www.roseryan.com/blog/2015/03/the-4-stages-of-the-business-lifecycle/ "}, {"number": 56, "question": "A small restaurant wants to expand, but first it needs to raise funds. John wants to raise capital through debt financing, but his partner, Damien, isn't sure that's a good idea. What is one downside of debt financing that Damien could cite to prove his point to John? ", "choices": ["A. They will need to sell stock in their business.", "B. Shareholders will own part of their business.", "C. They will have to pay interest on the borrowed amount.", "D. They will be required to repay the money immediately."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "They will have to pay interest on the borrowed amount. A downside of acquiring capital through debt financing is that the borrower must pay interest on the money borrowed. This means that John and Damien will end up owing more than the amount of money they initially borrowed. In equity financing, stocks are sold to shareholders and those shareholders own a stake in the company. Damien and John would not be required to repay the money immediately. SOURCE: FI:340 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2015). How does a company choose between debt and equity in its capital structure? Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/032515/how-does-company-choose-betweendebt-and-equity-its-capital-structure.asp "}, {"number": 57, "question": "Ethan is developing common-size financial statements so that he can compare financial performance across several different companies. Ethan is conducting __________ analysis. ", "choices": ["A. horizontal", "B. vertical", "C. ratio", "D. trend"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Vertical. Three common types of financial statement analysis are vertical analysis, horizontal analysis, and ratio analysis. When conducting vertical analysis, an individual calculates each individual item on a financial statement as a percentage of the total. After doing so, the analyst can develop common-size financial statements that allow him/her to compare performance across several years for a single company or across several different companies. Horizontal analysis, which is sometimes known as trend analysis, involves analyzing dollar amounts on financial statements for a single company across several years. Horizontal analysis does not involve the development of common-size financial statements. Ratio analysis involves the calculation of ratios based on a company's financial data. It allows analysts to compare numbers within a financial statement and determine the relationships among numbers on different financial statements. It can also be used to compare the performance of multiple companies. SOURCE: FI:334 SOURCE: eNotes.com. (n.d.). Financial statement analysis. Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://www.enotes.com/business-finance-encyclopedia/financial-statement-analysis/ Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25 "}, {"number": 58, "question": "Which of the following equations should employees know when they are verifying the accuracy of a business's balance sheet: ", "choices": ["A. Assets = Liabilities + Owner's Equity", "B. Owner's Equity = Available Cash - Liabilities", "C. Assets = Owner's Equity - Liabilities", "D. Owner's Equity = Liabilities + Available Cash"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Assets = Liabilities + Owner's Equity. A balance sheet is a financial statement that captures the financial condition of the business at that particular moment. Three main elements are included on the balance sheet\u2014assets, liabilities, and owner's equity. Available cash is one part of the business's total assets. If the assets do not equal the liabilities when the liabilities are added to the owner's equity (Assets = Liabilities + Owner's Equity), information on the balance sheet is incorrect. SOURCE: FI:335 SOURCE: Averkamp, H. (2004-2015). Balance sheet (explanation). Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://www.accountingcoach.com/balance-sheet/explanation/3 "}, {"number": 59, "question": "You want to have $8,000 in three years to purchase a car. You can earn 4% compound interest on your investment. How much should you invest today? ", "choices": ["A. $7,364.10", "B. $7,111.75", "C. $7,692.31", "D. $7,821.47"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "$7,111.75. To determine how much you should invest today, calculate the present value of your investment using the formula Present Value = Future Value / (1 + Interest Rate)Number of Years. So, the present value of your investment is equal to $8,000 / (1 + 0.04)3 . To solve this equation, first add one to the interest rate (1 + 0.04 = 1.04). Next, raise this sum to the third power, which is the same as multiplying the sum by itself three times (1.043 = 1.04 X 1.04 X 1.04 = 1.1249). Finally, divide the future value of your investment by this product ($8,000 / 1.1249 = $7,111.75). To have $8,000 in three years, you need to invest $7,111.75 today. SOURCE: FI:238 SOURCE: Garrison, S. (n.d.). Time value of money: Self-paced overview. Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://www.studyfinance.com/lessons/timevalue/index.mv "}, {"number": 60, "question": "Effective financial-information management involves implementing processes that help companies ", "choices": ["A. revise economic indicators.", "B. track their ongoing projects.", "C. interpret government regulations.", "D. make appropriate business decisions."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Make appropriate business decisions. Businesses track a variety of accounting and financial data. The data are presented as information to businesspeople to evaluate and to make business decisions. In order for businesspeople to make sound business decisions, the financial data must be accurate, current, and relevant. Making a decision based on incorrect or outdated data could be very costly to a business. Businesses use project-management software to track projects. Businesses implement effective financial-information management processes to be in compliance with government regulations. Businesses evaluate, rather than revise, economic indicators. SOURCE: FM:002 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 341-342). Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 61, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a businessperson exhibiting unethical behavior in relation to a business's financial information: ", "choices": ["A. A banker requests financial information from a business to process a loan.", "B. An auditor verifies the accuracy of a corporation's financial statements.", "C. An unauthorized employee reviews a client's financial information.", "D. A manager examines the business's financial records to develop a budget."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "An unauthorized employee reviews a client's financial information. Businesses have an ethical duty to protect their clients' financial information. Businesses must develop and implement procedures that reduce the risk of theft or unauthorized access to confidential financial information by internal and external sources. Verifying the accuracy of financial statements, requesting financial information to process a loan, and examining financial records to develop a budget are necessary and ethical practices. SOURCE: FM:003 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 339). Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 62, "question": "The foundation of the principle of least authority is that computer data are more secure when access to specific types of data are only available to ", "choices": ["A. the customers who request it.", "B. mid-level managers.", "C. personnel during set time periods.", "D. the people who need it."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "The people who need it. By limiting access to those who use or need it, confidential data are more secure and are less likely to be seen or modified by unauthorized people. Computer passwords are common methods of limiting access to certain computer data. Top-level management usually develops or approves the policies that determine who can access certain data. Mid-level managers usually need access to certain types of business data, but not all of it. Customers are often able to access some data about their personal accounts online. SOURCE: FM:011 SOURCE: Indiana University. (2012, October 9). What is the principle of least privilege? Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://kb.iu.edu/data/amsv.html Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26 "}, {"number": 63, "question": "Tara knows that for her small business to grow, she must increase her cash flow. She's unsure, though, whether she should take out a loan or a line of credit. Which of the following budgeting software tools could Tara use to assess the potential impact of each source of funding on her business: ", "choices": ["A. Zero-based modeling", "B. Decision trees", "C. Environmental scanning", "D. Debt modeling"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Debt modeling. Some budgeting software applications include a debt modeling tool which allows the user to assess the potential impact of loans and lines of credit. To use the debt modeling tool, the user would input the terms of the loan or line of credit, including the interest rate, term, principal, etc. Decision trees are a data-mining technique commonly used to classify data and build models. Environmental scanning involves gathering information about the environment surrounding a business, analyzing that information, and determining the future impact of that information on the business. Zero-based budgeting is a method of budgeting that requires a manager to demonstrate the need for every expense instead of relying on figures from a previous period. SOURCE: FM:013 SOURCE: Software Advice. (n.d.). PlanGuru software. Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://www.softwareadvice.com/accounting/planguru-profile/ "}, {"number": 64, "question": "What financial analysis application does a business use to evaluate changes in its cash position from month to month? ", "choices": ["A. Expense", "B. Cash flow", "C. Fixed costs", "D. Performance"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Cash flow. Computer applications aid businesses in analyzing many types of financial issues. Businesses often want to evaluate the changes in their cash position. To evaluate changes in cash position, the business would analyze its cash flow. Cash flow is the movement of funds into and out of the business. Evaluating cash flow helps the business forecast and determine the amount of cash it has to work with at any given time. Expenses are cash outflows and are one aspect of analyzing the business's cash flow. Fixed costs are expenses that are not affected by changes in sales volume. Analyzing performance may involve evaluating the productivity and efficiency of different resources (e.g., human, materials, equipment). SOURCE: FM:014 SOURCE: MicroStrategy. (2013). Financial reporting analysis module reference. Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://www2.microstrategy.com/producthelp/9.3.1/manuals/en/FRAMref.pdf "}, {"number": 65, "question": "Before approving a loan application, a bank is likely to analyze the applicant's ", "choices": ["A. inflation rate.", "B. debt ratio.", "C. brand preferences.", "D. performance goals."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Debt ratio. To reduce the risk of nonpayment or default on a loan, a bank reviews the loan applicant's debt ratio before approving the loan. The debt ratio indicates the applicant's current level of debt in relation to his/her current assets (e.g., income, home). If the applicant has a high level of outstanding debt and few liquid assets, the applicant is more likely to default on the loan. In this situation, the applicant would most likely be denied the loan. The bank may consider the economy's inflation rate in relation to the applicant's debt ratio when evaluating the loan application. The bank is not likely to consider the applicant's brand preferences or performance goals. SOURCE: FM:009 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 266-270). Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 66, "question": "The first task in the HR management activity of staffing is ", "choices": ["A. determining job descriptions.", "B. screening and selecting applicants.", "C. determining need.", "D. recruiting."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Determining need. The first task in the HR management activity of staffing is determining need. A company cannot fill job positions with appropriate employees until it knows exactly where human resources are lacking. Determining job descriptions, recruiting, and screening and selecting applicants are all staffing activities that occur after need has been determined. SOURCE: HR:410 SOURCE: HR LAP 35\u2014People Pusher (Nature of Human Resources Management) "}, {"number": 67, "question": "Business customers differ from final consumers in that ", "choices": ["A. there is a greater emphasis on personal selling in business-to-business marketing.", "B. business customers don't care about service as much as consumers do.", "C. consumers tend to buy in bulk more often than businesses do.", "D. consumer products tend to be more technical in nature."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "There is a greater emphasis on personal selling in business-to-business marketing. In consumer marketing, the emphasis is on promotion and advertising; in B2B marketing, however, there is a greater emphasis on personal selling. Businesses tend to buy products that are more technical in nature than consumer products. Businesses also tend to buy in bulk more than individual consumers do. Both business customers and individual consumers care about service, but it tends to be more important to businesses. SOURCE: MK:014 SOURCE: MK LAP 6\u2014Cause and Effect (Buying Behavior) Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27 "}, {"number": 68, "question": "Amy says, \"I think the primary reason that last year's sales were higher than this year's sales is because Jansen Electronics has taken a portion of our market share.\" This is an example of ", "choices": ["A. comparative criticism.", "B. a fact.", "C. historical data.", "D. an opinion."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "An opinion. An opinion is a person's point of view or belief about a topic. Amy is stating her opinion about why sales varied from one year to another. Her opinion may be supported by facts (true data), but she isn't presenting any data\u2014current or historical\u2014in her statement. There isn't enough information provided to determine if Amy is stating her opinion as criticism, which involves expressing disapproval. SOURCE: NF:077 SOURCE: Gunsch, J., Gilchrist, J., & Harris, B. (2014, January 1). What is the difference between fact and opinion? Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://www.wisegeek.org/what-is-thedifference-between-fact-and-opinion.htm "}, {"number": 69, "question": "What do most businesses use to store information for future use? ", "choices": ["A. Scanners", "B. Display screens", "C. Computer systems", "D. Firewalls"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Computer systems. Computer systems consist of the hardware and software components that enable computers to function. One of their purposes is to store information for future use. Scanners are input devices that can read text or illustrations on paper and translate the information into a form the computer can use. The scanner itself does not store information, but enables computers to store it. Display screens, or monitors, display the characters being keyed into the computer; they are not storage devices. Firewalls protect a business's computer system from unauthorized use by others (e.g., hackers). SOURCE: NF:081 SOURCE: Microsoft. (2013). Parts of a computer. Retrieved September 15, 2015 from http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-vista/parts-of-a-computer "}, {"number": 70, "question": "Adian is conducting online research for a marketing project at work. What web-based tool will help Adian save and organize the websites that contain the relevant information he needs for his final report? ", "choices": ["A. Personal intranet connection", "B. Notebook with color-coded dividers", "C. Word-processing memo template", "D. Browser bookmarking applications"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Browser bookmarking applications. Browsers are computer software that retrieve information from the World Wide Web. Browsers have bookmarking applications that allow computer users to select websites and store their URLs on a personal computer for easy access in the future. Bookmarking applications allow users to organize sites by categories by placing them into folders on a computer. Notebooks are not online tools. An intranet is an internal network similar to the Internet that is accessible only by authorized employees. A word-processing memo template formats a type of written message. SOURCE: NF:006 SOURCE: Boswell, W. (2015). What is a bookmark? Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://websearch.about.com/od/2/g/bookmarks.htm "}, {"number": 71, "question": "In which of the following situations would a business use a spreadsheet software program to estimate the effect of change on its financial situation: ", "choices": ["A. A salesperson kept all appointments.", "B. Mailing labels are needed for a catalog.", "C. Customers purchased more products.", "D. Sales are expected to increase by 5%."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Sales are expected to increase by 5%. Spreadsheet software programs allow businesses to use a computer to perform accounting and other financial calculations. An advantage of using a spreadsheet program is that a business can make various assumptions about sales and find out quickly what effect they will have on its financial situation. For example, a business could change the level of sales by different percentages, such as 5% or 10%, to find out the effect that would have on net income. The spreadsheet program automatically does the calculations. Although keeping appointments might lead to sales, a salesperson would likely not use a spreadsheet program to track appointments. Mailing labels are generated with database programs. Database programs are also used to track customers' purchases. SOURCE: NF:010 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 214-215). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 72, "question": "What application enables a business to identify when a record was added to a database? ", "choices": ["A. Validation rules", "B. Date/Time stamp", "C. Data replication", "D. Sort"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Date/Time stamp. The date/time stamp enables a business to identify the date and time that a particular record was added to the database. This can help a business track employees' keying activities and track when customers are added to the database. The validation-rules application enables a database developer to restrict how and/or what data can be keyed in a particular database field. The data replication application involves copying data from one database to another. This enables users to access the data they need to perform their tasks without interfering with others' work. The sort application enables users to view only the data they need to view, such as orders placed on a particular date. SOURCE: NF:124 SOURCE: Chapple, M. (n.d.). How to add a date or time stamp to an Access 2010 database table. Retrieved March 16, 2015, from http://databases.about.com/od/tutorials/ht/Access_2010_Timestamps.htm Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28 "}, {"number": 73, "question": "The primary purpose for record keeping is to provide information about what is happening with the ", "choices": ["A. industry.", "B. country.", "C. economy.", "D. business."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Business. The primary function of record keeping is to provide information that indicates the status of the business. In other words, record keeping provides information about what is happening with the business, such as whether it is making a profit or it is spending too much on expenses. The records that a business keeps are not designed to provide information about what is happening with the economy, the country, or the industry. However, the business's records might reflect current economic or industry trends. SOURCE: NF:001 SOURCE: NF LAP 1\u2014Record It (Business Records) "}, {"number": 74, "question": "Which of the following is an example of how a business or industry has a unique relationship with its environment: ", "choices": ["A. Social and cultural attitudes change over time.", "B. An economy in prosperity will eventually experience recession.", "C. Demand for skilled nursing care rises as the population ages.", "D. New technology causes new laws to be enacted."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Demand for skilled nursing care rises as the population ages. The impact of demographics (the age of the population) on a specific industry (health care) shows that businesses have unique relationships with their environments. The aging of the population affects other industries, but perhaps not as directly as it does health care. An economy phasing through the business cycle and a shift in social/cultural attitudes are examples of how environmental factors are dynamic. New technology causing new laws to be enacted is an example of how environmental factors are interrelated. SOURCE: NF:015 SOURCE: NF LAP 2\u2014Get the 411 (Environmental Scanning) "}, {"number": 75, "question": "Determine the mode for a customer-survey question using the following statistical information: 7, 5, 3, 7, 7, 9, 5, 7, 9, 9 ", "choices": ["A. 5", "B. 3", "C. 7", "D. 9"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "7. Central tendency refers to a type of average. Mode is a measure of central tendency and is the number that appears most frequently in a group of numbers. A business might determine the mode so it can identify the most common responses for questions appearing on a customer survey. The business assigns a numerical value to each response option on the survey. For example, the response, \"extremely satisfied with service,\" might have a value of nine. To determine the mode, count the number of times each value appears (3 appears 1 time; 5 appears 2 times; 9 appears 3 times; and 7 appears 4 times). The highest number of times a number appears is the mode (7). SOURCE: NF:093 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 182-183). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 76, "question": "Which of the following statements is true of workplace accidents: ", "choices": ["A. Accidents only occur in factories.", "B. All accidents can be predicted.", "C. There is no way to prepare for accidents.", "D. There are ways to reduce accident risk."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "There are ways to reduce accident risk. Although you can't prevent every accident from happening, there are things your company can (and should!) do to reduce accident risk. For example, to minimize trips and falls you should keep all floors clean, mop up spills, and make sure that ice outdoors is treated or removed. Workplace accidents cannot be predicted\u2014they can happen to anyone at any time. Although you cannot predict accidents, you can prepare for them by having an accident plan in place. Accidents can occur at any workplace, not just in factories. SOURCE: OP:009 SOURCE: Durham, Jeff. (2015, August 6). Common accidents at work. Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://www.safeworkers.co.uk/CommonWorkPlaceAccidents.html "}, {"number": 77, "question": "Which of the following is a common challenge for project managers: ", "choices": ["A. Laws and regulations", "B. Poorly defined goals", "C. A surplus of resources", "D. A lack of risk"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Poorly defined goals. Poorly defined project goals are one of the many challenges that project managers routinely face. A surplus of resources would be a good thing, as would a lack of risk! Laws and regulations may affect business projects, but they typically don't pose a challenge. SOURCE: OP:158 SOURCE: OP LAP 6\u2014Projected to Win (Nature of Project Management) Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29 "}, {"number": 78, "question": "What project-planning tool helps businesses to effectively plan and use time? ", "choices": ["A. Policies", "B. Objectives", "C. Schedules", "D. Guidelines"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Schedules. When planning a project, businesses often develop schedules to identify what tasks need to be done and how long it will take to perform those tasks. The use of schedules helps a business to organize work and establish completion dates to make sure the work is done on time. Scheduling an effective use of time helps a business to achieve the objectives, or goals, of the project. Policies are guidelines that businesses follow when making decisions about projects. Objectives, policies, and guidelines are other project-planning tools, but they do not involve planning the use of time. SOURCE: OP:002 SOURCE: Burrow, J.L., Kleindl, B., & Everard, K.E. (2008). Business principles and management (12th ed.) [pp. 329-331]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 79, "question": "Which of the following is NOT a benefit of a post-implementation review? ", "choices": ["A. Identifying ways to improve project planning", "B. Identifying cost-savings opportunities for future projects", "C. Identifying cost-savings opportunities for the current project", "D. Identifying ways to improve the company's processes"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Identifying cost-savings opportunities for the current project. A post-implementation review is conducted after a project is finished. Therefore, there is not an opportunity to save money on the current project. There is an opportunity to identify ways to improve future projects, such as cost-savings measures, improving project planning methods, and improving the processes used by the company. SOURCE: OP:159 SOURCE: Smith, E. (2015). Key activity in closing out a project. Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/key-activity-closing-out-project-35457.html "}, {"number": 80, "question": "Purchasing is important to international businesses because ", "choices": ["A. supplies should be delivered in a timely fashion.", "B. good relations with vendors reduce prices.", "C. quality standards should be maintained.", "D. controlling costs increases competitiveness."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Controlling costs increases competitiveness. Effective purchasing controls costs, which enables businesses to lower selling prices. For example, Japan, South Korea, and Taiwan can often produce for less. American companies must reduce costs to be competitive in such world markets. Good relations with vendors and suppliers are important but do not reduce prices. Maintaining quality standards is a production goal. SOURCE: OP:015 SOURCE: OP LAP 2\u2014Buy Right (Purchasing) "}, {"number": 81, "question": "An advantage to businesses of using quality control methods is that these methods often ", "choices": ["A. involve time.", "B. reduce costs.", "C. increase waste.", "D. require directions."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Reduce costs. It is often more costly not to provide quality than to use methods to increase quality. If businesses develop a reputation of providing low quality goods and services, they may lose customers, which is costly. Therefore, it is to the business's advantage to use quality control methods so the work will be done correctly rather than spend money to correct mistakes, handle customer complaints, and find new customers. Using quality control methods involves time, but it is time well spent to reduce the cost of correcting mistakes. Using quality control methods usually decreases waste. Some quality control methods might require directions which could be a disadvantage. SOURCE: OP:164 SOURCE: Pride, W.M., Hughes, R.J., & Kapoor, J.R. (2008). Business (9th ed.) [p. 293]. Boston: Houghton Mifflin. "}, {"number": 82, "question": "An organization with a quality culture would have executive-level managers who are ", "choices": ["A. flexible, indifferent, and not responsible for quality.", "B. good at delegating all commitments for quality assurance.", "C. committed and involved and take responsibility for quality.", "D. able to enlist the expertise of outside contractors for quality."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Committed and involved and take responsibility for quality. Executive-level managers are both committed and involved. They take responsibility for quality and do not delegate that responsibility. This is a characteristic shared by organizations with a quality culture. The alternatives remove the responsibility for quality from the executive-level manager and delegate it to others. SOURCE: OP:019 SOURCE: Kotelnikov, V. (n.d.) Six Sigma\u2014New approach to quality management and efficiency improvement. Retrieved June 28, 2010, from http://www.1000ventures.com/business_guide/mgmt_quality_six_sigma.html "}, {"number": 83, "question": "Joan achieved her goal of being a junior partner in five years. This achievement has made Joan feel good about herself, so she has set a new goal to be a senior partner in 10 years. Joan has received which of the following benefits of goal setting: ", "choices": ["A. Helps you to understand yourself", "B. Gives you a way to measure your progress", "C. Helps you to stay on task", "D. Raises your level of self-esteem"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Raises your level of self-esteem. Raising your self-esteem increases your self-confidence and encourages you to go on to achieve other goals. Achieving one goal has raised Joan's level of selfesteem so that she feels capable of reaching a higher goal. Goal setting helps you understand yourself, stay on task, and measure your progress, but these benefits were not described in this situation. SOURCE: PD:018 SOURCE: PD LAP 16\u2014Go for the Goal (Goal Setting) Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 30 "}, {"number": 84, "question": "Recognizing your strengths and weaknesses helps you to accept yourself, which is one of the foundations of ", "choices": ["A. safety.", "B. social acceptance.", "C. self-esteem.", "D. self-fulfillment."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Self-esteem. Self-esteem is the regard or respect that you have for yourself. People who have selfesteem understand themselves and like who they are. Social acceptance involves being accepted by others. Safety is associated with personal security and protection from harm. Self-fulfillment involves personal growth, achievement, and reaching one's fullest potential. SOURCE: PD:013 SOURCE: Ponton, L. (2013). Building self-esteem. Psych Central. Retrieved on September 22, 2015, from http://psychcentral.com/lib/building-self-esteem/ "}, {"number": 85, "question": "Diana prepares bills and invoices for her company. Her career is in the area of ", "choices": ["A. marketing communications.", "B. corporate finance.", "C. securities and investments.", "D. professional selling."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Corporate finance. Diana's job preparing bills and invoices for her company is in the area of corporate finance. The corporate finance function in a company is to manage policy and strategy for (and the implementation of) capital structure, budgeting, acquisition and investment, financial modeling and planning, funding, dividends, and taxation. Diana's career is not in the area of marketing communications, securities and investments, or professional selling. Marketing communications involves marketing activities that inform, remind, and/or persuade the targeted audience of ideas, experiences, goods/services, and/or images. The securities and investments industry consists of brokerage firms, investment banks, and stock exchanges, all of which support the flow of funds from investors to companies and institutions. Careers in professional selling involve marketing and management activities that determine customer needs/wants and respond through planned, personalized communication to influence purchase decisions and enhance future business operations. SOURCE: PD:025 SOURCE: PD LAP 15\u2014Go For It! (Careers in Business) "}, {"number": 86, "question": "Some job application forms ask why the applicant left a previous job. Which of the following would be an acceptable answer to this question: ", "choices": ["A. \"I was expected to do too much work.\"", "B. \"I was seeking a more responsible job.\"", "C. \"I couldn't get along with my supervisor.\"", "D. \"I wanted to get out of a difficult situation.\""], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "\"I was seeking a more responsible job.\" This is a positive response which indicates that the applicant is interested in getting ahead and is willing to accept additional responsibility. A job applicant should not make negative remarks about his/her previous employer(s) or coworkers. Even though all of the other alternatives could be true statements, they are negative and will reflect poorly on the job applicant. SOURCE: PD:027 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed.) [p. 47]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 87, "question": "Bobbi, who works for an insurance company, is responsible for calculating the risk of loss, establishing premium rates, and designing insurance policies to cover risk. Bobbi works as a(n) ", "choices": ["A. underwriter.", "B. agent.", "C. accountant.", "D. financial analyst."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Underwriter. The work of underwriters is important to the insurance industry. Underwriters are responsible for calculating the risk of loss, establishing premium rates, and designing policies to cover risk. Many choose to specialize in life insurance, health insurance, or property and casualty insurance. Insurance agents are responsible for selling insurance policies and other financial services. Accountants are responsible for preparing, analyzing, and verifying a variety of financial data. Financial analysts evaluate companies and industries and make recommendations to buy, sell, or hold certain securities. Financial analysts are also known as securities analysts or investment analysts. SOURCE: PD:152 SOURCE: PD LAP 20\u2014Career Opportunities in Finance "}, {"number": 88, "question": "Corporate governance is primarily concerned with __________ desires. ", "choices": ["A. vendors'", "B. CEO's", "C. stakeholders'", "D. competitors'"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Stakeholders'. Corporate governance is the system of rules and practices that control the company. Corporate governance revolves around balancing the desires of the stakeholders in a company. Corporate governance is not just concerned with the CEO's or vendors' desires; instead, it focuses on the desires of all stakeholders, including customers, financiers, the community, the government, and managers. Corporate governance is not necessarily concerned with a company's competitors' desires. SOURCE: PD:213 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2015). Corporate governance. Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://www.investopedia.com/terms/c/corporategovernance.asp Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 31 "}, {"number": 89, "question": "Which of the following is a benefit of corporate governance: ", "choices": ["A. It encourages transparency.", "B. It decreases investor confidence.", "C. It creates a less definable brand.", "D. It maximizes corruption."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "It encourages transparency. Corporate governance creates a more transparent business environment, which can increase investor confidence, create a defined brand, and minimize corruption. SOURCE: PD:213 SOURCE: Management Study Guide. (2013). Corporate governance-Definition, scope, benefits. Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://www.managementstudyguide.com/corporategovernance.htm "}, {"number": 90, "question": "Which of the following is a positive characteristic for the members of a corporation's board of directors to possess: ", "choices": ["A. Independent thinking", "B. Conformity", "C. Indecisiveness", "D. Single-minded attitude"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Independent thinking. It is important for members of a corporation's board of directors to be able to think independently. This involves questioning current policies and proposed actions so that the board as a whole acts in the best interests of the corporation and its shareholders. Board members should also be open-minded and willing to listen to suggestions and different opinions so they can make informed, thoughtful decisions. Conformity often involves following or agreeing with others to \u201cfit in\u201d with the group. Conformity can lead to decision-making practices that do not look out for the best interests of the corporation and its shareholders. SOURCE: PD:214 SOURCE: Hoban, M. (2013, March 8). Outstanding directors: The five essential traits for great directors. Retrieved March 10, 2015, from http://www.bizjournals.com/baltimore/printedition/2013/03/08/outstanding-directors-the-five.html "}, {"number": 91, "question": "Which employee reports directly to a corporation's board of directors? ", "choices": ["A. Chief executive officer", "B. Accounting manager", "C. Vice president of operations", "D. Director of sales"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Chief executive officer. The board of directors is the group of people chosen to govern the activities of a corporation. The board members are elected by the corporation's shareholders. The corporation's chief executive officer (CEO) reports directly to the board of directors. The vice president of operations is most likely to report to the CEO. The accounting manager and director of marketing are mid-level managers. The accounting manager is most likely to report to the vice president of finance, and the director of sales is most likely to report to the vice president of marketing. SOURCE: PD:302 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2015). The basics of corporate structure. Retrieved March 10, 2015, from http://www.investopedia.com/articles/basics/03/022803.asp "}, {"number": 92, "question": "Ryan is a college student who is interested in becoming a teacher. Every Tuesday afternoon, he spends his free time tutoring second-grade students in reading and math at a local elementary school. What technique is Ryan using to obtain work experience? ", "choices": ["A. Volunteering", "B. Informational interview", "C. Job shadowing", "D. Internship"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Volunteering. Volunteer work involves donating time without pay to complete tasks or projects. Because Ryan is tutoring in his free time, he is performing volunteer work. By volunteering to tutor students, Ryan can determine if he enjoys working with and teaching young children. Participating in these activities may help Ryan determine if he would like to pursue a career in teaching. Internships involve training in which schools and businesses cooperate to provide on-the-job practice for learners. Job shadowing involves observing an individual perform his/her daily job activities in the workplace. An informational interview involves talking with a business professional about his/her job. SOURCE: PD:032 SOURCE: Preston, K. (2014, October 6). 4 ways to gain job experience. Retrieved September 6, 2015, from http://www.fastweb.com/career-planning/articles/the-4-ways-to-gain-job-experience "}, {"number": 93, "question": "Is the following statement about trade associations and professional organizations true or false: Once a law has been enacted, organizations/associations are unable to affect the way that law will be enforced. ", "choices": ["A. True, members of organizations/associations have no way of influencing the enforcement of\nlaws.", "B. False, there are exceptions that apply to every law.", "C. False, organizations/associations often can change unfavorable regulations to more favorable\nones.", "D. True, laws cannot be changed and must be obeyed."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "False, organizations/associations often can change unfavorable regulations to more favorable ones. Once legislation becomes law, administrative rules are often adopted to enable the regulatory agency to enforce the law. Organizations/Associations frequently are able to change unfavorable regulations to more favorable ones by serving as liaison between the industry or profession and the regulatory agency. SOURCE: PD:036 SOURCE: Dummies.com. (2015). Trade associations as Washington, D.C., lobbyists. Retrieved September 22, 2015, from http://www.dummies.com/how-to/content/trade-associations-aswashington-dc-lobbyists.html Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 32 "}, {"number": 94, "question": "One way to build professional relationships in the finance industry is to ", "choices": ["A. encourage others to discuss their finances.", "B. read about industry trends.", "C. implement a referral system.", "D. print new business cards for distribution."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Implement a referral system. A referral is a recommendation given to an individual or business by another individual or business. For example, satisfied clients may refer their friends, family, or colleagues to their financial planners for financial advice. This is one way that businesspeople working in the financial industry can build professional relationships. A financial planner may implement a referral system or program to encourage clients or associates to provide referrals. A referral system might involve giving a free consultation or discount to a client who has provided the financial planner with a lucrative referral. Reading about industry trends and printing new business cards are not actions that build professional relationships. The finance professional must take action on the trends s/he has researched and distribute the business cards to others to begin building professional relationships. Because financial information is personal and confidential, people are usually selective with whom they share their information. SOURCE: PD:153 SOURCE: Yokam, C. (n.d.). How to build business relationships. Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://www.ehow.com/how_4488222_build-business-relationships.html "}, {"number": 95, "question": "To manage potential risks resulting from unethical conduct, many companies build internal infrastructures that promote and enforce ethical practices. This internal infrastructure is likely to include appropriate audit procedures, a code of conduct, and a __________ policy. ", "choices": ["A. whistleblower", "B. credit", "C. monetary", "D. constituent"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Whistleblower. One way to manage potential risks resulting from unethical conduct is to build an internal infrastructure that promotes and enforces ethical practices and offers incentives to behave ethically. This internal infrastructure typically includes appropriate audit procedures, a code of conduct, a committee to develop the code, training for employees about the code, and a whistleblower policy. A whistleblower policy encourages and enables employees to report unethical behavior or actions without fear of negative repercussions such as demotion or firing. A credit policy is a guideline for a business to follow in controlling the use of payment plans that allow customers to purchase now and pay later. Monetary policy is the government policy that determines the amount of money that will be in circulation and the level of interest rates. Constituent policies are public policies that apply to the government or nation as a whole. Constituent policies include national security, foreign affairs, diplomacy, etc. SOURCE: RM:041 SOURCE: Francis, R. & Armstrong, A. (n.d.). Ethics as a risk management strategy: The Australian experience. Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://eprints.vu.edu.au/777/1/JBEthicsRisk.pdf "}, {"number": 96, "question": "Many computer software programs help businesses determine their levels of business risk, which is helpful when they develop ", "choices": ["A. monetary regulations.", "B. content theories.", "C. endorsement records.", "D. contingency plans."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Contingency plans. A contingency plan is an alternative course of action. A contingency plan states specific guidelines that a business uses when responding to undesirable circumstances. Businesses often use computer software programs to obtain numerical data about their levels of risk in different areas of the business. They use this information to make business decisions and to help them develop alternative action plans when circumstances occur that increase or decrease risk at a given time. Content theories are theories of motivation that focus on internal needs, drives, and incentives that cause people to behave in a certain manner. An endorsement is approval by a reputable external source. Governments develop monetary and fiscal regulations. Risk management software programs do not help businesses develop content theories, endorsement records, and fiscal policies. SOURCE: RM:042 SOURCE: Manktelow, J. (1996-2015). Contingency planning: Developing a good \"plan B.\" Retrieved September 10, 2015, from https://www.mindtools.com/pages/article/newLDR_51.htm Test 1123 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 33 "}, {"number": 97, "question": "How does forming a captive insurance company typically impact a corporation's federal tax liability? ", "choices": ["A. Reduces tax due on the captive's premiums", "B. Increases tax due on the captive's loss reserves", "C. Increases the corporation's sales tax liabilities", "D. Eliminates the corporation's state tax liabilities"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Reduces tax due on the captive's premiums. Even if it is not associated with an insurance company, an individual company, industry, or association may create a captive insurance company to specifically protect its parent group(s). The captive insurer aids its parent group(s) by reducing premium expenses, freeing up capital, and covering risks not commonly addressed by the greater insurance company. In addition, forming a captive insurance company can reduce, eliminate, or defer federal taxes due on the corporation's insurance premiums. A captive insurer typically decreases the tax due on a company's loss reserves. Forming a captive insurance company does not typically increase the corporation's sales tax liabilities, nor does it eliminate the corporation's state tax liabilities. SOURCE: RM:043 SOURCE: Bertucelli, R.E. (2013, March 1). The benefits of captive insurance companies. Retrieved September 15, 2015, from http://www.journalofaccountancy.com/Issues/2013/Mar/20126102.htm "}, {"number": 98, "question": "To control online transactional risks, a business should consider outsourcing its technology needs when it lacks ", "choices": ["A. internal expertise.", "B. financial resources.", "C. secondary data.", "D. external training."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Internal expertise. An important aspect of controlling online risk is making sure that customers' transactions are secure. Online transactions require customers to provide confidential information (e.g. credit card numbers), so businesses must have the technological tools and expertise to prevent unauthorized access to the information. If a business does not have employees with the expertise to work with this technology, the business should consider hiring a consultant or firm that has the knowledge and training to handle its technological needs. Outsourcing requires a business to have the money (financial resources) to pay for the services. Secondary data are facts and figures that have been collected for purposes other than the project at hand. SOURCE: RM:058 SOURCE: Corporate Computer Services, Inc. (2015). IT outsourcing: The reasons, risks, and rewards. Retrieved September 10, 2015, from http://www.corpcomputerservices.com/articles/outsourcing-reasons "}, {"number": 99, "question": "It is important for companies to practice enterprise risk management (ERM) because ", "choices": ["A. most risks are predictable and manageable.", "B. it leads to loss of shareholder value.", "C. most risks are unexpected.", "D. it increases business costs in the long run."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Most risks are predictable and manageable. Enterprise risk management is important and helpful because most business risks are predictable and manageable. If a company can plan for risks, it can minimize its losses. Although some risks are surprises, most of them are not. Not managing risks can cause loss of shareholder value. ERM should reduce business costs in the long run by helping a business avoid or manage risks that could lose money. SOURCE: RM:062 SOURCE: Thomson Reuters. (n.d.). Practical guidance: Seven steps for effective enterprise risk management. Retrieved September 10, 2015, from https://web.actuaries.ie/sites/default/files/ermresources/233_Seven_Steps_to_Enterprise_Risk_Management.pdf "}, {"number": 100, "question": "Why should managers know how to do the work of the workers they supervise? ", "choices": ["A. To create a team spirit among employees", "B. To establish a chain of command", "C. To have realistic expectations for workers", "D. To coordinate employees' efforts"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To have realistic expectations for workers. Even though managers don't do the actual jobs, it is important for managers to understand the jobs of the workers they supervise. This helps managers to know how workers should do the work, to be realistic in the amount of work they expect workers to complete, or even to fill in when workers are absent or there is an emergency situation of some kind. Managers do not need to know how to do the work to establish a chain of command. Coordinating employees' efforts and creating a team spirit are managerial responsibilities that improve the output of workers but are not related to managers' knowledge of the jobs to be done. SOURCE: SM:001 SOURCE: SM LAP 3\u2014Manage This! (Concept of Management"}], "1161-FIN": [{"number": 1, "question": "Which of the following is a way that local zoning laws affect businesses: ", "choices": ["A. Prohibit price discrimination", "B. Restrict placement of billboards", "C. Limit creation of monopolies", "D. Require labels on products"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Restrict placement of billboards. Local zoning laws affect businesses in a variety of ways, such as restricting the placement of billboards. Local communities have the right to regulate where businesses can locate, the physical appearance of the building, and the type of signage that can be used. Communities can also decide if billboards are allowed and where they can be placed. Businesses that want to use billboards to advertise must follow the zoning laws of the community. Zoning laws do not require labels on products, prohibit price discrimination, or limit the creation of monopolies. SOURCE: BL:001 SOURCE: Scenic America. (n.d.). Legal issues and billboards. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.scenic.org/billboards-a-sign-control/legal-issues-and-billboards "}, {"number": 2, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a voluntary debtor-creditor relationship: ", "choices": ["A. Requiring specific information", "B. Receiving a monetary gift", "C. Obtaining a loan from a bank", "D. Owing punitive damages"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Obtaining a loan from a bank. The debtor is the individual or business that owes money to another individual or business, which is the creditor. A business that obtains a loan from a bank is entering into a voluntary debtor-creditor relationship. It is voluntary because the business (debtor) is seeking to obtain funds from the bank (creditor) by going through a loan application process. A monetary gift is given without expectations of repayment. A monetary gift and a request for information are not examples of debtor-creditor relationships. In tort cases, the court can order one party to pay punitive damages to the other party. This is an example of an involuntary debtor-creditor relationship. SOURCE: BL:071 SOURCE: BizFilings. (2012, May 24). Understanding the debtor-creditor relationship. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.bizfilings.com/toolkit/research-topics/running-yourbusiness/understanding-the-debtorcreditor-relationship "}, {"number": 3, "question": "Every channel of distribution begins with the __________ and ends with the user or consumer. ", "choices": ["A. intermediary", "B. producer", "C. retailer", "D. agent"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Producer. A channel of distribution is the route that a product takes in moving from a producer to a user or consumer. Hence, the producer is always at the beginning of a channel of distribution, and the user is at the end, regardless of the number of channel intermediaries used. Agents, wholesalers, and retailers are intermediaries who may perform specific functions as the product moves through the channel. These intermediaries are part of indirect channels. SOURCE: CM:003 SOURCE: LAP-CM-003\u2014Channel It (Channels of Distribution) "}, {"number": 4, "question": "How does implementing an electronic data interchange (EDI) system benefit businesses? ", "choices": ["A. It allows trading communities to establish linear distribution strategies.", "B. It increases the use of artificial intelligence systems.", "C. It duplicates the data entry process within the supply chain.", "D. It improves the speed and accuracy of information flow."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "It improves the speed and accuracy of information flow. Electronic data interchange is a computer network that links two or more businesses for the exchange of information. Retailers often use EDI systems for reordering inventory with their vendors. Using an EDI system can cut back on paperwork for all businesses, resulting in speedier order processing and reducing the margin of error. The system eliminates duplication of the data entry process. Artificial intelligence systems are computer programs or machines that perform functions that humans carry out. Implementing an EDI system does not necessarily dictate the type of distribution system businesses use and, therefore, does not necessarily create a benefit. SOURCE: CM:004 SOURCE: EDI Basics. (2017). What is EDI (electronic data interchange)? Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.edibasics.com/what-is-edi/ "}, {"number": 5, "question": "Marsha got a great deal on a phone that she bought on the Internet. When she had a problem with it, she contacted the manufacturer and was told that the company would not honor the warranty because her phone had been sold by the manufacturer to a company in China. The manufacturer would not honor the warranty because Marsha's phone is an example of a product in the ", "choices": ["A. distribution channel.", "B. product life cycle.", "C. product mix.", "D. gray market."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Gray market. Manufacturers price their products differently based on what a market will bear in a country. Goods are often sold in Asian countries for less than they are in the U.S. and Canada. Eager to make a profit, unscrupulous people buy up the products at the cheap price and resell them in the U.S. or Canada for less than the manufacturers' prices in those countries. A product life cycle is the various stages a product moves through from its inception to its death. A product mix is the combination of products that a business sells. A distribution channel is the route or path a product takes from its producer/provider to the ultimate consumer/industrial user. SOURCE: CM:006 SOURCE: Northrup, L. (2017, May 10). What is the gray market, and why should I care? Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://consumerist.com/2013/05/09/what-is-the-gray-market-andwhy-should-i-care/ Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 14 "}, {"number": 6, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about channel-member relationships in the supply chain: ", "choices": ["A. Members can often reduce conflict by focusing on the common goal of customer satisfaction.", "B. Because the producers are the channel leaders, they usually have more negotiating power.", "C. Technological advancements have made interaction among channel members unnecessary.", "D. To minimize horizontal conflict, most wholesalers in the supply chain charge slotting fees."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Members can often reduce conflict by focusing on the common goal of customer satisfaction. Channel members are all of the businesses or individuals that move goods and services from the producer to the end user. The channel members depend on each other to make sure the end users receive the products when they need them and where they need them. Therefore, it is important for all channel members to remember that their common goal is customer satisfaction, especially when one or more of them disagree about a course of action that another channel member wants to take. Producers are not always channel leaders, nor do they necessarily have more negotiating power. Because the channel members are interdependent, interaction among the members is necessary. Slotting fees may cause a channel conflict rather than reduce it. SOURCE: CM:008 SOURCE: Hoos, D. (2017, April 7). How to overcome channel conflict with retail partners. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://thegood.com/insights/overcoming-channel-conflict/ "}, {"number": 7, "question": "An important factor in effective verbal communication is ", "choices": ["A. reading from a script.", "B. developing mannerisms.", "C. having a pleasant voice.", "D. enunciating rapidly."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Having a pleasant voice. Verbal communication has a much more positive effect on listeners when the speaker has a pleasant voice. Listeners are more likely to concentrate on the speaker's message than they would if the speaker's voice is harsh, unpleasant, or irritating. Enunciating, or pronouncing clearly, is important but should not necessarily be done rapidly. Mannerisms are part of body language, the way you express yourself through posture, facial expression, etc., and these are not forms of verbal communication. While reading from a script is occasionally appropriate, depending on the situation, it is not an important factor in effective verbal communication. SOURCE: CO:147 SOURCE: Erupting Mind. (2016, March 28). How to become a better communicator. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.eruptingmind.com/how-to-really-become-a-bettercommunicator/ "}, {"number": 8, "question": "When Jeremy extended his hand toward Hank as they were introduced, Hank said, \"Hello, Jeremy.\" However, he ignored Jeremy's hand and kept his own hands in his pockets. What kind of nonverbal message was Hank sending? ", "choices": ["A. We have met before.", "B. I am glad to meet you.", "C. We have a lot in common.", "D. I don't want to know you."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "I don't want to know you. There are several situations in which nonverbal communication is a better indicator of a person's attitude than words. In this situation, Hank has made a polite verbal response, but he has indicated by refusing to shake hands that he is not glad to meet Jeremy and does not really want to know Jeremy. Even if they had met before, shaking hands would have been appropriate. SOURCE: CO:059 SOURCE: Roberts, S.J. (2012). Fundamentals of business communication (pp. 30-32). Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox. "}, {"number": 9, "question": "What type of communication style is usually most appropriate to use when evaluating employees? ", "choices": ["A. Formal", "B. Casual", "C. Routine", "D. Instructional"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Formal. Different communication styles are appropriate for different situations and for different audiences. When conducting evaluation or counseling interviews with employees, it is usually appropriate to use a formal communication style. The person conducting the interview is in a position of authority and may be discussing problems or behavioral issues with an employee. Maintaining a formal communication style will help the interviewer to remain in control and provide the guidance that may be necessary. Casual and routine communication styles usually are appropriate for discussions between friends or coworkers on the same level. An instructional style may be appropriate when communicating information about how to perform specific tasks. SOURCE: CO:084 SOURCE: Rawes, E.M. (2010, December 9). Types of communication in the workplace. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.ehow.com/info_7742528_types-communicationworkplace.html Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15 "}, {"number": 10, "question": "Which of the following should you be sure to do when taking notes: ", "choices": ["A. Write in complete sentences.", "B. Use correct spelling and grammar.", "C. Write as legibly as possible.", "D. Try to write down everything the teacher says."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Write as legibly as possible. Even though you may be writing your notes quickly, it's important to write as neatly as you can. After all, your notes won't be very helpful if you can't even read them later! You shouldn't worry about using correct spelling and grammar when taking notes. It's more important to focus on content. You also don't need to write in complete sentences. This will only slow down your notetaking. It's impossible to write down everything the teacher says; instead, just try to capture the main points and important information. SOURCE: CO:085 SOURCE: Stanford University. (2017, June 27). Study tips resources: Note taking (various methods). Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://vptl.stanford.edu/students/academic-skills/studytips-resources "}, {"number": 11, "question": "Identify the type of appeal used in the following persuasive message: \"This new book is written by Dr. Juliet Browne, who holds a doctorate from the Harvard School of Medicine and is the Chair of the World Health Organization.\" ", "choices": ["A. Shock value", "B. Reason", "C. Emotions", "D. Credibility"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Credibility. Credibility is achieved when the audience has confidence in the persuader. In this case, Dr. Browne's prestigious job title and degree lead the audience to believe she is a credible source. Reason is when logic is used to persuade someone to do something. It often involves solid facts and statistics. An emotional appeal affects the audience's feelings, such as sympathy or love. An appeal that uses shock value is a form of an emotional appeal that includes information that the audience would find shocking. SOURCE: CO:031 SOURCE: McIntyre, M., & McKee, J. (2012, April 16). Ethos. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://writingcommons.org/index.php/open-text/information-literacy/rhetoricalanalysis/rhetorical-appeals/585-ethos "}, {"number": 12, "question": "A characteristic of simple memorandums written by business employees is that they usually are intended to be read by a(n) ", "choices": ["A. internal audience.", "B. board of directors.", "C. planning committee.", "D. group of suppliers."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Internal audience. Memorandums are a type of simple written report that business employees often prepare to provide information to others within the business. Since memorandums are usually intended to be read by an internal audience, they are less formal and shorter than traditional business letters. They often provide information about the progress of current projects or an explanation of upcoming events. Not all businesses have boards of directors or planning committees. However, these are examples of internal audiences that may, or may not, receive memorandums. A group of suppliers is an external audience. SOURCE: CO:094 SOURCE: Kaiser, K. (n.d.) Memorandums and letters. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://writingcommons.org/chapters/professional-technical-communication/memosproposals-reports/798-memorandums-and-letters "}, {"number": 13, "question": "A disadvantage of problem-solving in groups is that it ", "choices": ["A. hinders communication.", "B. decreases conformity.", "C. decreases risk-taking.", "D. takes more time."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Takes more time. Group problem-solving takes more time than individual problem-solving because of conflicting schedules, differing opinions, and more discussion. Group problem-solving increases conformity and risk-taking, rather than decreasing them. Finally, group problem-solving increases communication rather than hindering it. SOURCE: CO:067 SOURCE: Hadler, G. (2005-2016). Solving problems using a group - Advantages and disadvantages. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.itseducation.asia/groups.htm "}, {"number": 14, "question": "Businesses must keep in mind that word-of-mouth promotion can be ", "choices": ["A. bought.", "B. avoided.", "C. negative.", "D. inconsequential."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Negative. Businesses must keep in mind that word-of-mouth promotion can be negative as well as positive. It's important for businesses to build positive customer relations so word-of-mouth promotion will work in their favor since it cannot be avoided, cannot be bought, and is very powerful. SOURCE: CR:003 SOURCE: LAP-CR-001\u2014Accentuate the Positive (Nature of Customer Relations) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16 "}, {"number": 15, "question": "When management establishes policies that help employees to deal with customers in the same way, under the same circumstances, the main purpose of these policies is the ", "choices": ["A. fair treatment of customers.", "B. reduction of expenses.", "C. satisfaction of customers' wants.", "D. smooth operation of the business."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Fair treatment of customers. Clear policies give employees guidelines to follow and help to reduce misunderstandings that create bad feelings. Fair treatment of customers is not an expense-reduction measure. Satisfying customers' wants is not possible since wants are constantly changing. The business may run more smoothly if customers are treated fairly, but that is not the main purpose of the policy. SOURCE: CR:007 SOURCE: Government of South Australia Equal Opportunity Commission. (2011, July 1). Developing your customer complaint policy. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.eoc.sa.gov.au/eo-business/shops-and-services/shops-and-servicestoolkit/developing-your-customer-complaint-policy "}, {"number": 16, "question": "Some natural resources are plentiful but are expensive and difficult to ", "choices": ["A. obtain.", "B. use.", "C. sell.", "D. conserve."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Obtain. Although many of the earth's resources are plentiful, some of them are difficult to obtain. For example, it is difficult and expensive to drill for the vast oil reserves on the floor of the ocean. Natural resources usually are not difficult to use or sell. The fact that some resources are difficult to obtain can help to conserve them. SOURCE: EC:001 SOURCE: LAP-EC-006\u2014Are You Satisfied? (Economics and Economic Activities) "}, {"number": 17, "question": "When the demand for a product increases, a producer will normally increase the quantity of product supplied. In this situation, what will usually happen to the product's price? ", "choices": ["A. The price will increase.", "B. The price is not affected.", "C. The price will decrease.", "D. The price will remain constant."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The price will increase. In this situation, a producer will normally increase the price in order to maximize profits. A decrease in the price would not achieve a maximum profit margin. Similarly, leaving prices at their present level would not maximize the advantage achieved through increased demand. SOURCE: EC:006 SOURCE: LAP-EC-012\u2014When More Is Less (Functions of Prices) "}, {"number": 18, "question": "The owner of a small retail store has decided to offer designer jeans for the back-to-school campaign. Which of the following business activities should be used to inform the potential customers about the new items for sale: ", "choices": ["A. Production", "B. Financial analysis", "C. Marketing", "D. Strategic management"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Marketing. Marketing is a primary business activity that involves creating, communicating, and delivering value to customers and managing customer relationships in ways that benefit the organization and its stakeholders. The communication, or promotion, aspect provides a connecting link between businesses and consumers by explaining the goods and services available for sale. Financial analysis, production, and strategic management are not used to inform the potential customers about new items for sale. SOURCE: EC:071 SOURCE: LAP-EC-019\u2014Strictly Business (Business Activities) "}, {"number": 19, "question": "A car dealership purchases new cars from a Ford factory and then sells them to consumers. What type of business model is this? ", "choices": ["A. Trader", "B. Manufacturer", "C. Distributor", "D. Importer"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Distributor. A distributor purchases products from a manufacturer and then resells them. A car dealership purchases new cars from the Ford manufacturer and resells them to customers. A manufacturer, such as a Ford factory, creates products out of raw materials (or premade parts). Traders and importers are not types of business models. SOURCE: EC:138 SOURCE: Job, A. (2016, August 15). Types of business models. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.entrepreneurmag.co.za/advice/starting-a-business/business-model/types-ofbusiness-models/ "}, {"number": 20, "question": "How does innovation support a business's long-term survival? ", "choices": ["A. By decreasing organizational conflict", "B. By making it impossible for employees to predict what's coming next", "C. By enabling a business to cut costs", "D. By giving a business a competitive edge"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "By giving a business a competitive edge. Innovation is key for a business's long-term survival outlook. It must constantly look for ways to improve products, develop new products or processes, obtain new markets, etc., if it is to survive in today's marketplace. When a business innovates, it obtains an advantage over its competitors that enables the business to attract customers. Although innovation may be disruptive to the way things have always been done, it doesn't make it impossible for employees to predict what's coming next. Although some innovations may cut costs, not all of them do. Innovation does not relate to organizational conflict. SOURCE: EC:107 SOURCE: LAP-EC-107\u2014Keep the Change (Adapting to Markets) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17 "}, {"number": 21, "question": "The owner of Bonnie's Birds and Bugs realizes that she cannot completely protect her building from the possibility of fire. What would be the best means of dealing with this risk? ", "choices": ["A. Retain the risk", "B. Prevent the risk", "C. Avoid the risk", "D. Transfer the risk"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Transfer the risk. Along with reasonable prevention, risks may be transferred to some other person or business. This would most effectively be done through the purchase of insurance. Preventing the risk means to absolutely prevent the possibility of fire, which is not realistic. If fire were to occur, even after thorough prevention, the business would experience a great financial loss if it was not insured. Retaining the risk means to do nothing about the risk. This would be an ineffective means of dealing with this particular risk. Avoiding the risk means to recognize and then avoid or eliminate the risk completely. It would be very difficult to completely avoid or eliminate the risk of fire. SOURCE: EC:011 SOURCE: LAP-EC-003\u2014Lose, Win, or Draw (Business Risk) "}, {"number": 22, "question": "Union and management officials are meeting next week to determine the terms and conditions that will be provided to employees. This process is known as ", "choices": ["A. striking.", "B. collective bargaining.", "C. picketing.", "D. corporate campaigning."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Collective bargaining. Collective bargaining is the process in which unions and company officials engage to determine worker contracts. Strikes occur when the collective bargaining process breaks down, and the employees refuse to work. When employees picket, they stand outside the company to protest such things as company policies and pay scales. In a corporate campaign, dissatisfied union members might disrupt a company's shareholder meetings or even attempt to buy up stock and gain more control of the company. SOURCE: EC:015 SOURCE: LAP-EC-005\u2014Get United (Organized Labor) "}, {"number": 23, "question": "Randy used to work in a factory. However, after technological advances brought robots that could do the same job for less money, he was laid off. Randy is looking for a new job in a factory, but everything requires knowledge of computer programs, which he doesn't have. Randy is facing __________ unemployment. ", "choices": ["A. cyclical", "B. frictional", "C. structural", "D. seasonal"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Structural. Structural unemployment occurs when workers' skills don't match up with the jobs available. This often happens when there are technological advances, like in Randy's situation. Although he is a skilled worker, the jobs available need a different set of skills. In Randy's case, his best option is to get more education or training so he will have the necessary skills to become employed again. Frictional unemployment occurs when the right jobs and workers just haven't been matched up. Unlike with structural employment, there is a job that utilizes the employee's skills, but s/he just hasn't found it yet. Cyclical unemployment happens when there's an overall decline in the economy. For example, when a recession hits, fewer people are able to find employment. This is not the case for Randy, as there are plenty of jobs. He just doesn't have the skills necessary for any of them. Seasonal unemployment is predictable and expected in many industries. For example, teachers aren't usually employed in the summer. SOURCE: EC:082 SOURCE: LAP-EC-029\u2014Help Wanted? (Impact of Unemployment Rates) "}, {"number": 24, "question": "What do individuals often identify when assessing their personal strengths and weaknesses? ", "choices": ["A. Risks", "B. Careers", "C. Benefits", "D. Interests"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Interests. Interests are the things that a person is curious about, concerned for, or involved with. When assessing their personal strengths and weaknesses, people often identify their interests because interests are strong points that might lead to appropriate occupations. For example, an individual works on the school newspaper, likes to create posters for upcoming events, and belongs to the English club. These interests are this person's strengths. After assessing personal strengths and weaknesses, individuals might select suitable careers. Assessing personal strengths and weaknesses does not involve identifying benefits or risks. SOURCE: EI:002 SOURCE: LAP-EI-017\u2014Assess for Success (Assessing Personal Strengths and Weaknesses) "}, {"number": 25, "question": "The act of deliberately giving a wrong or false impression of something is considered to be ", "choices": ["A. poor communications.", "B. dishonest.", "C. tactless.", "D. good business."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Dishonest. One form of dishonesty is lying or deliberately misleading others by giving a wrong or false impression. This is not a form of good business, but bad business\u2014as it creates mistrust in the minds of customers. Poor communications are ineffective efforts to provide information, not deliberate efforts to deceive. Being tactless is lacking in tact, the ability to do or say the right thing in a given situation. SOURCE: EI:022 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (p. 221). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18 "}, {"number": 26, "question": "We know we are being treated fairly when we ", "choices": ["A. are being treated better than others.", "B. get our way and receive the outcomes we want.", "C. feel happy and satisfied with others' decisions.", "D. are being treated the way we deserve to be treated."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Are being treated the way we deserve to be treated. Our general understanding of fairness usually means that we feel that we are being treated the way we deserve. It does not always mean getting our way and receiving the outcomes we want. Fairness also does not always mean we feel happy and satisfied with others' decisions. Fairness does not mean that we are being treated better than others. SOURCE: EI:127 SOURCE: LAP-EI-127\u2014Fair or Foul? (Demonstrating Fairness) "}, {"number": 27, "question": "If you cannot take the blame for your mistakes, then ", "choices": ["A. you will never be successful.", "B. your friends will likely take the blame for you.", "C. you cannot take the credit for your successes.", "D. it will be difficult to graduate."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "You cannot take the credit for your successes. If you cannot take the blame for your mistakes, then you cannot take the credit for your successes\u2014because you've given up control over your own life. To be responsible, a person must assume accountability for all of his/her actions and decisions. Your friends may or may not take the blame for you. Not taking the blame for your mistakes doesn't necessarily mean you'll never be successful or will have difficulty graduating, but it will certain cause other problems in your life. SOURCE: EI:075 SOURCE: LAP-EI-075\u2014It's Up to You (Taking Responsibility for Decisions and Actions) "}, {"number": 28, "question": "It is considered unethical for an employee to spread malicious gossip about a coworker because the gossip may ", "choices": ["A. earn the person a promotion.", "B. make the person uncomfortable.", "C. damage the person's reputation.", "D. affect the person's social life."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Damage the person's reputation. Gossip that may hurt a person or damage that person's reputation or character is malicious. Employees who spread malicious gossip about coworkers are behaving unethically. If an employee hears malicious gossip about a coworker, that employee should refuse to pass on the information. Employees who try to stop the spread of malicious gossip are behaving ethically because most gossip is inaccurate. Spreading malicious gossip may make people uncomfortable or affect their social lives, but those are not reasons it is unethical. Malicious gossip probably will not earn a person a promotion. SOURCE: EI:038 SOURCE: Conlan, C. (2017). 4 ways to handle gossip at work. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.monster.com/career-advice/article/ways-to-handle-gossip-at-work "}, {"number": 29, "question": "Alicia is trying to persuade members of her work team to implement a new process. Because Alicia used this process with her former employer, she is very knowledgeable and knows what needs to be done to make a smooth transition. The work team is likely to go along with the change because Alicia has ", "choices": ["A. exhibited cultural sensitivity.", "B. established personal credibility.", "C. demonstrated empathy.", "D. coached others effectively."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Established personal credibility. Credibility is believability. To be able to persuade others, individuals need to be credible so others believe what they say. Individuals who are credible have a reputation of providing accurate information in a fair manner. They are well-informed and use reliable sources to support their opinions and ideas. As a result, others believe them and often are persuaded to do what they want. Because Alicia is an honest person who has prior experience with the process, she has credibility. There is not enough information provided to determine if Alicia has exhibited cultural sensitivity, demonstrated empathy, or coached others effectively. SOURCE: EI:012 SOURCE: LAP-EI-121\u2014Win Them Over (Persuading Others) "}, {"number": 30, "question": "Often, people can creatively resolve a conflict by ", "choices": ["A. brainstorming.", "B. debating.", "C. deciding.", "D. mediating."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Brainstorming. Many people use brainstorming to come up with ideas to resolve conflicts. Brainstorming is a creative-thinking technique involving the identification of as many different ideas as possible during a certain time frame. Debating is disagreeing. Deciding is choosing among alternatives. Mediating is a process that involves asking a neutral third party to help resolve a conflict. It is not considered a creative solution. SOURCE: EI:015 SOURCE: LAP-EI-007\u2014Stop the Madness (Conflict Resolution in Business) "}, {"number": 31, "question": "Zane is feeling overwhelmed about his stressful job. Which action should he take to manage his stress? ", "choices": ["A. Talk through the situation with a friend or coworker.", "B. Create an employee survey for his coworkers.", "C. Take on a greater amount of work.", "D. Skip work often so that he has time to relax."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Talk through the situation with a friend or coworker. Sharing your feelings with others is one way to manage stress. Holding stress inside doesn't make it go away\u2014in fact, it usually just makes it worse. Talking through problems with a friend or trusted coworker can often reduce stress. Creating an employee survey is a way that employers can identify stress. Zane should not take on a greater amount of work or skip work often. SOURCE: EI:028 SOURCE: LAP-EI-025\u2014Keep Your Cool (Stress Management) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19 "}, {"number": 32, "question": "Once a coach has helped a coachee establish an improvement plan, it is important for the coach to ", "choices": ["A. give monetary rewards to the coachee.", "B. set goals for the coachee.", "C. give harsh feedback to the coachee.", "D. track the coachee's progress."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Track the coachee's progress. Once a coach and coachee have developed an improvement plan, the coach must track the coachee's progress and provide support whenever possible. A coach and coachee must work together to set goals before an action or improvement plan can be implemented. A coach should provide constructive criticism so it comes across as helpful, instead of harsh. Harsh criticism tends to make coachees feel defensive. A coach does not always give monetary rewards to the coachee. SOURCE: EI:041 SOURCE: LAP-EI-041\u2014Bring Out the Best (Coaching Others) "}, {"number": 33, "question": "One benefit of assessing the long-term value and impact of your actions on others is helping you to act ", "choices": ["A. more ethically.", "B. on behalf of your business.", "C. in your own best interest.", "D. your age."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "More ethically. One benefit of assessing the long-term value and impact of your actions on others is helping you to act more ethically (with integrity and honesty). Considering the needs of others is an important part of ethical behavior. Assessing the long-term value and impact of your actions on others won't necessarily help you to act on behalf of your business, in your own best interest, or your age. SOURCE: EI:137 SOURCE: LAP-EI-137\u2014Choose for the Future (Assessing the Long-Term Value and Impact of Actions on Others) "}, {"number": 34, "question": "Following your teacher's guidelines is an example of which ethical principle? ", "choices": ["A. Viability", "B. Transparency", "C. Trust", "D. Rule of law"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Rule of law. Although the rules at your school and work are not laws, it's still ethically important to follow them. Following your teacher's rules is not an example of trust, viability, or transparency. SOURCE: EI:123 SOURCE: LAP-EI-123\u2014Rules to Live By (Nature of Ethics) "}, {"number": 35, "question": "Cornell wants to start his own business, but he isn't exactly sure what product or service he wants to pursue at the moment. The first step of the entrepreneurial process that Cornell should focus on is ", "choices": ["A. idea generation.", "B. a feasibility study.", "C. illumination.", "D. verification."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Idea generation. Coming up with an idea is the first step in the entrepreneurial process; without an initial idea, none of the other steps can be completed. A feasibility study is conducted to see if the idea is viable. Two steps in the feasibility study are illumination (where the idea becomes realistic) and verification (where the idea is found to be practical and useful). SOURCE: EN:039 SOURCE: Chand, S. (2014, February 8). Entrepreneurship: Characteristics, importance, types, and functions of entrepreneurship. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.yourarticlelibrary.com/entrepreneur/entrepreneurship-characteristicsimportancetypes-and-functions-of-entrepreneurship/5228/ "}, {"number": 36, "question": "In an ancient society, townspeople used cows to pay for the things they needed. The cows are an example of __________ money. ", "choices": ["A. commodity", "B. representative", "C. fiat", "D. paper"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Commodity. Commodity money is a physical item that has value on its own. A cow, for example, has value even if it is not being used as money. Fiat money is not backed by a commodity. Instead, it has value because the government says it does. Representative money can be traded in for something valuable. A cow is not an example of paper money. SOURCE: FI:059 SOURCE: Money Instructor. (2002-2017). What is money? The evolution of money. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.moneyinstructor.com/doc/moneyevolution.asp "}, {"number": 37, "question": "Saving money helps you achieve __________ goals, while investing money helps you achieve __________ goals. ", "choices": ["A. long-term; career", "B. long-term; short-term", "C. career; short-term", "D. short-term; long-term"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Short-term; long-term. Saving money involves putting away a portion of your income to use in the future. This may involve placing money in a savings account where you can easily withdraw the funds when you need them. Saving money can help you achieve your short-term goals such as buying a new computer or taking a trip. Often, people use their savings to make investments. Investing money involves using money to make money. By investing your money, you can make more money than you can with just income and savings. The money you make from your investments can help you achieve your long-term goals such as funding your children's college education, starting your own business, or using it for living expenses when you retire. Your career goals involve your vocation, occupation, or profession and do not always involve saving or investing money. SOURCE: FI:270 SOURCE: The Money Advice Service. (n.d.). Should I save or invest my money? Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.moneyadviceservice.org.uk/en/articles/should-i-save-or-invest Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20 "}, {"number": 38, "question": "Morgan received an email that claimed to be from her credit card company. The email said that her account would be cancelled immediately if she didn't follow a link and enter her credit card and social security numbers. After Morgan did so, she found out that the email wasn't actually from her credit card company. Instead, it was a scam designed to steal her personal information. Morgan was a victim of ", "choices": ["A. phishing.", "B. baiting.", "C. skimming.", "D. hacking."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Phishing. Phishing occurs when a scammer sends out an email pretending to be a legitimate company, such as a credit card company, in order to gain personal information. The phisher typically sends readers to a fake website that asks them to enter personal information, which can include credit card numbers, social security numbers, bank account numbers, etc. It's a good idea to be especially suspicious of any requests for personal information you receive online. Avoid giving out personal information unless you contact the company yourself. Skimming occurs when a thief runs a credit card through a \"skimmer\" to steal personal information. Hacking involves a person gaining access to a computer system to steal information. Baiting is not a term commonly used to describe phishing. SOURCE: FI:073 SOURCE: Microsoft Safety & Security Center. (2017). How to recognize phishing email messages, links, or phone calls. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.microsoft.com/enus/safety/online-privacy/phishing-symptoms.aspx "}, {"number": 39, "question": "The biggest risk to a real estate investment is ", "choices": ["A. inability to write checks.", "B. low rate of return.", "C. not being FDIC-insured.", "D. depreciation."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Depreciation. The biggest risk to a real estate investment is depreciation. If property values go down, the investor will not make a return and could even lose money. Only bank accounts are FDIC-insured, so not having that advantage does not necessarily make real estate a riskier investment than any other ownership investment. The same goes for the inability to write checks\u2014this is not an advantage any other ownership investments have, either. As with most ownership investments, real estate has the potential for a high rate of return. SOURCE: FI:077 SOURCE: LAP-FI-077\u2014Invest for Success (Types of Investments) "}, {"number": 40, "question": "When John was injured in an auto accident on his way to work, what kind of insurance paid his hospital bill? ", "choices": ["A. Term", "B. Disability", "C. Health", "D. Life"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Health. Health insurance covers such medical expenses as hospital bills, doctors' fees, lab charges, and other medical costs. Disability insurance is sometimes called loss-of-income insurance because it pays a percentage of a worker's normal wages to the worker when s/he cannot work because of an illness or injury. Life insurance pays a sum of money at the time of death. Term is a form of life insurance that covers a specific number of years. SOURCE: FI:081 SOURCE: Kapoor, J.R., Dlabay, L.R., & Hughes, R.J. (2009). Personal finance (9th ed.) [pp. 343-344]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. "}, {"number": 41, "question": "Finemart's bookkeeper journalizes the business's income and expenditures at the time they occur even if no money changes hands at that time. Finemart uses the __________ accounting method to record transactions. ", "choices": ["A. managerial", "B. cash", "C. accrual", "D. tax"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Accrual. Businesses using the accrual accounting method journalize income and expenditures at the time they occur even if no money changes hands at that time. This means that the business enters the amount of a transaction into the appropriate journal when a customer makes a credit purchase, or when the business orders goods from a supplier. Businesses using the cash accounting method record income and expenditures at the time the money changes hands. This means that the business enters the amount of a transaction into one of its journals on the day the money is received from a customer or paid out to a creditor. Managerial accounting involves reporting financial data to internal users. Tax accounting involves recording transactions for tax purposes. Finemart does not use the cash accounting method, and there is no indication that it is using managerial accounting or tax accounting to record transactions, either. SOURCE: FI:085 SOURCE: LAP-FI-085\u2014Show Me the Money (Nature of Accounting) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21 "}, {"number": 42, "question": "Why do some governments require businesses to use specific accounting methods? ", "choices": ["A. To provide external sources with accurate financial information", "B. To ensure that the businesses are complying with intellectual property laws", "C. To control the ways in which businesses develop credit policies", "D. To monitor how businesses establish their sales goals and budgets"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "To provide external sources with accurate financial information. The accounting function collects and records the financial information in the appropriate format. Governments require businesses to provide certain types of financial information to regulatory agencies and shareholders in specific ways. For example, some governments require large businesses to use a specific accounting method, such as the accrual method. The accrual accounting method records transactions at the time they occur even if no money changes hands at that time. An advantage of using the accrual method is that it provides investors, creditors, and customers with a more accurate picture of a business's cash flow over time. Governments do not require businesses to use a specific accounting method to ensure that they are complying with intellectual property laws, to control the ways in which businesses develop credit policies, or to monitor how businesses establish sales goals and budgets. SOURCE: FI:353 SOURCE: Fishman, S. (2017). Cash vs. accrual accounting. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/cash-vs-accrual-accounting-29513.html "}, {"number": 43, "question": "Which of the following is an example of an employee-assistance program: ", "choices": ["A. Training on the use of dangerous power equipment", "B. Compensation", "C. Career and education planning", "D. Corrective action"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Career and education planning. Career and education planning is an example of an employee-assistance program a company may offer. Employee-assistance programs are part of the HR management activity of employee relations. Compensation is pay for work completed, not extra assistance. Training on the use of dangerous power equipment is a compliance issue. Corrective action is a training and development issue that occurs when an employee's performance is not up to standard. SOURCE: HR:410 SOURCE: LAP-HR-035\u2014People Pusher (Nature of Human Resources Management) "}, {"number": 44, "question": "Businesses that obtain information about competitors with the use of questionable techniques, even though these techniques are legal, are often behaving ", "choices": ["A. aggressively.", "B. unethically.", "C. carelessly.", "D. recklessly."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Unethically. Unethical behavior is behavior that is wrong or immoral. It is often considered unethical to obtain information about competitors with the use of questionable techniques, even though these techniques are legal. For example, it is illegal to take aerial photographs of a competitor's facility, but it is not illegal to purchase aerial photographs from governmental agencies that have obtained them for other purposes. However, buying those photographs with the intent of obtaining information about a competitor's operation is usually considered to be unethical. Using questionable techniques to obtain information is not an example of being reckless, aggressive, or careless. SOURCE: IM:025 SOURCE: LAP-IM-025\u2014Info With Integrity (Ethics in Marketing-Information Management) "}, {"number": 45, "question": "Which situation is an example of SUGGING? ", "choices": ["A. A salesperson offers a customer the opportunity to try an expensive product free of charge.", "B. A telemarketer asks a customer if s/he knows anyone who would want to buy a certain product.", "C. A marketer tells a customer that s/he is conducting research, and then begins a sales pitch.", "D. A business promotes a product by sending samples to its customers without authorization."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "A marketer tells a customer that s/he is conducting research, and then begins a sales pitch. SUGGING is an acronym for \"selling under the guise of research.\" SUGGING is an unethical practice in which a marketer pretends to conduct research but, in fact, is really attempting to sell a good or service to a consumer. SUGGING is deceptive and rarely facilitates a long-term selling relationship. It also harms the integrity of the general marketing-research field because potential respondents who have been subjected to SUGGING are less likely to trust researchers and are likely to question their true motives. A telemarketer who asks a person if s/he knows anyone who might buy a certain product is trying to obtain a referral. Sending samples to consumers is a promotional technique. A salesperson providing a customer the opportunity to try a product for a certain period of time is implementing a strategy to make a sale. SOURCE: IM:419 SOURCE: Mordecai, V. (2014, October 9). Sugging is not (good) market research. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.insightsassociation.org/article/sugging-not-good-marketresearch Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22 "}, {"number": 46, "question": "A marketing-research project that gathers sufficient information to help the business in its decisionmaking would be described as ", "choices": ["A. thorough.", "B. efficient.", "C. tedious.", "D. predictive."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Thorough. An important characteristic of effective marketing research is that it should be thorough. Incomplete or insufficient research won't give the business enough information to enable it to make good decisions. The way in which the research is carried out would determine whether or not it was efficient. Predictive research is marketing research used to help the business forecast future business developments. Some aspects of marketing research are tedious, tiresome, monotonous, or boring, but these aspects are not necessarily related to the amount of information gathered. SOURCE: IM:010 SOURCE: LAP-IM-010\u2014Seek and Find (Marketing Research) "}, {"number": 47, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about qualitative research: ", "choices": ["A. It is based on statistics and facts.", "B. It is often conducted through experiments.", "C. It uses large samples of the population.", "D. It is conducted during a short time frame."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "It is conducted during a short time frame. Qualitative research is conducted during a short timeframe. It uses small samples of the population and is based on subjective data\u2014thoughts, feeling, experiences, emotions, etc. Quantitative research uses experiments as a method; qualitative research relies more on questionnaires, focus groups, informal interview, etc. SOURCE: IM:281 SOURCE: LAP-IM-015\u2014What's the Source? (Obtaining Marketing-Research Data) "}, {"number": 48, "question": "Which of the following is determined in a research project's master plan: ", "choices": ["A. How much data to collect", "B. The company's target market", "C. How much the marketers will be paid", "D. The purpose of the research"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "How much data to collect. A research project's master plan, known as the research design, determines the types of data needed, how much data to collect, what collection methods to use, and how the data will be analyzed. The company should already know its target market and the purpose of the research before creating a research design. The research design does not include information about how much marketers will be paid. SOURCE: IM:284 SOURCE: LAP-IM-284\u2014Better by Design (Marketing Research Designs) "}, {"number": 49, "question": "Which probability design allows marketers to study distinct groups within the target population? ", "choices": ["A. Simple random sampling", "B. Stratified random sampling", "C. Systematic random sampling", "D. Cluster sampling"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Stratified random sampling. Stratified random sampling is a probability sampling method in which researchers break the target population down into non-overlapping groups and draw simple random samples from each one. The results are representative, yet marketers still have the ability to study distinct subgroups within the population. Simple random sampling is a probability sampling method in which every sampling unit has a known and equal chance of being selected. Systematic random sampling is a probability sampling method in which researchers place sampling units into a random list and draw a sample using a skip interval. Cluster sampling is a probability sampling method in which researchers divide the target population into non-overlapping subpopulations that are determined by geography and then randomly sample each one. SOURCE: IM:285 SOURCE: LAP-IM-016\u2014Take Your Pick (Nature of Sampling Plans) "}, {"number": 50, "question": "What type of marketing data can a business obtain by reviewing its inventory reports and customers' invoices? ", "choices": ["A. Customers' credit limits", "B. Customers' product preferences", "C. Product quality", "D. Actual market share"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Customers' product preferences. Internal records provide businesses with information about their customers' buying habits and product usage. By reviewing inventory reports, a business can determine which products are selling well and which products are moving slowly. This information may prompt the business to phase out the slow moving product and increase promotional efforts for the products that are selling well. Customers' invoices provide information about an individual customer's buying preferences and habits. For example, invoices might reveal that certain customers buy a certain quantity of a particular product four times a month. By knowing this type of information, the business can customize promotions for its customers and take steps to ensure that it has sufficient product on hand when it is needed. Financial reports provide information about customers' credit status and limits. Customer invoices do not provide information about a product's level of quality. Businesses need to analyze industry and competitors' data and compare them with internal data to evaluate their market share. SOURCE: IM:184 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 594-595). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23 "}, {"number": 51, "question": "Listing the number of respondents who answered \"agree,\" \"no opinion,\" or \"disagree\" to each question on a marketing questionnaire is an example of ", "choices": ["A. tabulation.", "B. proportion.", "C. deviation.", "D. association."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Tabulation. In many cases, processing marketing information involves tabulating the results. Tabulating is counting the number of respondents who answered each question with one of the possible answers. For example, if 100 people answered a questionnaire, researchers need to know how many of them agreed, disagreed, or had no opinion about the questions. Also, tabulating helps researchers to determine if some people did not answer all the questions, which might have an effect on the accuracy of the information. Listing the number of respondents who answered a certain way to each question is not an example of deviation, proportion, or association. SOURCE: IM:062 SOURCE: QuickMBA. (1999-2010). Marketing research. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.quickmba.com/marketing/research/ "}, {"number": 52, "question": "Interviewers cause marketing-research errors when they ", "choices": ["A. allow respondents to answer questions honestly.", "B. communicate clearly with respondents.", "C. ask the respondents to answer all of the questions.", "D. express a biased attitude when asking questions."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Express a biased attitude when asking questions. If an interviewer uses a particular tone of voice, emotionally charged words, or expresses personal or biased opinions during an interview, respondents may feel uncomfortable and less willing to provide honest answers. When respondents do not answer interview questions honestly, the integrity of the marketing research is compromised. To reduce risks associated with improper interviewing techniques, interviewers should receive proper training, which helps them learn how to ask questions in an objective manner. Communicating clearly, ensuring that respondents answer all of the questions, and allowing respondents to answer questions honestly are ways in which interviewers can reduce the risk of marketing-research errors. SOURCE: IM:292 SOURCE: Churchill, G.A., Brown, T.J., & Suter, T.A. (2010). Basic marketing research (7th ed.) [pp. 382-383, 390]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 53, "question": "The belief that profitable sales volume will result from giving customers quality products at fair and reasonable prices is part of the ", "choices": ["A. planning process.", "B. marketing concept.", "C. marketing mix.", "D. consumers' movement."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Marketing concept. The marketing concept expresses a philosophy of conducting business that is based on the belief that all business activities should be aimed toward satisfying consumer wants and needs while achieving company goals. Product planning, pricing, promoting, and distributing goods and services are elements of the marketing mix. The consumers' movement refers to organized efforts by consumers to establish fairness, quality, and safety in the marketplace. SOURCE: MK:001 SOURCE: LAP-MK-004\u2014Have It Your Way! (Nature of Marketing) "}, {"number": 54, "question": "When a local athletic apparel store sells shoes, clothing, and accessories that are designed specifically for runners, it is using ____________ segmentation. ", "choices": ["A. geographic", "B. psychographic", "C. demographic", "D. rate of usage"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Psychographic. Market segmentation is dividing the market into groups that have similar characteristics. Segmenting markets helps businesses identify the people who are most likely to buy their products. Businesses segment markets in different ways. In the example, the athletic apparel store used psychographics to divide the market, which means that the market is divided on the basis of a lifestyle choice\u2014running. Geographic segmentation involves dividing a market on the basis of location (e.g., zip code). Demographics are the physical and social characteristics of the population. A business that segments the market on the basis of demographics considers factors such as the age, gender, and ethnicity of the population. Rate of usage is a type of behavioral segmentation, which involves dividing customers into groups according to their response to a product. SOURCE: MP:003 SOURCE: LAP-MP-003\u2014Have We Met? (Market Identification) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24 "}, {"number": 55, "question": "Which of the following is a question that a business should answer about its target market while conducting a situational analysis: ", "choices": ["A. What are our customers buying?", "B. How are our financing methods affecting our company's growth?", "C. Are we operating at peak efficiency?", "D. Which shipping companies are we using?"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "What are our customers buying? A situation analysis is a determination of a business's current situation and the direction in which the business is headed. A situation analysis evaluates many internal and external factors. The business's customers (target market) are an external factor the business considers when conducting a situation analysis. The business needs to know which products the customers are buying so it can determine if it needs to make product line changes, delete items, add items, etc. Answering questions about financing, efficiency, and shipping companies do not help the business obtain information about its target market. SOURCE: MP:008 SOURCE: Boundless. (2017, March 29). Conducting a situation analysis. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.boundless.com/marketing/textbooks/boundless-marketingtextbook/marketing-strategies-and-planning-2/steps-to-creating-a-marketing-plan28/conducting-a-situational-analysis-151-7221/ "}, {"number": 56, "question": "Which of the following factors affects how far ahead a business needs to predict its sales: ", "choices": ["A. The business's resources", "B. The typical information that is available", "C. The similarity of competitors", "D. The productivity of the business"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The business's resources. A business that is short of operating funds could use a short-term forecast in order to determine whether sales income will be enough to cover operating expenses. A business that has plenty of financial resources can afford to prepare a longer term sales forecast. Other factors that affect how far ahead a business needs to predict its sales are the objectives of the business, the purpose(s) of the forecast, and the conditions of the market. The choice of forecasting methods is affected by the type of information that is available. The productivity of the business affects the level at which the sales forecast will be set. Changes in the number of competitors or in their marketing strategies may require that sales forecasts be adjusted. However, the similarity of competitors does not affect the selection of a time frame for forecasting sales. SOURCE: MP:013 SOURCE: LAP-MP-005\u2014Futurecast (The Nature of Sales Forecasts) "}, {"number": 57, "question": "Your web search results contain URLs from a variety of sources. Which of the following sources should provide the most reliable data: ", "choices": ["A. A government agency", "B. A term paper", "C. A personal blog", "D. A Wikipedia site"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "A government agency. A government agency, such as the Bureau of Labor Statistics, should contain unbiased, accurate information. A term paper and a personal blog would probably be biased based on the writer's viewpoint. Although Wikipedia is an open source of information that is constantly updated, you might have received wiki information when it was inaccurate. SOURCE: NF:079 SOURCE: GCF LearnFree. (1998-2017). How to judge online information. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.gcflearnfree.org/searchbetter/judging-online-information/1/ "}, {"number": 58, "question": "Thomas wants to change the word \u201cdevelop\u201d to the word \u201ccreate\u201d in several places throughout his document. The quickest way to make these changes is by using the __________ function. ", "choices": ["A. find and replace", "B. cut and paste", "C. header and footer", "D. styles and formatting"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Find and replace. The find and replace function allows computer users to make changes to their documents quickly. This function is beneficial when working with large documents that contain multiple words or phrases that need to be changed. The cut function allows a computer user to remove text or graphics from the document. The paste function allows a computer user to place cut or copied text or graphics in the document. Although the cut and paste functions allow users to change words, they are not as quick as the find and replace function, which is one step. The header and footer function allows a computer user to place document names and page numbers into a document. The style and formatting function allows a computer user to organize the document's contents in a standard or consistent manner. SOURCE: NF:007 SOURCE: Microsoft. (2017). Find and replace text and other data in a Word document. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://support.office.com/en-us/article/Find-and-replace-text-andother-data-in-a-Word-document-c6728c16-469e-43cd-afe4-7708c6c779b7 Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25 "}, {"number": 59, "question": "Which of the following is needed to post a web page: ", "choices": ["A. Web server", "B. Product to sell", "C. Interested audience", "D. Legal permit"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Web server. After creating a web page, the developer needs to post the web page through a web server or Internet service provider (IPS). The Web server or IPS may charge a fee to post and store the web page, although some web servers will provide the service free of charge. Developers post web pages for many reasons, which may include selling products to interested audiences. Legal permits are not required to post a web page. SOURCE: NF:042 SOURCE: Build-Website.com. (2010). Upload web page to server. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://build-website.com/guide/upload.html "}, {"number": 60, "question": "Analyzing data with Simpson's Paradox in mind can help account for ", "choices": ["A. unconsidered variables or dimensions.", "B. human error.", "C. inconsistencies in data generation.", "D. incorrect assumptions."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Unconsidered variables or dimensions. Simpson's Paradox occurs when a trend that appears in different groups of data disappears when the groups are combined. It helps to reveal instances where data can be misinterpreted or variables can be overlooked because data have not been examined from multiple perspectives. Simpson's Paradox does not necessarily account for human error, inconsistencies in data generation, or incorrect assumptions about data. SOURCE: NF:139 SOURCE: Reda, G. (2014, March 23). Principles of good data analysis. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.gregreda.com/2014/03/23/principles-of-good-data-analysis/ "}, {"number": 61, "question": "Businesses can use data mining to ", "choices": ["A. show why information is valuable.", "B. see patterns within data.", "C. eliminate the need to understand data.", "D. make decisions for them."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "See patterns within data. Data mining is a way for businesses to see the relationships and patterns within data. Data mining can give businesses the information they need to make decisions, but it cannot make decisions for them. Businesses must decide for themselves why the information is valuable. Businesses still need to understand data. SOURCE: NF:152 SOURCE: SAS. (2017, August 7). Data mining: What it is and why it matters. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.sas.com/en_us/insights/analytics/data-mining.html "}, {"number": 62, "question": "A growing trend that is influencing the way that many companies do business is the concern for ", "choices": ["A. protecting the environment.", "B. distributing the wealth.", "C. monitoring the economy.", "D. regulating the government."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Protecting the environment. The growing concern over the condition of the environment is influencing the way that many companies do business. Businesses that once ignored the damage they did to the environment are now spending billions of dollars to correct the problems and to change the way they operate. Public sentiment is forcing these companies to address environmental issues, such as pollution. The businesses that fail to do their part to protect the environment often anger consumers, which may lead to a loss of sales. The government, rather than business, is concerned with the distribution of wealth. Monitoring the economy is not a new trend but an ongoing business function. Businesses do not regulate government; instead, government regulates business. SOURCE: NF:013 SOURCE: Zahorsky, D. (2016, June 1). Emerging business trends that are rocking the business world. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.thebalance.com/business-trends-affectprofitability-2951403 "}, {"number": 63, "question": "Statistical data revealed that Zane Industries sold 32% more of the Model EQ2 desktop photocopier last year after it made changes to increase the photocopier's speed and refine its print quality. In this situation, the statistical findings helped the company determine that ", "choices": ["A. its sales forecasts were inaccurate.", "B. product improvements helped boost sales.", "C. research and development expenses exceeded the budget.", "D. the company achieved its sales goals."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Product improvements helped boost sales. Statistics are information presented in numerical form. Businesses use statistics to evaluate performance and identify trends. In the situation described, the business used statistics to identify a specific increase in sales after it made improvements to a product. There is not enough information provided to know how the statistical information relates to the company's sales goals, sales forecasts, and research and development budget. SOURCE: NF:093 SOURCE: Bianca, A. (2011, August 14). The advantages of statistics in business. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/advantages-statistics-business-18698.html Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26 "}, {"number": 64, "question": "A company trains its human resources department in how to handle emergency situations. Is this an example of operations management? ", "choices": ["A. Yes, because the human resources department is considered an outside customer.", "B. Yes, because it involves the operational aspects of safety and security.", "C. No, because the human resources department does not interact with outside customers.", "D. No, because the human resources department does not use operations."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Yes, because it involves the operational aspects of safety and security. Operations management involves the processes used by both internal and external customers. Emergency training in human resources improves the processes the department would use in emergency situations. The human resources department is an internal part of the company, not an outside customer. Internal customers can also benefit from improvements in operations management. The human resources department does use processes, or operations, to complete valuable internal tasks for the organization. SOURCE: OP:191 SOURCE: Dhoul, T. (2014, April 30). What is operations management? Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.topmba.com/mba-programs/what-operations-management "}, {"number": 65, "question": "Which of the following situations is an example of a hazard that affects the safety of the workplace: ", "choices": ["A. Wide aisles to accommodate foot traffic", "B. Proper lighting throughout the building", "C. Boxes stacked in front of a fire exit", "D. Secure locks on the building's exterior doors"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Boxes stacked in front of a fire exit. Nothing should ever block a fire exit. If a fire breaks out and the building's fire exit is blocked, employees may not be able to vacate the premises. Proper lighting, wide aisles, and secure locking systems promote workplace safety rather than present a workplace hazard. SOURCE: OP:008 SOURCE: SafeWork SA. (2014, October 21). Managing the work environment and facilities. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.safework.sa.gov.au/show_page.jsp?id=113704 "}, {"number": 66, "question": "Which of the following situations may represent a risk to the business: ", "choices": ["A. A regular customer is impatient when the cashier takes a telephone order.", "B. A regular customer brings a new neighbor to shop at the business.", "C. A new customer with a check provides a piece of photo identification.", "D. A new customer's check is for an amount larger than the purchase total."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "A new customer's check is for an amount larger than the purchase total. The customer's check may be valid, or it may be a bad check because there is not enough money in the customer's account to honor the check. If the business accepts a bad check, the bank will not honor the check, and the business will lose not only the value of the customer's purchase but the additional cash as well. To protect themselves, some businesses require checks for more than the purchase total to be approved by a manager. A regular customer who brings in a new neighbor does not represent a risk to the business. Most customers are rightfully impatient when they are kept waiting by telephone transactions. Photo identification is considered the most acceptable form because it carries both a picture and a signature. SOURCE: OP:013 SOURCE: Connecticut Department of Banking. (2002-2017). Checks and related issues. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.ct.gov/dob/cwp/view.asp?a=2235&q=297900 "}, {"number": 67, "question": "What do managers often use to evaluate project results? ", "choices": ["A. Activities", "B. Techniques", "C. Resources", "D. Standards"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Standards. Standards are specifications or statements that are used as a basis for making comparisons or judgments. Managers often use standards as the basis for evaluating project results. For example, one standard might be financial, such as to increase sales by a certain amount. Then, the manager compares the results with the standard to determine if the project was effective. Techniques are methods or activities that might be used to carry out the project. Resources are items that are needed to complete a project. SOURCE: OP:159 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 258). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 68, "question": "A materials and notions buyer who purchases more zippers and buttons from a supplier to replace depleted inventory is placing a ", "choices": ["A. production requisition.", "B. reorder.", "C. back order.", "D. line requisition."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Reorder. A purchase order is written documentation that a company provides to its suppliers. It outlines specific items, prices, and delivery dates for desired goods. A reorder is an order that is placed for the same items that have previously been ordered to replenish items that have been used or sold. Back orders are items that vendors do not have available for shipment at the time the customer requests the goods. Production and line requisitions are not terms generally used in the purchasing environment. SOURCE: OP:016 SOURCE: Davidson, E. (n.d.). A basic inventory control tutorial. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/basic-inventory-control-tutorial-2230.html Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27 "}, {"number": 69, "question": "Stan is a small-business owner who is always looking for ways to increase his company's ability to do the job right the first time. He listens to his staff members' suggestions and implements many of their ideas for improvement. What is Stan doing? ", "choices": ["A. Creating a quality culture", "B. Developing new products", "C. Supporting external resources", "D. Reorganizing priorities"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Creating a quality culture. A business with a quality culture believes that each employee has valuable ideas. A quality culture involves nurturing an environment in which all employees are committed to consistently achieve the business's quality standards and look for ways to improve those standards. Improvement might involve reorganizing priorities, supporting various initiatives, increasing personal work efficiency, streamlining processes, using creative thinking, improving goods and services, and obtaining external resources. SOURCE: OP:019 SOURCE: Leadership Review. (2014, December 12). How to build a culture of quality for your organization. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.leadershipreview.net/buildinga-culture-of-quality "}, {"number": 70, "question": "Which of the following is one of the biggest expenses that employees can help a business control: ", "choices": ["A. Rent", "B. Advertising", "C. Payroll", "D. Taxes"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Payroll. One of a business's biggest expenses is payroll. Therefore, it is important for businesses to get full value for their payroll dollars to control expenses. Employees who arrive on time and work their designated hours are helping to ensure that the business receives the time it pays for. Advertising, taxes, and rent are other types of business expenses that are not under the employee's control. SOURCE: OP:025 SOURCE: LAP-OP-025\u2014Buck Busters (Employee Role in Expense Control) "}, {"number": 71, "question": "Cathy is allowing her four friends to pick out a skirt for her at the mall\u2014with one request: that all four friends agree about the selection. Which style of decision-making is Cathy asking her friends to use? ", "choices": ["A. Minimum", "B. Maximum", "C. Medium", "D. Moderate"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Maximum. Cathy is asking her friends to use the maximum-input decision-making style\u2014one in which the entire group decides together. With the minimum-input style, the decision maker decides without help. With the moderate-input style, the decision maker asks for some help before deciding. Medium is not used to describe decision-making styles. SOURCE: PD:017 SOURCE: LAP-PD-010\u2014Weigh Your Options (Decision Making in Business) "}, {"number": 72, "question": "Why do we need creativity? ", "choices": ["A. It indicates one's intelligence.", "B. It moves the world along.", "C. It shows businesses which employees can think in concrete terms.", "D. It helps businesses to identify employees who will succeed in performing routine tasks."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "It moves the world along. Without creativity, we would still be living in caves. Everything in our existence is based on something that was once a new idea. Without creativity, we'd have no new goods or services. Many highly intelligent people are not creative. Creative people think in abstract terms so that they are able to see what is not readily apparent. Creative people prefer variety and change to routine. SOURCE: PD:012 SOURCE: LAP-PD-012\u2014Imagine That (Demonstrating Creativity) "}, {"number": 73, "question": "If individuals enjoy operating machinery, driving vehicles, or using tools, they might consider a career that involves working with ", "choices": ["A. things.", "B. animals.", "C. people.", "D. information."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Things. Individuals should consider what they like to do, their favorite activities, when identifying possible occupations. For example, some individuals enjoy operating machinery, driving vehicles, or using tools. As a result, they might consider a career that involves working with things which are tangible items. Examples include a landscaper who operates equipment and drives a truck, and a carpenter who uses tools to build furniture. Careers that involve working with people and animals require a lot of personal interaction and patience. Careers that involve working with information involve keeping track of data such as facts and statistics. SOURCE: PD:023 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G. (2012). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 38-41). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 74, "question": "Javier had an interview with a potential employer, Dan Martinez. The interview was pretty casual and informal. How should Javier begin his thank you note? ", "choices": ["A. He doesn't need to send a thank you note for a casual interview.", "B. Dear Dan", "C. Hi Dan", "D. Dear Mr. Martinez"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Dear Mr. Martinez. Even if the interview was fairly casual, it's always better to err on the side of formality. If Javier isn't sure whether he should refer to his potential employer as Mr. Martinez or Dan, he should go with Mr. Martinez. It's very unlikely that his potential employer will take offense to that, but he may take offense to being referred to by his first name. Starting a thank you letter with \u201cHi Dan\u201d is definitely too informal. It's important to send follow-up letters after every job interview. This includes casual interviews, interviews that didn't go well, and interviews for jobs you don't think you want. SOURCE: PD:029 SOURCE: Littrell, J.J., Lorenz, J.H., & Smith, H.T. (2012). School to career (9th ed.) [pp. 375-379]. Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox. Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28 "}, {"number": 75, "question": "Which of the following provides a business's employees with a foundation for acceptable behavior in the workplace: ", "choices": ["A. Rules of conduct", "B. Organizational chart", "C. Grievance procedures", "D. Articles of incorporation"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Rules of conduct. The rules of conduct outline a company's policies, procedures, and expectations regarding employees' behavior in the workplace. An organizational chart is a graphical representation of the flow of authority within an organization. Formal methods of settling disagreements between workers and employers are grievance procedures. Articles of incorporation is a document outlining a corporation's name, purpose, location, amount of stock to be issued, names of the board of directors, and other information about the conditions under which the business will operate. SOURCE: PD:251 SOURCE: Brunot, T. (n.d.). The importance of the code of conduct. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.ehow.com/about_6559640_importance-code-conduct.html "}, {"number": 76, "question": "The ability for marketers to think fast on their feet is most associated with ", "choices": ["A. decision-making.", "B. creativity.", "C. people skills.", "D. people knowledge."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Decision-making. With the marketing environment growing at such a fast pace, employers are looking for people who can think fast on their feet. To do this, marketers need to be independent thinkers who can solve problems without needing supervision. Examples of decision-making skills that marketers use regularly include determining what customers need, solving customers' problems, and resolving complaints. Creativity involves using imagination and intellect to generate new ideas. Creativity is not necessarily a fast process. People knowledge and skills deal with knowing what makes customers tick and how to best work with meeting customers' needs. SOURCE: PD:024 SOURCE: LAP-PD-021\u2014Career Opportunities in Marketing "}, {"number": 77, "question": "The price function often influences the place function by determining ", "choices": ["A. how the product is advertised.", "B. why the product is shipped.", "C. where the product is sold.", "D. when the product is made."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Where the product is sold. The place function involves shipping, handling, and storing of items and determining when and where they will be available. Pricing affects the place decision by determining where the product is sold. Products with high prices usually are sold in stores that carry expensive items, while products with low prices often are sold in other types of stores, such as discounters. The price function does not influence the place function by determining why the product is shipped, how the product is advertised, or when the product is made. SOURCE: PI:001 SOURCE: LAP-PI-002\u2014The Price Is Right (Nature of Pricing) "}, {"number": 78, "question": "In which of the following situations might loss-leader pricing be illegal: ", "choices": ["A. Customers pay a premium.", "B. Businesses make a large profit.", "C. Products are sold below cost.", "D. Competitors match the price."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Products are sold below cost. Loss-leader pricing involves selling products near or below cost. In some situations, laws prohibit the use of loss-leader pricing if the products are sold below cost. The reason is that the prices may be so low that competition is eliminated. However, the laws governing loss-leader pricing are seldom enforced because customers benefit from the low prices. Businesses often do not make any profit on loss-leader pricing because the purpose of that tactic is to attract customers who then will buy additional items at the regular price. Customers do not pay a premium when buying loss-leader items. Competitors often match the loss-leader price or try to beat it. SOURCE: PI:017 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 595-596). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 79, "question": "In product/service management, a major disadvantage of rapid technological changes is the ", "choices": ["A. increase in customer satisfaction and profitability.", "B. number of new products entering the market.", "C. increase of customer product awareness.", "D. rate at which existing products become obsolete."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Rate at which existing products become obsolete. Technology advances so rapidly that products introduced to market are quickly being reintroduced with upgrades or changes that make the original obsolete. The problem is that many technically advanced products have a short life cycle because more advanced products take their place. Increasing the introduction of new products and improving customer awareness will increase customer satisfaction and, as a result, increase sales and profitability. These are advantages of new technology. SOURCE: PM:039 SOURCE: Reynolds, P. (2011, December). Managing obsolete technologies: Strategies and practices. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://iom.invensys.com/EN/pdfLibrary/ManagingObsoleteTechnologiesStrategiesandPractices.pdf Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29 "}, {"number": 80, "question": "Which of the following is a technique that many businesses use to identify product opportunities: ", "choices": ["A. Evaluating a prototype", "B. Testing the market", "C. Observing the competition", "D. Developing a brand"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Observing the competition. Businesses often observe the products developed by competitors in order to identify possible product opportunities. For example, a business might observe that a competitor's new product is popular and selling well. As a result, the business develops a similar product that is somewhat more advanced. By paying attention to what competitors are doing, businesses often are able to identify product opportunities. Once the opportunity is identified, businesses often evaluate a prototype and test the market. One of the final steps before introducing a new product is developing a brand. SOURCE: PM:134 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 707-709). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 81, "question": "The primary goal during the brainstorming process is to ", "choices": ["A. come up with as many ideas as possible.", "B. analyze each idea as it is presented.", "C. rate each idea in relation to one another.", "D. come up with a set number of ideas within a certain time."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Come up with as many ideas as possible. Brainstorming is a creative-thinking technique involving the identification of as many different ideas as possible during a certain time frame. The process involves getting ideas out in an open, nonjudgmental environment. Therefore, rating and analyzing ideas are not primary goals during brainstorming sessions. SOURCE: PM:127 SOURCE: LAP-PM-127\u2014Unleash Your Mind (Techniques for Generating Product Ideas) "}, {"number": 82, "question": "Which federal agency has the responsibility for inspecting meat that is shipped across state lines? ", "choices": ["A. U.S. Department of Agriculture", "B. U.S. Department of Commerce", "C. Federal Trade Commission", "D. Interstate Commerce Commission"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "U.S. Department of Agriculture. Federal law states that all meat that is shipped across state lines is subject to inspection by the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA). The U.S. Department of Commerce grades fish that is sold for commercial consumption, but this is a voluntary program. The Interstate Commerce Commission regulates rates and other aspects of commercial transportation between states. The Federal Trade Commission administers and enforces antitrust laws to prevent price fixing and to prohibit unfair competitive practices. SOURCE: PM:019 SOURCE: LAP-PM-008\u2014Raise the Bar (Grades and Standards) "}, {"number": 83, "question": "A group of related products is called a product ", "choices": ["A. item.", "B. line.", "C. mix.", "D. expansion."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Line. An example of a product line would be bread, rolls, cookies, and cakes in a supermarket. Product items are each individual good, service, or idea that a business offers for sale. A product mix is the particular assortment of products that a business offers in order to meet its market's needs and its company's goals. Expansion is a product mix strategy in which a business expands its product mix by adding additional product items or product lines. SOURCE: PM:003 SOURCE: LAP-PM-003\u2014Mix and Match (The Nature of the Product Mix) "}, {"number": 84, "question": "Which of the following situations is an example of product bundling: ", "choices": ["A. Buy item Y and receive service W free for six months.", "B. Buy item Z and receive a $50 manufacturer's rebate.", "C. Buy product X and receive a $15 discount if it is paid within 10 days.", "D. Buy service M and receive a coupon to use for future purchases."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Buy item Y and receive service W free for six months. Product bundling involves combining goods and/or services and offering them to customers as one product for a lower price than if the customers were to buy all of the products individually. Often, businesses bundle new products with existing products in order to create interest in the new product. A business that provides a free service for a certain amount of time hopes that the customer gets used to having the service and will pay to continue receiving the service once the free offer expires. Businesses may use rebates, invoice discounts, and coupons in conjunction with product-bundle strategies. SOURCE: PM:041 SOURCE: Boone, G., & Kurtz, D.L. (2013). Contemporary marketing 2013 (p. 660). Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 85, "question": "The following statement appears on a company's website: \"Unlike our competitors, Naturally Yours Cosmetics uses organically-grown ingredients in its facial scrubs and lotions.\" What strategy is the company using to position its line of skin-care items? ", "choices": ["A. Product reliability", "B. Price", "C. Customization", "D. Unique attributes"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Unique attributes. Product positioning is the customer's image or impression of a product as compared to that of competitive products. In the example, the company emphasizes that its products' ingredients are organically grown. Because organic ingredients are product attributes, Naturally Yours Cosmetics is using the attributes to set itself apart from other cosmetic companies that provide similar products. The business is not using price, customization, or product reliability to position its skin-care line. SOURCE: PM:042 SOURCE: LAP-PM-019\u2014Getting Piece of Mind (Factors Used to Position Products/Services) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 30 "}, {"number": 86, "question": "One reason that a brand name should be adaptable is so that the business can ", "choices": ["A. change the brand name as often as necessary.", "B. use the brand name in multinational marketing.", "C. use the brand name in packaging and advertising.", "D. make its products look like other similar products."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Use the brand name in multinational marketing. A good brand name should be easy to pronounce in all countries where the product will be marketed. For example, Kodak and Exxon are easy to pronounce by people who speak other languages. The business would want to establish a brand in consumers' minds, not change it frequently. The business would also want the brand name to set its product(s) apart rather than making them resemble competitive products. The length of the brand name, rather than its adaptability, makes it appropriate for packaging and advertising. SOURCE: PM:021 SOURCE: LAP-PM-006\u2014It's a Brand, Brand, Brand World! (Nature of Product Branding) "}, {"number": 87, "question": "Employee interactions, websites, and advertisements are all examples of ", "choices": ["A. corporate brands.", "B. touch points.", "C. logos.", "D. distributor brands."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Touch points. Touch points are all the opportunities that businesses have to connect with customers and reinforce their brand values. Any chance a business gets to interact with customers is a touch point; this includes products, packaging, employee interactions, websites, advertisements, social media interactions, and much more. Logos are distinctive symbols, designs, or groups of letters. Distributor brands are owned by the retailer or wholesaler that sells the brands, rather than the manufacturer. Corporate brands are all the combined customer impressions and experiences associated with a particular company. SOURCE: PM:206 SOURCE: LAP-PM-020\u2014Corporate Identity (Nature of Corporate Branding) "}, {"number": 88, "question": "Many of the town's residents have heard that this coming summer is predicted to be the hottest summer ever. As a result of hearing this, Tim, the owner of an appliance store, decided to do more advertising for air conditioners. Which of the following external factors has affected Tim and his business: ", "choices": ["A. Technology", "B. Legal and political factors", "C. Demand", "D. Cultural and social trends"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Demand. Demand for certain products tends to change with the seasons, such as air conditioners for summer. This means that Tim needs to adjust his promotion to meet this change. Technology deals with technological developments, not demand for a product. Legal and political factors deal with government regulations and restrictions, not demand for a product. Cultural and social trends deal with changes in attitudes, lifestyles, and tastes of the consumers, not demand for a product. SOURCE: PR:001 SOURCE: LAP-PR-002\u2014Razzle Dazzle (Nature of Promotion) "}, {"number": 89, "question": "A promotion that makes false or exaggerated claims about a product is considered to be ", "choices": ["A. stereotypical.", "B. deceptive.", "C. offensive.", "D. manipulative."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Deceptive. When a promotion includes misleading or untrue claims, it is considered to be deceiving to consumers. An offensive promotion is one that is in bad taste, vulgar, or insulting to consumers. When a promotion reinforces stereotypes, it portrays people in ways that are stereotypical. Promotions that manipulate a consumer are ones that persuade people to act against their free will to purchase a good or service that they may not need. SOURCE: PR:002 SOURCE: LAP-PR-004\u2014Know Your Options (Product and Institutional Promotion) "}, {"number": 90, "question": "Technological advancements in computer software have made it possible for media planners to calculate reach, frequency, and __________ of their placements more quickly. ", "choices": ["A. promotional mix", "B. attention value", "C. cost efficiency", "D. audience fluency"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Cost efficiency. Computer software developments have made it possible for advertisers and agencies to calculate and analyze data to determine a medium's reach, frequency, and cost efficiency in relation to the overall placement. This information can now be calculated by computer programs instead of manually, which took a much longer time to ascertain. The information is used to determine optimal venues for advertising placement. Attention value refers to the level of viewer interest as it relates to the ad's message, copy, and medium. Attention value is a qualitative consideration and can be difficult to measure or calculate. Promotional mix is defined as a combination of marketing communication channels that a business uses to send its messages to consumers. Audience fluency is not a term that is widely used in the promotion industry. SOURCE: PR:100 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 277-279). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 31 "}, {"number": 91, "question": "To qualify as a specialty medium, an item must be ", "choices": ["A. delivered through the postal service.", "B. sold to a prospective customer.", "C. used for decorative purposes only.", "D. imprinted with the business's name/logo."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Imprinted with the business's name/logo. Specialty items must pass three criteria. They must have the business's name or logo printed on them. An example would be a Century 21 key chain. Also, they should be given away freely, not sold to a customer for any price. Finally, they should be a useful item (as opposed to simply decorative) such as a pen or baseball cap. An item does not need to be delivered through the postal service to be considered a specialty item. SOURCE: PR:007 SOURCE: LAP-PR-003\u2014Ad-quipping Your Business (Types of Advertising Media) "}, {"number": 92, "question": "Which of the following is an example of direct advertising: ", "choices": ["A. A retailer conducts a telephone survey to determine its customers' satisfaction with its services.", "B. A hotel chain develops an advertising campaign that includes television spots and billboards.", "C. A soft drink company places an advertisement on television during a major sporting event.", "D. An apparel company mails its latest catalog to customers who have ordered items within a year."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "An apparel company mails its latest catalog to customers who have ordered items within a year. Direct advertising refers to promotional messages that are sent directly to the target market through a medium in which market response can be measured. Catalogs that are mailed directly to established customers represent an example of direct advertising. Unless interactive capabilities are available, television is usually considered a mass medium that has substantial reach but cannot always be measured effectively. Therefore, the options referring to soft drinks and hotel chains are not examples of direct advertising. Telephone surveys are considered a function related to market research rather than promotion. SOURCE: PR:089 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 396-397). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 93, "question": "The reason for using certain communications channels, such as coupons, in sales promotion is to ", "choices": ["A. advertise a new product.", "B. create long-term demand.", "C. persuade customers to remain loyal.", "D. generate an immediate response."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Generate an immediate response. A communications channel is a path or means used to provide information to others. In sales promotion, coupons are a type of communications channel that are used to provide information about products to customers. The reason for using coupons is to generate an immediate response by offering reduced prices on specific items. The hope is that customers will be motivated to buy the product now because of the information they received. Sales promotion is usually intended to encourage a quick response, while advertising is intended to create long-term demand and persuade customers to remain loyal. Sales promotion involves promotional activities other than advertising. SOURCE: PR:249 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 405-411). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 94, "question": "In what communications channels are holding press conferences and giving interviews used? ", "choices": ["A. Target marketing", "B. Corporate management", "C. Personal selling", "D. Public relations"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Public relations. Public relations is a function of business designed to establish good relations between the business and the public. One way to establish good relations is to communicate with the public. Businesses often hold press conferences and give interviews to communicate information and pass on positive news about the business. Corporate management involves managing the business. Personal selling is the form of promotion that determines client needs and wants and responds through planned, personalized communication that influences purchase decisions and enhances future business opportunities. Target marketing is the identification and selection of markets for a business or for a product. SOURCE: PR:250 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 396-399). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 95, "question": "One way that salespeople develop and maintain positive relationships with customers is by providing excellent ", "choices": ["A. sales management.", "B. customer service.", "C. opportunities.", "D. demonstrations."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Customer service. Salespeople strive to develop and maintain positive relationships with customers to keep them as customers. Effective salespeople know that customers expect more than just a product when they purchase something. The salespeople who are able to provide excellent service for their customers are usually able to maintain positive selling relationships with them. Excellent demonstrations might help to sell customers the first time, but will not help to develop positive relationships unless salespeople also provide good service. Salespeople are not responsible for providing sales management. Providing the opportunity to buy will not necessarily help to develop positive relationships with customers. SOURCE: SE:076 SOURCE: LAP-SE-130\u2014Go Beyond the Sale (Customer Service in Selling) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 32 "}, {"number": 96, "question": "A selling activity that helps salespeople to make sales is ", "choices": ["A. available credit.", "B. quality repair.", "C. referrals.", "D. preparation."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Preparation. This involves gathering information about potential clients in order to understand the client's needs and problems. Gathering information is also important when considering how business products can meet the needs of clients. Referrals are individuals or businesses to whom salespeople are recommended. Offering quality repair service and credit are ways businesses can build a clientele, not selling activities. SOURCE: SE:828 SOURCE: LAP-SE-115\u2014Keep Them Loyal (Key Factors in Building Clientele) "}, {"number": 97, "question": "What type of law prevents salespeople from one company from interfering with their competition's activities? ", "choices": ["A. Warranty liability", "B. Product safety", "C. Consumer credit", "D. Unfair trade"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Unfair trade. Activities such as stealing a competitor's trade secrets, or attempting to get a competitor's customer to breach a contract, are considered unfair trade practices and are illegal practices in many countries. Consumer protection laws address issues such as product safety, consumer credit, and warranties. SOURCE: SE:108 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2014). Unfair trade practice. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.investopedia.com/terms/u/unfair-trade-practice.asp "}, {"number": 98, "question": "Information about new or unusual uses for a product can often be obtained easily from ", "choices": ["A. factory visits.", "B. customers.", "C. inventors.", "D. the product manual."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Customers. Customers may have discovered new or different uses for products through actual use of the products. The product manual and factory visits provide basic information rather than innovative product uses. Sales personnel seldom have contact with inventors. SOURCE: SE:062 SOURCE: LAP-SE-131\u2014Get Informed (Acquiring Product Information for Use in Selling) "}, {"number": 99, "question": "When a customer buying an appliance, piece of electronics, or vehicle asks questions about repairs, the salesperson should explain features and benefits relating to its ", "choices": ["A. service and warranty.", "B. popularity.", "C. history.", "D. appearance and style."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Service and warranty. When a customer buying an appliance, piece of electronics, or vehicle asks questions about repairs, the salesperson should explain features and benefits relating to its service and warranty. In some cases, whether or not a customer buys depends on the service your company offers and/or the warranty on the product. These factors may convince the customer to buy, and they are more important to a practical customer than a product's popularity, appearance, style, or history. SOURCE: SE:109 SOURCE: LAP-SE-113\u2014Find Features, Boost Benefits (Feature-Benefit Selling) "}, {"number": 100, "question": "A human resources manager sets up a computerized system for maintaining employee records. What type of resource is the manager using? ", "choices": ["A. Material", "B. Financial", "C. Human", "D. Natural"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Material. Material resources are equipment and supplies used by businesses in their operation. Financial resources are all the sources of money available to the business. Human resources are people who work to produce goods or services. Natural resources are resources found in nature that are used to produce goods and services. SOURCE: SM:001 SOURCE: LAP-SM-003\u2014Manage This! (Concept of Management"}], "1184-FIN": [{"number": 1, "question": "Businesses must comply with regulations that limit the amount and type of pollution and waste they produce. These regulations are referred to as __________ laws. ", "choices": ["A. environmental", "B. antitrust", "C. property", "D. industrial"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Environmental. The purpose of environmental laws is to protect the natural environment\u2014the air, soil, and water. Environmental laws help reduce pollution and govern the ways in which individuals and all types of businesses (e.g., service, industrial businesses) dispose of waste. Businesses that do not comply with environmental laws may be fined by the government or shut down. Antitrust laws protect free trade and competition in the marketplace. Property laws regulate the ownership of land and buildings. SOURCE: BL:073 SOURCE: Brown University. (2018). Fields of law. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from https://www.brown.edu/academics/college/advising/law-school/fields-law/fields-law "}, {"number": 2, "question": "What form of business ownership is best to use when the business owners have difficulty acquiring enough money to pay for the startup costs and initial operating expenses? ", "choices": ["A. Partnership", "B. Sole proprietorship", "C. Franchise", "D. Corporation"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Corporation. By starting a corporation, the business owners can sell stock to raise the necessary capital to cover business expenses. By owning the majority of the stock themselves, they can still control the business. A sole proprietorship is a business owned by one person. A major disadvantage of a partnership is that the capital available is limited to the partners' resources, so partnership is not the best option for the business owners. A franchise owner buys the right to sell the goods or services of the parent company. Franchises are business ownership options rather than legal business structures. SOURCE: BL:003 SOURCE: LAP-BL-001\u2014Own It Your Way (Types of Business Ownership) "}, {"number": 3, "question": "An important purpose of full-disclosure laws and regulations is to ", "choices": ["A. allow company employees to use inside information for personal gain.", "B. provide information to investors so they can make informed decisions.", "C. require companies to disclose all information about their operations.", "D. prevent a stock's par value from dropping below its market value."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Provide information to investors so they can make informed decisions. Full-disclosure laws and regulations require companies to disclose\u2014publicize\u2014any information that could affect the value of the firms' stocks. Investors need this information so they can make informed buy, hold, or sell decisions about investments. Full-disclosure laws also prevent company employees and other insiders from using privileged information for their personal gain. Full-disclosure laws do not require companies to disclose every bit of information about their operations\u2014some undisclosed trade secrets are permitted. Fulldisclosure laws and regulations are not designed to impact par values of stock. SOURCE: BL:133 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2018, April 18). Full disclosure. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from https://www.investopedia.com/terms/f/fulldisclosure.asp "}, {"number": 4, "question": "Which of the following is a tax-deductible gift: ", "choices": ["A. Stocks", "B. Vacation home", "C. Charitable donation", "D. Inherited items"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Charitable donation. Gifts are money, financial products, or property given to an individual or organization. Some gifts, such as charitable donations, are tax deductible. This means that the donor pays a reduced amount of tax or is exempt from paying the tax, depending on the type and value of the gift. Vacation homes, stocks, and inherited items are taxable gifts. SOURCE: BL:134 SOURCE: Internal Revenue Service. (2018, August 20). Frequently asked questions on gift taxes. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from https://www.irs.gov/businesses/small-businesses-selfemployed/frequently-asked-questions-on-gift-taxes "}, {"number": 5, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a preventive internal control: ", "choices": ["A. Physical inventories", "B. Data reconciliations", "C. Variance analyses", "D. Segregation of duties"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Segregation of duties. Several types of internal controls are used in compliance. Preventive controls such as the segregation of duties attempt to prevent unwanted events (noncompliance) from occurring. Detective controls, on the other hand, are used to identify and document noncompliance. Data reconciliations, variance analyses, and physical inventories are all detective internal controls. Corrective controls are used after noncompliance has been identified. They may include disciplinary action or additional training. SOURCE: BL:148 SOURCE: Bradford, C. (2017, November 21). Examples of internal controls. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from https://smallbusiness.chron.com/examples-internal-controls-57039.html Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 14 "}, {"number": 6, "question": "What type of technology do businesses use to inspect financial transactions and ensure that they are in compliance with government regulations? ", "choices": ["A. Domain computing", "B. Cyber mapping", "C. Virtual auditors", "D. Simulation browsers"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Virtual auditors. A virtual auditor is a type of compliance technology that uses multiple reasoning processes to help businesses identify errors that affect their compliance with government regulations. Using this technology provides a business with the ability to fix problems quickly and reduce risks associated with noncompliance. Businesses do not use cyber mapping, domain computing, or simulation browsers to inspect financial transactions and ensure that they are in compliance with government regulations. SOURCE: BL:149 SOURCE: Virtual Auditor. (2018). Virtual auditor. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://www.virtualauditor.com/ "}, {"number": 7, "question": "A researcher should consider an author's expertise in a particular topic when assessing the validity of written articles and publications to ", "choices": ["A. analyze the author's emotional intelligence.", "B. verify the timeliness of the information.", "C. evaluate the author's level of credibility.", "D. confirm personal understanding of the information."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Evaluate the author's level of credibility. When conducting research for a business, it is important to consider the source's level of credibility. A person who has extensive knowledge of or expertise in a specific topic is more credible and more likely to present valid or reliable information. For example, an article about the side effects of a medication tends to be more credible if it was written by a doctor or pharmacist rather than if the article was written by a financial planner or mechanic. Although the timeliness of written material is a consideration, it is not related to the author's level of expertise. A researcher cannot always determine the author's level of emotional intelligence by reading a written document. And, it is possible to possess a high level of knowledge about a subject and have low emotional intelligence. The way in which the article is written, rather the author's expertise, will impact the understandability of the information. SOURCE: CO:054 SOURCE: University of California Santa Cruz. (2018, September 6). Evaluate the quality and credibility of your sources. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://library.ucsc.edu/help/research/evaluate-the-quality-and-credibility-of-your-sources "}, {"number": 8, "question": "What method of note-taking involves using headings and subheadings to record the relationships and content in a well-organized, multi-level structure? ", "choices": ["A. Sentence", "B. Outline", "C. Mapping", "D. Shorthand"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Outline. The outline format of note-taking involves organizing the content in levels. Under each heading or subheading, the note taker writes short descriptive phrases or key points that relate to the heading or subheading. The sentence method of note-taking involves writing each new thought, topic, or point on a separate line. A disadvantage to using the sentence method is that the content is not always connected to or organized in relation to a previous topic, point, or category of information. Mapping is a visual method of note-taking that involves writing the main topic in a shape (e.g., circle or rectangle) and writing supporting ideas around the shape. Shorthand is a note-taking method that involves the use of symbols and abbreviations to represent words. SOURCE: CO:085 SOURCE: University of Redlands. (2015, June 18). Five notetaking methods. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://www.redlands.edu/globalassets/depts/student-life/academicsuccess/skills-worksheets/1five_methods_of_notetaking_2015.pdf "}, {"number": 9, "question": "In a formal business letter, the salutation is written ", "choices": ["A. after the body of the letter.", "B. on the front of the envelope.", "C. on the back of the envelope.", "D. before the body of the letter."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Before the body of the letter. The word \u201csalutation\u201d comes from the Latin word \u201csalve,\u201d which means \u201chello\u201d or \u201cwelcome.\u201d Therefore, the salutation is a greeting that is written immediately before the beginning of the business letter. Salutations usually begin with the word \u201cdear,\u201d followed by the addressee's name and sometimes his/her title. The salutation is not written on the front or back of the envelope or after the body of the letter. SOURCE: CO:133 SOURCE: Purdue Online Writing Lab. (1995-2018). Writing the basic business letter. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://owl.purdue.edu/owl/subject_specific_writing/professional_technical_writing/basic_busi ness_letters/index.html Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15 "}, {"number": 10, "question": "What is an example of a topic that would be addressed in an informational message? ", "choices": ["A. Request for payment on a past-due account", "B. Date and time of appointment with customer", "C. Charitable appeal for a corporate donation", "D. Invitation to speak at a national conference"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Date and time of appointment with customer. Informational messages are written every day in business in order to send routine information to others. Sending a customer a message confirming the date and time of the next appointment is an example of a topic that would be addressed in an informational message. The topic concerns routine information and deals with common business situations. Requesting payment on a past-due account, a charity appealing for a donation, or inviting someone to speak at a conference are examples of topics that would be addressed in persuasive messages. SOURCE: CO:039 SOURCE: Whalen, S. (2016, September 4). Written communication: Informative versus persuasive messages. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://salemwhalen.wordpress.com/2016/09/04/written-communication-informative-versuspersuasive-messages/ "}, {"number": 11, "question": "Because Caroline does not have enough time to read an entire 400-page business report, what section of the report should she review to obtain an overview of the most important content? ", "choices": ["A. Appendices", "B. Table of contents", "C. Executive summary", "D. Conclusions"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Executive summary. The executive summary provides an overview of the entire report and contains the most important information included in the body of the report. When businesspeople have time constraints, they often read the executive summary of a lengthy report. The table of contents is the portion of the report in which the various report sections are listed with their page numbers for easy access. The appendices are segments that are added to the end of the report and provide supporting information. The conclusion section of the report summarizes results and in some reports, this section includes recommendations for a certain course of action. SOURCE: CO:091 SOURCE: Roberts, S.J. (2012). Fundamentals of business communication (1st ed.) [pp. 420, 423]. Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Company. "}, {"number": 12, "question": "What type of information is often transmitted through upward communication? ", "choices": ["A. Instructions", "B. Suggestions", "C. Evaluations", "D. Corrections"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Suggestions. Upward communication involves sending a message to someone at a higher level in the business. Many businesses encourage upward communication by making it possible for employees to send suggestions and comments to management. Employees who have suggestions on how to improve quality or make positive changes are given an opportunity to transmit that information upward to managers. Instructions, evaluations, and corrections are usually transmitted from a higher level down to employees at a lower level. SOURCE: CO:014 SOURCE: Roberts, S.J. (2012). Fundamentals of business communication (1st ed.) [pp. 27-28]. Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Company. "}, {"number": 13, "question": "It is appropriate for a participant to ask questions during a staff meeting when ", "choices": ["A. s/he needs a point clarified.", "B. another participant is speaking.", "C. the agenda is being distributed.", "D. s/he does not agree with the speaker."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "S/He needs a point clarified. When employees do not understand what the speaker has said, it is appropriate to raise their hand to ask for clarification; however, it is rude to interrupt another person while s/he is speaking. In many meetings, the leader will ask the participants if they have questions, and it would be appropriate to ask for clarification at that time. Asking questions due to differing opinions or when the agenda is being distributed may not be appropriate. SOURCE: CO:063 SOURCE: Jarrow, C. (2013). Did you participate in the meeting or were you just there? Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://timemanagementninja.com/2013/10/did-you-participate-inthe-meeting-or-were-you-just-there/ "}, {"number": 14, "question": "A customer asked a salesperson whether a hair dryer purchased last month could be returned or exchanged. In order to answer the question, the salesperson should be familiar with the business's ", "choices": ["A. finances.", "B. promotions.", "C. policies.", "D. products."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Policies. Policies are established by businesses to ensure that employees make consistent decisions in handling transactions. All staff should be thoroughly familiar with the business's policies and use them as guidelines. Salespersons should also be familiar with the business's products and promotions, but that information will not help in this situation. Some salespersons are knowledgeable about the business's finances, but that information would also not be useful here. SOURCE: CR:007 SOURCE: Burrow, J., & Kleindl, B. (2013). Business management (13th ed.) [pp. 88-89]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16 "}, {"number": 15, "question": "Which of the following types of customer relationship management software would be most appropriate for a company that is looking for a more efficient way to track potential new clients and customers: ", "choices": ["A. Matching engine technology", "B. Campaign management software", "C. Personalization technology", "D. Sales force automation"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Sales force automation. Many companies use sales force automation (SFA) technology to support, coordinate, and increase the productivity of their sales professionals. SFA technology, which is a type of customer relationship management software, can help automate many aspects of the sales process, such as tracking leads, prospects, and customers. Other SFA technology features include contact management, sales forecasting, and sales report generation. Campaign management software is used by marketers to develop, execute, and track the effectiveness of promotional campaigns to targeted groups of potential or established customers. Businesses often use personalization technology to target certain products to certain customers based on the customer's purchase history. Matching engine technology works in a similar manner. Based on a particular customer's needs or preferences, matching engine technology determines the product offering that would best appeal to that customer. SOURCE: CR:018 SOURCE: Krasnoff, B. (2018, July 13). The best lead management software of 2018. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://www.pcmag.com/roundup/356147/the-best-leadmanagement-software "}, {"number": 16, "question": "What is the most common reason for a client to leave or fire his/her financial advisor? ", "choices": ["A. Location of the office", "B. Poor investment return", "C. High commission fees", "D. Lack of communication"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Lack of communication. Although a poor investment return, high commission fees, or the geographic location of the financial advisor's office may influence a client's decision to leave the advisor, the most common reason given for firing a financial advisor is a lack of communication. Above all else, financial clients expect\u2014and need\u2014their advisors to communicate on a regular basis. This means returning the clients' phone calls as soon as possible, replying quickly to their emails, and contacting them regularly to discuss their accounts and answer any questions that they might have. SOURCE: CR:012 SOURCE: O'Connell, B. (n.d.). Why clients fire financial advisors. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://www.investopedia.com/articles/professionals/071113/why-clients-fire-financialadvisors.asp "}, {"number": 17, "question": "Businesses use data-cleansing applications to ", "choices": ["A. calculate statistical data.", "B. update their databases.", "C. duplicate internal records.", "D. generate necessary reports."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Update their databases. Businesses use data-cleansing applications to ensure that their customer databases contain useful, relevant, and accurate data. The data-cleansing process removes duplicate records, updates expired data, and completes incomplete data fields. When a business's database is current and up to date, it can generate accurate reports that help the business make well-informed decisions. Businesses do not use data-cleansing applications to calculate statistical data. SOURCE: CR:024 SOURCE: Technopedia. (2010-2018). Data cleansing. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://www.techopedia.com/definition/1174/data-cleansing"}, {"number": 18, "question": "Justin is trying to decide whether he wants to spend a $50 birthday check on a new video game or tickets to a concert. If he chooses the video game, what is the opportunity cost of this decision? ", "choices": ["A. Birthday check", "B. Video game", "C. Concert tickets", "D. $50"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Concert tickets. Opportunity cost is the benefit that is lost when a decision is made to use scarce resources for one purpose rather than for another. In this case, the concert tickets were given up; therefore, they are the opportunity cost. SOURCE: EC:001 SOURCE: LAP-EC-006\u2014Are You Satisfied? (Economics and Economic Activities) "}, {"number": 19, "question": "Which of the following is most likely to affect the selling price of roses: ", "choices": ["A. A large number of rose bushes are killed by disease.", "B. Plants and small shrubs are also sold at the flower shop.", "C. The flower shop also carries silk flowers.", "D. A reorder shipment of roses arrives."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "A large number of rose bushes are killed by disease. This would reduce the supply of roses and increase the price of the flowers. Any factor that causes changes in supply and demand will also cause changes in prices. The assortment carried does not affect the price of the other flowers. SOURCE: EC:006 SOURCE: LAP-EC-012\u2014When More Is Less (Functions of Prices) Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17 "}, {"number": 20, "question": "What must a business be organized to do to be able to contribute to society? ", "choices": ["A. Preserve the environment", "B. Earn a profit", "C. Sell an idea", "D. Hire an advisor"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Earn a profit. The goal of business is to earn a profit. If businesses do not earn a profit, they will not be able to contribute to society. Businesses contribute to society in many ways, and most of these require money. For example, they create jobs and hire employees so members of the community have income to support themselves and their families. Businesses often allow employees to participate in certain community activities on company time, such as cleaning up a neighborhood. Businesses also donate money to support community programs. None of this would be possible if the business was not organized in a way that allowed it to earn a profit. SOURCE: EC:103 SOURCE: LAP-EC-103\u2014Designed To Work (Organizational Design of Businesses) "}, {"number": 21, "question": "Which of the following is a result of globalization: ", "choices": ["A. Shrinking product life cycles", "B. Decreased competition", "C. Increased consumer spending", "D. Higher productivity"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Higher productivity. Higher productivity is a result of globalization. When countries or regions concentrate on creating specific goods or services in which they have a production advantage, productivity goes up all over the world. Globalization also results in increased competition. The trend does not necessarily affect consumer spending or product life cycles. SOURCE: EC:107 SOURCE: LAP-EC-107\u2014Keep the Change (Adapting to Markets) "}, {"number": 22, "question": "What type of tax are businesses required to pay on the profits they earn? ", "choices": ["A. Excise", "B. Income", "C. Sales", "D. Property"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Income. Income tax is a tax on profit. When businesses earn a profit from supplying goods and services to consumers, they pay a certain percentage of that profit to the government. The tax that businesses pay on the profits they earn is not an example of excise or sales tax. Property tax is a tax on material goods rather than on profit. SOURCE: EC:072 SOURCE: LAP-EC-027\u2014Pay Your Share (Business Taxes) "}, {"number": 23, "question": "Allowing employees to make more decisions, set their own work pace, and supervise coworkers is considered to be job ", "choices": ["A. rotation.", "B. satisfaction.", "C. enrichment.", "D. enlargement."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Enrichment. Job enrichment refers to adding interest and satisfaction to a job task. Making decisions, setting work pace, and supervising fellow employees could all be ways of adding interest and satisfaction to a job. Job rotation refers to exposing employees to more than one job task. Job satisfaction refers to an employee's contentment with his/her job tasks. Job enlargement refers to combining specific job tasks in an effort to create exposure to more than just one work area. All four of these are ways in which companies combat job boredom, decreased morale, or other negatives in the workplace. SOURCE: EC:014 SOURCE: LAP-EC-007\u2014Divide and Conquer (Specialization and Division of Labor) "}, {"number": 24, "question": "The rate of underemployed workers is often highest when a nation is experiencing an economic ", "choices": ["A. recession.", "B. expansion.", "C. peak.", "D. inhibition."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Recession. A recession occurs when an economic contraction exists for at least six consecutive months. During this time, consumer spending decreases and companies reduce hiring or lay off workers. As a result, jobs are more difficult to obtain and many workers take jobs for which they are overqualified. These workers are underemployed workers. During times of expansion or when a business cycle peaks, employment opportunities tend to increase, reducing the number underemployed workers. Inhibition is not a common term that describes a phase of a business cycle. SOURCE: EC:082 SOURCE: LAP-EC-029\u2014Help Wanted? (Impact of Unemployment Rates) "}, {"number": 25, "question": "Businesspeople must be cautious not to offend their international customers by understanding the importance of nonverbal cues, which include the use of ", "choices": ["A. proper grammar.", "B. accurate word pronunciation.", "C. hand gestures.", "D. interactive feedback."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Hand gestures. Nonverbal communication (body language) involves gestures or facial expressions rather than the use of words. Because different countries have unique cultural and social behaviors, it is important for businesspeople to understand these differences when doing business in other nations. For example, a hand gesture may mean a sign of friendship in one country but be a sign of disrespect in another country. Word pronunciation and grammar usage are language (verbal) issues. Interactive feedback is a general term that includes both verbal and nonverbal communication elements. SOURCE: EC:045 SOURCE: LAP-EC-045\u2014On Top of the World (Impact of Culture on Global Trade) Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18 "}, {"number": 26, "question": "Which of the following is a main cause of prejudice and discrimination: ", "choices": ["A. A lack of knowledge about a group of people", "B. Exposing yourself to new situations", "C. Openly discussing bias with others", "D. Naturally occurring differences of opinion"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "A lack of knowledge about a group of people. If you are surrounded by those who are just like you, you may not understand people who are different. You may experience discomfort or even fear when you do encounter someone different, which can lead you to resort to prejudicial thinking. Exposing yourself to new situations and openly discussing bias with others can decrease prejudice and discrimination rather than causing it. Finally, naturally occurring differences of opinion might cause disagreements, but they do not cause prejudice and discrimination. SOURCE: EI:017 SOURCE: LAP-EI-139\u2014Don't Jump to Conclusions! (Recognizing and Overcoming Personal Biases and Stereotypes) "}, {"number": 27, "question": "Susan is a purchasing manager for a manufacturer. On Monday, Susan received a call from the plant manager, who frantically told Susan that the production line ran out of 3/8\u201d washers, which has forced production to stop. Because Jason is the senior buyer in charge of ordering the washers, Susan set up a meeting with Jason to discuss the problem. During the meeting, Susan asked Jason to explain why the washers were out of stock. Jason replied, \u201cWell, I told the office assistant to check the inventory. It's not my fault that we don't have the washers in stock.\u201d What is Jason doing? ", "choices": ["A. Denying that a problem exists", "B. Helping Susan resolve the problem", "C. Providing Susan with a valid reason for the stock-out", "D. Blaming another person for his mistake"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Blaming another person for his mistake. Taking responsibility for your actions involves accepting the consequences (good or bad) of your behavior, admitting and learning from your mistakes, and trying to do better in the future. In the example, Jason blamed the office assistant for the mistake, but he is the employee who is responsible for ordering the washers. By blaming another employee, Jason is failing to accept responsibility for his actions. Jason was not helping Susan resolve the problem, providing a valid reason for the stock-out, or denying that a problem exists. SOURCE: EI:075 SOURCE: LAP-EI-075\u2014It's Up to You (Taking Responsibility for Decisions and Actions) "}, {"number": 28, "question": "Joe has a two-hour sales meeting with a new customer at 10 a.m. today. Early this morning, a vendor telephoned Joe to schedule a one-hour luncheon meeting to discuss a co-op advertising program. The vendor would like to meet at a restaurant that is 30 minutes from Joe's office at 1:00 p.m. today. Joe must be back at his office by 2:00 p.m. for an important computer training session. Should Joe meet with the vendor today? ", "choices": ["A. Yes. Joe can meet with the vendor after the vendor changes the lunch reservation to 12:45 p.m.", "B. No. It is rude for the vendor to assume that Joe has time to meet today.", "C. Yes. Joe can meet with the vendor after he reschedules his training session.", "D. No. Joe would have only 30 minutes to meet with the vendor before he needs to return to the"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "No. Joe would have only 30 minutes to meet with the vendor before he needs to return to the office. Managing work commitments in a timely manner involves allowing enough time to complete the most important tasks first. Joe had commitments that he needs to keep from 10 a.m. to 12 p.m. and at 2:00 p.m. Because the vendor asked Joe to meet at a restaurant that was 30 minutes away from his office, he doesn't have enough time to meet with the vendor for one hour at 1:00 p.m. If the vendor is not available at an earlier time at a closer location, Joe must decline the luncheon invitation and schedule it at a time that is more convenient for both of them. It's not unusual for last-minute meetings to take place, if other commitments are not an issue. Therefore, the vendor was not being rude by asking Joe if he had time to meet. There is not enough information to determine if Joe had the authority to reschedule the training session. Moving the lunch reservation to 12:45 p.m. would not help because Joe would be 15 minutes late to his training session. SOURCE: EI:077 SOURCE: LAP-EI-077\u2014Commit to It! (Managing Commitments in a Timely Manner) "}, {"number": 29, "question": "Typical characteristics of a person with a negative attitude are that s/he is ", "choices": ["A. courteous and considerate toward others.", "B. inflexible and resistant to change.", "C. generous and helpful to others.", "D. flexible and open to new ideas."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Inflexible and resistant to change. Negative people tend to be inflexible and resistant to change. Being flexible and open to new ideas, generous and helpful, courteous and considerate are all characteristics of someone with a positive attitude. SOURCE: EI:019 SOURCE: LAP-EI-003\u2014Opt for Optimism (Positive Attitude) "}, {"number": 30, "question": "When you react defensively to criticism, the result is likely to be ", "choices": ["A. pleasant.", "B. sympathetic.", "C. negative.", "D. cooperative."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Negative. A person who is defensive is easily angered or upset by criticism or suggestions perceived as criticism. His/Her defensive response is usually irritating to the person offering the criticism or suggestions, which may trigger an unsympathetic, unpleasant, or uncooperative reaction from the speaker. SOURCE: EI:003 SOURCE: LAP-EI-015\u2014Grin and Bear It (Using Feedback for Personal Growth) "}, {"number": 31, "question": "Being able to put yourself in another person's place means that you have ", "choices": ["A. perspective.", "B. respect.", "C. empathy.", "D. understanding."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Empathy. Empathy is the ability to put yourself in another person's place or to \"walk in another person's shoes.\" Respect is honor and esteem. Perspective is the way in which people view life. Understanding is the ability to comprehend or to think and learn. SOURCE: EI:030 SOURCE: LAP-EI-030\u2014Have a Heart (Showing Empathy for Others) Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19 "}, {"number": 32, "question": "What is the first step toward building trusting relationships? ", "choices": ["A. Increasing sales", "B. Increasing productivity", "C. Developing ideas", "D. Being transparent"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Being transparent. Being transparent is the first step toward building trusting relationships. Increased productivity, better ideas, and increased sales are all benefits of transparency. SOURCE: EI:129 SOURCE: LAP-EI-129\u2014Can We Talk? (Fostering Open, Honest Communication) "}, {"number": 33, "question": "An example of assertive verbal behavior would be ", "choices": ["A. complimenting someone to obtain a favor.", "B. maintaining appropriate eye contact.", "C. initiating conversations with others.", "D. giving a progress report in a staff meeting."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Initiating conversations with others. Taking the initiative to approach other people and begin conversations is a good example of assertive verbal behavior. Other examples include openly expressing your positive or negative thoughts, asking questions, and requesting help. Maintaining appropriate eye contact is an example of nonverbal behavior. Giving a progress report in a staff meeting is a routine job task that does not demonstrate assertive verbal behavior. Complimenting someone to obtain a favor is not assertive but dishonest and manipulative. SOURCE: EI:008 SOURCE: LAP-EI-018\u2014Assert Yourself (Assertiveness) "}, {"number": 34, "question": "Ethical behavior increases productivity and morale because it ", "choices": ["A. makes employees want to support the organization's mission.", "B. makes sure people are following the rules.", "C. leads to increased profits and more product sales.", "D. makes sure laws are never broken."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Makes employees want to support the organization's mission. When all people involved in a group behave ethically, it runs better. Productivity and morale are higher because everyone feels respected and wants to contribute to the success of the organization. They are likely to agree with and support the organization's mission. Ethical behavior does not necessarily ensure that people are following the rules. It also does not necessarily lead to increased profits and more product sales, although it can help make an organization more successful. While ethical behavior generally correlates with the law, it does not necessarily make sure that laws are never broken. SOURCE: EI:132 SOURCE: LAP-EI-132\u2014Practice What You Preach (Modeling Ethical Behavior) "}, {"number": 35, "question": "When a person is inspired, s/he is ", "choices": ["A. driven to take action.", "B. disengaged from work.", "C. uninterested and bored.", "D. likely to break the rules."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Driven to take action. When a person is inspired, s/he is driven to take action. An inspired individual is not disengaged from work, uninterested, bored, or likely to break the rules. In fact, inspired people are typically more engaged, enthusiastic, and excited about their work. SOURCE: EI:133 SOURCE: LAP-EI-133\u2014A Force for Good (Inspiring Others) "}, {"number": 36, "question": "Unethical actions ", "choices": ["A. are acceptable if everyone else does them.", "B. always have legal consequences.", "C. are not always illegal.", "D. only affect the person doing them."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Are not always illegal. Being unethical does not always mean breaking the law, so it doesn't always have legal consequences. An unethical action doesn't become acceptable if everyone is doing it. Behaving ethically means doing the right thing, no matter what. Unethical behavior doesn't just affect the person doing it\u2014it can affect everyone. SOURCE: EI:123 SOURCE: LAP-EI-123\u2014Rules to Live By (Nature of Ethics) "}, {"number": 37, "question": "At what stage of the entrepreneurial process does an entrepreneur determine the amount of capital needed to launch the business? ", "choices": ["A. Actualization", "B. Discovery", "C. Development", "D. Harvesting"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Development. An entrepreneur determines the amount of capital needed to launch a business during the development stage of the entrepreneurial process. The discovery stage involves exploring potential business opportunities for feasibility and profitability. Actualization, the actual launching and running of the business, cannot occur until capital has been obtained. Harvesting is the final step when the entrepreneur determines how to exit the business. SOURCE: EN:039 SOURCE: Business Jargons. (n.d.). Entrepreneurial process. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://businessjargons.com/entrepreneurial-process.html Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20 "}, {"number": 38, "question": "By understanding the time value of money concept, you know that ", "choices": ["A. saving money can buy time on debt payment.", "B. it is better to receive $101 a year from now than $100 today.", "C. it is better to receive $100 today than $101 a year from now.", "D. time and money are related by due date."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "It is better to receive $100 today than $101 a year from now. According to the concept of the time value of money, the sooner money is received the more time you have to let it grow. Receiving money later costs you the opportunity to earn interest or other appreciation. Saving money will not buy time on debt payment. Time and money are not related by due date. SOURCE: FI:062 SOURCE: Carther, S. (2018, May 18). Understanding the time value of money. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://www.investopedia.com/articles/03/082703.asp "}, {"number": 39, "question": "Margot wants to be sure that when she dies, her money, house, and cars will go to her sister. Margot should create a ", "choices": ["A. will.", "B. retirement fund.", "C. college savings fund.", "D. bank account."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Will. A will is a legal document that outlines how a person wishes his/her assets to be distributed once s/he dies. If Margot wants to be sure that her sister receives her assets, she should set up a will. Retirement funds, college savings funds, and bank accounts do not guarantee that Margot's assets will be given to her sister. SOURCE: FI:064 SOURCE: Williams, G. (2018, June 19). 10 steps to writing a will. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://money.usnews.com/money/personal-finance/family-finance/articles/steps-to-writing-awill "}, {"number": 40, "question": "When should you record bank transactions in your check register? ", "choices": ["A. When checks bounce", "B. When bank statements are received", "C. As bank statements are reconciled", "D. As soon as each check is written"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "As soon as each check is written. To keep accurate records, you need to record all information in the check register as each transaction occurs. Otherwise, the date, check number, or check amount may be recorded inaccurately. Waiting to record check information can result in difficulties with balancing bank statements when they arrive. This could also result in checks being returned to you for inadequate funds. SOURCE: FI:069 SOURCE: Mycreditunion.gov. (2018). Understanding a check and balancing a checkbook. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://www.mycreditunion.gov/Pages/pocket-cents-understandinga-check-and-balancing-checkbook.aspx "}, {"number": 41, "question": "Which of the following international financial institutions provides financing and advice to countries to encourage economic development: ", "choices": ["A. Commonwealth of Nations", "B. Small Business Administration", "C. World Bank Group", "D. Liberty Institute"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "World Bank Group. The World Bank Group, which includes the World Bank as well as several other international organizations, is an international financial institution that provides financing and advice to impoverished countries to encourage economic development and eliminate poverty. The Small Business Administration is a U.S. government financial institution that provides financial assistance and advice to American small businesses. The Commonwealth of Nations and the Liberty Institute are not financial institutions. The Commonwealth of Nations is an international organization that promotes world peace, democracy, and free trade. The Liberty Institute is an international organization based in the country of Georgia that advocates civil liberties as well as public accountability and effective governance. SOURCE: FI:336 SOURCE: Investopedia (n.d.) The world bank. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://www.investopedia.com/terms/w/worldbank.asp "}, {"number": 42, "question": "Which of the following statements regarding debt and equity markets is correct: ", "choices": ["A. If a company suffers financial difficulties, its stockholders are paid before its bondholders.", "B. Investors who purchase a company's bonds gain partial ownership of the business.", "C. Bonds, which are debt instruments, are typically less risky investments than stocks.", "D. Common stock, an example of a debt instrument, is traded on the equity market."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Bonds, which are debt instruments, are typically less risky investments than stocks. Equity instruments such as common stock are traded on the equity market. Individuals who purchase equity instruments, not debt instruments such as bonds, gain partial ownership of a business. If a company suffers financial difficulties, its bondholders are paid before its stockholders. SOURCE: FI:337 SOURCE: Scrofano, J. (2017, September 26). Debt and equity instruments. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://bizfluent.com/list-7178096-debt-equity-instruments.html Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21 "}, {"number": 43, "question": "The Money for You Bank recently merged with the Keeping You Safe Insurance Company. The merger is an example of __________ in the finance industry. ", "choices": ["A. licensing", "B. consolidation", "C. tactical planning", "D. convergence"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Convergence. Convergence occurs when financial providers from different financial sectors (e.g., banking services and insurance) merge. Consolidation takes place when financial providers within the same institutional category merge. For example, if two banks were to merge, they would be consolidating their companies. Tactical planning is short-range planning (one year) of specific actions the business will take. Two businesses should look much further ahead than just one year before making the decision to merge. Licensing is a business structure that requires the authorization or permission from an owner of another entity to use trademarked, copyrighted, or patented material for a specific activity, during a specific time period, for the profit of both parties. Businesses that enter into licensing agreements do not merge. SOURCE: FI:573 SOURCE: Abel, S., & Back, C. (2016). Achieving convergence of finance, risk and actuarial functions: Beyond transformations. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://www.ey.com/Publication/vwLUAssets/ey-achieving-convergence-of-finance-risk-andactuarial-function-beyond-transformation/$FILE/ey-achieving-convergence-of-finance-riskand-actuarial-function-beyond-transformation.pdf "}, {"number": 44, "question": "When the unemployment rate rises, stock values typically ", "choices": ["A. increase.", "B. decrease.", "C. stabilize quickly.", "D. remain unchanged."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Decrease. Economic factors such as the unemployment rate can affect stock prices. If trends indicate a rise in unemployment rates, the economy may be heading into a recession. In this situation, individuals are often fearful about losing their jobs and are likely to hold onto their money rather than invest it. They may also sell their stock in anticipation of needing the money for living expenses. Businesses often react the same way\u2014they may hold onto their funds until the economy rebounds before making major investments. All these factors can cause the value of stocks to decrease. SOURCE: FI:574 SOURCE: Levitt, A. (n.d.). Economic indicators that affect the U.S. stock market. Retrieved September 11, 2018, from http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/031413/economic-indicatiorsaffect-us-stock-market.asp "}, {"number": 45, "question": "Which of the following has contributed to financial globalization: ", "choices": ["A. An increase in restrictions on foreign investment and international trade", "B. An increase in taxes on international financial transactions", "C. A reduction in foreigners' access to domestic financial markets", "D. A movement from fixed exchange rates to floating exchange rates"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "A movement from fixed exchange rates to floating exchange rates. A fixed exchange rate is one that the government sets and maintains. A fixed exchange rate does not change very often. A floating exchange rate, on the other hand, is constantly in flux\u2014determined by the market through supply and demand. To enable capital to flow more freely across their national borders, countries around the world have moved from fixed to floating exchange rates, lowered taxes on international financial transactions, increased foreigners' access to domestic financial markets, and decreased restrictions on foreign investment and international trade. SOURCE: FI:575 SOURCE: Pologeorgis, N. (n.d.). The globalization of financial services. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://www.investopedia.com/articles/financial-theory/09/risk-free-rate-return.asp "}, {"number": 46, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about stock information resources: ", "choices": ["A. It has never been easier to find stock information.", "B. There are very few stock information sources.", "C. Only wealthy investors have access to stock information.", "D. It is very difficult to find stock information."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "It has never been easier to find stock information. A few short years ago, only professionals and wealthy investors had access to in-depth stock information. Now, there is a great deal of easy-to-find information, all available to the individual investor. SOURCE: FI:274 SOURCE: Ryan, J.S. (2012). Personal financial literacy (2nd ed.) [pp. 377-380]. Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning. Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22 "}, {"number": 47, "question": "Analyze the information in the securities table about Home Depot. 52-WEEK YLD HI LO STOCK (SYM) P/E CLOSE CHG EARNINGS DIV % 37.03 26.62 Home Depot (HD) 18.92 35.01 +.62 1.85 0.95 2.7 Based on the information provided, which of the following statements about Home Depot is most likely to be accurate: ", "choices": ["A. The previous day's closing price was $34.39, $0.62 less than the last price for today.", "B. Home Depot's stock share price is 2.7 times higher than its earnings per share.", "C. The lowest price paid for Home Depot stock during the last year was $18.92.", "D. An investor who owned 100 shares of Home Depot's stock last quarter earned $27 in dividends."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The previous day's closing price was $34.39, $0.62 less than the last price for today. To calculate the previous day's closing price, investors can subtract the net change (the difference between the closing price and the previous day's closing price) from the last price for the day ($35.01 - $0.62 = $34.39). The price/earnings ratio (P/E) indicates how much higher the stock share price is than its earnings per share. So, Home Depot's stock share price is 18.92 times higher than its earnings per share. The lowest price paid for Home Depot stock during the last year was $26.62. An investor who owned 100 shares of Home Depot's stock last quarter earned $95 in dividends (100 shares X $0.95 per share = $95). SOURCE: FI:275 SOURCE: Ryan, J.S. (2012). Personal financial literacy (2nd ed.) [p. 394]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 48, "question": "Certificates of deposit and collectibles are types of ", "choices": ["A. earnings.", "B. accounts.", "C. securities.", "D. investments."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Investments. There is a wide range of investments available to individuals who want the opportunity to increase their worth. Some investments are riskier than others, which means that individuals might lose money rather than make money. Certificates of deposit are safe investments because they pay a guaranteed amount of interest over a specific period of time. Collectibles are a riskier type of investment because the collectible, such as a baseball card, might lose value over time and not have any worth. Certificates of deposit and collectibles are not types of accounts or securities. Certificates of deposit earn interest while collectibles may or may not increase in value. SOURCE: FI:077 SOURCE: LAP-FI-077\u2014Invest for Success (Types of Investments) "}, {"number": 49, "question": "When preparing a statement of changes in an owner's equity document, which of the following are specifically represented on the statement: ", "choices": ["A. New investments by the owner", "B. Property taxes paid by the owner", "C. Depreciation of company assets", "D. Lost revenue due to discharged debt"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "New investments by the owner. New investments or withdrawals by the owner are specifically represented on a statement of changes in an owner's equity document, as well as the business's net income or loss. Property taxes, depreciation of company assets, and lost revenue are considered when determining net income or loss, but they are not specifically listed on the statement of changes in an owner's equity document. SOURCE: FI:630 SOURCE: Guerrieri, D.J., Haber, F.B., Hoyt, W.B., & Turner, R.E. (2012). Accounting: Real-world applications & connections (First-year course) [pp. 228-231]. Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 50, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a finance professional exhibiting responsible behavior: ", "choices": ["A. During their first meeting, a financial planner asks Colin specific questions about his financial\ngoals.", "B. Katherine wants to make a large commission, so she tries to sell a high-risk financial product to a\nclient.", "C. A financial advisor delays contacting Olivia to advise her that the value of some of her stock is\nrapidly declining.", "D. During a dinner party, Ryan tells his friend specific details about a client's stock portfolio and"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "During their first meeting, a financial planner asks Colin specific questions about his financial goals. Responsible financial planners ask questions to determine their clients' financial goals and their comfort levels with risk. When financial planners understand their clients' financial needs and wants, they are better equipped to help their clients set realistic financial goals. The statement does not provide enough information to determine if Katherine's client is comfortable buying a high-risk financial product. If the client is not a risk-taker, then Katherine is acting irresponsibly. Sharing a client's confidential information with a friend and delaying bad news about an investment are irresponsible and unethical behaviors. SOURCE: FI:355 SOURCE: Peavler, R. (2018, April 26). Financial ethics will improve the profitability of your small business. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://bizfinance.about.com/od/fraud/a/Financial_Ethics.htm "}, {"number": 51, "question": "A new employee left JRB Manufacturing two weeks after s/he completed the company's training program. The expense of training the new employee is a(n) __________ for the company. ", "choices": ["A. external cost", "B. sunk cost", "C. current asset", "D. capital liability"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Sunk cost. Sunk costs are costs that are incurred and cannot be recovered. In the situation described, the business spent money to train an employee who quit shortly thereafter. The business will not be able to recoup the training costs because the employee is no longer there to perform the work that s/he was trained to do. Training is an internal cost. Current assets include things such as inventory, cash, accounts receivable, etc. A capital liability is the responsibility incurred when purchasing a capital asset such as a building or a piece of equipment. This often involves borrowing a large amount of money to obtain the asset. SOURCE: FI:658 SOURCE: Bragg. S. (2017, August 23). Sunk cost. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://www.accountingtools.com/articles/what-is-a-sunk-cost.html Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23 "}, {"number": 52, "question": "A managerial accountant can help a company market its products by ", "choices": ["A. examining the relevant costs of advertising options.", "B. determining whether to make or buy a component.", "C. developing a target market analysis.", "D. creating a budget for hiring increases."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Examining the relevant costs of advertising options. Managerial accountants can use techniques such as relevant cost analysis to assist marketers in making decisions regarding advertising options. They can determine which will have the lowest and highest costs. Determining whether to buy or make a component is not necessarily a marketing decision. Developing a target market analysis would generally not be a task for a managerial accountant. Creating a budget for hiring increases is not directly related to marketing products. SOURCE: FI:660 SOURCE: Freedman, J. (2018, June 27). Why management accounting is important in decisionmaking. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/managementaccounting-important-decisionmaking-53947.html "}, {"number": 53, "question": "What type of variance analysis involves determining the difference between the standard costs and the actual costs of raw materials used for production? ", "choices": ["A. Selling price", "B. Purchase price", "C. Material yield", "D. Fixed overhead"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Purchase price. A variance is the difference between an established standard and the actual outcome. It is important for a business to monitor variances in the price of raw materials because they affect its bottom line. When a vendor increases the prices that it charges for raw materials, it costs the business (manufacturer) more money to produce an item. The business may need to find a vendor that charges less for the materials or parts, or it may need to increase its selling price\u2014the amount that the business charges its customers for the finished good. Fixed overhead costs are expenses that do not change in relation to changes in sales volume and include things such as rent and employee salaries. Material yield analysis involves analyzing variances in the number of materials/products that are supposed to be used/sold with the actual number of materials/products that have been used/sold in a certain timeframe. SOURCE: FI:661 SOURCE: Bragg, S. (2017, August 30). Variance analysis. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://www.accountingtools.com/articles/what-is-variance-analysis.html "}, {"number": 54, "question": "Kenneth is easily able to guide the actions of his employees by referring to his budget. This is an example of which function of budgets? ", "choices": ["A. Controlling", "B. Planning", "C. Directing", "D. Monitoring"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Directing. Budgeting involves setting goals, executing those goals, and comparing results to those goals. Kenneth is executing his goals by directing his employees' actions with the help of his budget. Planning is setting goals. Controlling is comparing performance to expectations. Monitoring is tracking progress. They are all functions of budgets, but they are not specifically related to Kenneth's example. SOURCE: FI:662 SOURCE: Warren, C.S., Reeve, J.M., & Duchac, J. (2014). Managerial accounting (12th ed.) [p. 230]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 55, "question": "Gathering and communicating financial information that businesses can use to plan the business's operations is the focus of __________ accounting. ", "choices": ["A. accrual", "B. managerial", "C. financial", "D. equity"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Managerial. Managerial accounting involves obtaining and analyzing financial data, which the business can use to make decisions about how to operate the business. For example, businesses gather financial information to develop budgets to guide the business's operations. They also analyze costs in relation to profit in order to make decisions about which products to produce and sell. Accrual is a method of accounting that records transactions at the time they occur even if no money changes hands at the time. The focus of financial accounting is preparing information for external users. Equity is the net worth of the business. SOURCE: FI:657 SOURCE: Investopedia. (n.d.). Managerial accounting. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://www.investopedia.com/terms/m/managerialaccounting.asp "}, {"number": 56, "question": "Which of the following is an example of an indirect cost in an automobile factory: ", "choices": ["A. Shipping", "B. Glass", "C. Electricity", "D. Assembly line workers' salaries"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Electricity. Indirect costs are those which are not associated with one particular business activity and cannot easily be assigned to specific cost objects. Because electricity is used for many purposes in an automobile factory, it is considered an indirect cost. Glass is not an indirect cost because it goes toward specific products. Shipping costs, too, can be easily allocated to a particular product or business activity. Because the workers on an assembly line are contributing their efforts toward a particular product, their salaries can also be considered direct costs. Some employees' salaries are considered indirect, depending on the nature of their jobs. SOURCE: FI:663 SOURCE: Speilman, E. (2018, February 9). Direct costs vs. indirect costs: Understanding each. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://www.businessnewsdaily.com/5498-direct-costsindirect-costs.html Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24 "}, {"number": 57, "question": "What is one of the main purposes of a business's sales budget? ", "choices": ["A. To estimate income", "B. To forecast trends", "C. To predict the economy", "D. To track the competition"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "To estimate income. The sales budget sets the financial pace for a business by estimating what amount of expenses and income can be expected from the sale of the business's goods and services. Sales budgets are extremely important because they estimate the major source of income, which helps a business determine if it will be profitable. Businesses take into consideration future trends, the state of the economy, and the level of competition when developing sales budgets. SOURCE: FI:106 SOURCE: LAP-FI-106\u2014Money Tracks (Nature of Budgets) "}, {"number": 58, "question": "Yazmin earned $5,000 from her summer job. If she invests it at a rate of 5%, how much will it be worth in two years? ", "choices": ["A. $5,025.50", "B. $10,250", "C. $5,500", "D. $5,512.50"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "$5,512.50. The formula for calculating future value is Future Value = Present Value X (1 + Interest Rate)number of periods. To calculate the future value of Yazmin's investment, first add one to the interest rate (1+ 0.05 = 1.05). Then square that sum, which is the same as multiplying that sum by itself (1.052 = 1.05 X 1.05 = 1.1025). Finally, multiply the product by the original investment to determine the value of Yazmin's investment in two years (5,000 X 1.1025 = $5,512.50). SOURCE: FI:238 SOURCE: Carther, S. (2017, May 18). Understanding the time value of money. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from http://www.investopedia.com/articles/03/082703.asp "}, {"number": 59, "question": "What is the most negative information possible on a credit report? ", "choices": ["A. Collection agency report", "B. Late payment", "C. Lien", "D. Bankruptcy"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Bankruptcy. Bankruptcy is the last-resort action for poor credit. Late payments, liens, and collection agency reports all appear on a credit report, but none have as negative of an impact as bankruptcy. SOURCE: FI:568 SOURCE: Griffin, R. (2014, August 7). Bankruptcy may prevent qualifying for a credit card. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from http://www.experian.com/blogs/ask-experian/bankruptcy-creditcard/ "}, {"number": 60, "question": "An effective financial-information management system enables managers to obtain reports to determine how the company is using its funds. If the managers find that the company is not operating efficiently, they may reallocate funds from one business function to another to improve profitability. In this situation, the reports generated by the financial-information management system are ", "choices": ["A. guiding decision-making.", "B. ensuring compliance.", "C. improving customer service.", "D. tracking purchasing behavior."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Guiding decision-making. One activity of the financial-information management function is to provide accurate financial reports so that managers can make sound decisions about business activities. For instance, managers use the financial reports to make decisions about how to use or reallocate money to operate more efficiently. The reports are not being used to ensure compliance. There is not enough information provided to determine if the managers want to improve customer service or track purchasing behavior by reallocating funds to different departments or business activities. SOURCE: FM:002 SOURCE: Stair, R., & Reynolds, G. (2014). Fundamentals of information systems (7th ed.) [pp. 300- 303]. Boston, MA: Course Technology Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 61, "question": "Pamela was dismissed from her job as a financial database administrator because she shared her username and password with a coworker so that he could access a customer database that is typically off-limits to him. Pamela failed to fulfill her responsibilities as a data ", "choices": ["A. processor.", "B. auditor.", "C. sponsor.", "D. steward."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Steward. A data steward is, in essence, responsible for ensuring the integrity of an organization's data. To ensure those data's integrity, data stewards must make sure that data are used ethically and honestly\u2014and only by those individuals authorized to do so. Pamela failed to fulfill her responsibilities as a data steward because she allowed a coworker to access data that he was not authorized to see or use. An auditor is responsible for verifying the accuracy of business records. In business, a sponsor is typically an individual or organization that financially supports a project, event, or promotion. A data processor is responsible for analyzing facts and figures and putting them into formats useful to the business. SOURCE: FM:003 SOURCE: Smith, A.M. (2013). A new view of data stewardship\u2014Unbiased data presentation. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://www.information-management.com/news/1056150- 1.html?zkPrintable=1&nopagination=1 Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25 "}, {"number": 62, "question": "Why has online technology's use increased in financial-information management? ", "choices": ["A. Protection of customers' right to privacy", "B. Removal of electronic information exchange procedures", "C. Recognition that the security of transactions is no longer an issue", "D. Passage of laws that recognize electronic documents as legally binding"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Passage of laws that recognize electronic documents as legally binding. As businesses have become more comfortable with the use of electronic information, their willingness to accept electronic documents as legally binding contracts has also increased. This has been buoyed by the passage of laws recognizing electronic documents and signatures as legally binding. Electronic information exchange procedures have not been removed. These procedures provide a way for people to exchange information electronically. Security remains an issue for online financial-information management. Although customers' right to privacy is an issue, it has not contributed to the increased use of online technology in financial-information management. SOURCE: FM:011 SOURCE: Swan, E. (2015, October 1). Electronic signature laws in the U.S. and around the world. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://www.efilecabinet.com/electronic-signature-lawsin-the-u-s-and-around-the-world/ "}, {"number": 63, "question": "What computer application enables a business to access information from its enterprise resource planning (ERP) software program for use in its budgeting software program? ", "choices": ["A. Cross-reference", "B. Automated data transfer", "C. Group", "D. Data-validation"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Automated data transfer. Businesses typically use different software programs to accommodate their various needs. To quickly and efficiently obtain the financial information stored in other programs, some budgeting software programs have applications that automatically transfer data from other programs (e.g., ERP and CRM) to facilitate budget development and report generation. The cross-reference function in a spreadsheet program enables computer users to locate related data or information in other worksheets, spreadsheets, etc. The group function in a spreadsheet program enables computer users to group different cells of data. In spreadsheet applications, the data validation function ensures that computer users input correct values into specific spreadsheet cells. SOURCE: FM:013 SOURCE: Centage Corporation. (2018). ERP system data integration with your accounting or g/l system. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://centage.com/Products/Editions/LinkMaestro.asp "}, {"number": 64, "question": "Helena's manager asked her to put together a report containing a number of different financial ratios, including the company's current ratio and rate of return on equity. To create the report, Helena should use __________ software. ", "choices": ["A. data-mining", "B. budgeting", "C. financial analysis", "D. field service"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Financial analysis. Businesses often use financial analysis applications to quickly and easily examine their financial health. The software calculates and reports many different financial ratios, compares a business's financial performance to that of competitors and industry standards, and increases the finance department's productivity. Budgeting software allows business owners and managers to develop budgets, study each item in a budget individually and together as a whole, and measure the impact that different actions would have on the budget. Data mining software is often used to find relationships or patterns among a vast amount of company data. Data mining software is also used to analyze data; however, not all data mining software analyzes financial data. Field service software is typically used by businesses with sales and service teams who do most of their work outside the office. Professionals such as plumbers and home health care aides use field service software to report their hours, activities, clients, etc. SOURCE: FM:014 SOURCE: Thomson Reuters. (n.d.). Financial analysis CS: Features and benefits. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://cs.thomsonreuters.com/financial-analysis/features.aspx "}, {"number": 65, "question": "Tank's Trucking Company is focusing on eliminating waste and creating more value with fewer resources. Which of the following methodologies is Tank's Trucking Company using: ", "choices": ["A. Sustainability", "B. Six sigma", "C. Activity-based costing", "D. Lean"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Lean. Lean is a production practice that focuses on eliminating wasteful processes that do not add value. It increases implementation speeds and productivity. Six sigma is a set of strategies that focuses on limiting defects and variability in order to improve process control. Its focus is on quality rather than speed and waste elimination. Activity-based costing is a strategy for assigning overhead costs in a logical manner. Tank's Trucking Company is not necessarily focused on costing methods. Finally, sustainability is the management of social, environmental, and financial demands to minimize impact on the environment or society. Eliminating waste could be a part of sustainability, but creating more value with fewer resources is not related to sustainability. SOURCE: FM:016 SOURCE: Process Excellence Network. (2013, April 22). Process excellence explained: What's the difference between lean, six sigma, and business process management? Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://www.processexcellencenetwork.com/business-processmanagement-bpm/articles/process-excellence-explained-what-s-the-difference/ Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26 "}, {"number": 66, "question": "What is the primary reason that creditors analyze their customers' financial information? ", "choices": ["A. To determine how often their customers' inventory turns over", "B. To know whether they're making a good investment", "C. To determine the likelihood of getting paid", "D. To understand the type of accounting method customers use"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To determine the likelihood of getting paid. Creditors take risks when extending credit to customers whether they are letting them borrow money or defer payment for product. By analyzing customers' financial information, they have a better idea of whether the customers pay their debts. Stockholders analyze financial information to determine whether they are making good investments. The accounting method customers use indicates when sales and expenses are recorded in the customers' books. Determining how often inventory turns must be compared with other companies in the same industry to determine whether inventory is being held too long. The figure by itself does not communicate anything to creditors. SOURCE: FM:009 SOURCE: Inc. (2018). Credit evaluation and approval. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from http://www.inc.com/encyclopedia/credit-evaluation-and-approval.html "}, {"number": 67, "question": "Latisha, a human resources manager at a hospital, is writing a list of the skills, knowledge, and characteristics for a nurse position she hopes to fill. She focuses on what education a nurse in that position should have, what personal traits s/he should have, and what s/he should be like. Latisha is working on a(n) ", "choices": ["A. onboarding activity.", "B. job description.", "C. strategic plan.", "D. job specification."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Job specification. A job specification is an explanation of the skills, knowledge, and characteristics required for a job. It describes what a person in that position should be. When Latisha lists the education and personal traits she wants a nurse to have, she's creating a job specification. A job description is an explanation of the responsibilities and tasks associated with a specific job. It describes what an employee in the position does. If Latisha wrote a job description for the nurse position, she would explain the actual duties of the job. Strategic planning is long-range planning (about three to five years) for the company as a whole. Onboarding activities are part of the staffing process and include employee orientation and various types of paperwork, like insurance, tax withholding, direct deposit, and citizenship information. SOURCE: HR:410 SOURCE: LAP-HR-035\u2014People Pusher (Nature of Human Resources Management) "}, {"number": 68, "question": "Marketing encourages people from different countries to __________ frequently. ", "choices": ["A. train", "B. trade", "C. think", "D. travel"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Trade. Since marketing creates exchanges between people and nations, it encourages people from different countries to trade frequently. Traveling, training, and thinking are reputable activities, but they are not specifically encouraged by marketing. SOURCE: MK:001 SOURCE: LAP-MK-004\u2014Have It Your Way! (Nature of Marketing) "}, {"number": 69, "question": "A benefit of informed decisions is that they ", "choices": ["A. reduce a business's risk.", "B. are usually bad decisions.", "C. cost less money.", "D. hurt a business's chances at competing."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Reduce a business's risk. Informed decisions are better decisions, and they reduce a business's risk. Informed decisions help businesses compete better. They may or may not cost less money. SOURCE: NF:110 SOURCE: LAP-NF-110\u2014In the Know (Nature of Information Management) "}, {"number": 70, "question": "Why is it important for businesses to manage employee information in a way that keeps it secure? ", "choices": ["A. To beat the competition", "B. To be secretive", "C. To be ethical", "D. To avoid publicity"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To be ethical. Businesses gather and maintain a wide range of information, and some of this information may be private or confidential. For example, businesses may have personal information about customers and employees. Making sure that this information is secure is a matter of ethics. Businesses have an ethical obligation to protect certain information so it does not become public and cause harm to individuals. Businesses do not keep information secure to be secretive, beat the competition, or avoid publicity. SOURCE: NF:111 SOURCE: Australian Association of Social Workers. (2015, December). Ethics and practice guidelineInformation management. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from http://www.aasw.asn.au/document/item/4680 "}, {"number": 71, "question": "A legal issue associated with the use of information might involve the violation of __________ laws. ", "choices": ["A. patent", "B. copyright", "C. trademark", "D. contract"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Copyright. Copyright is the legal protection of books and other artistic works granted by government and gives their creators sole rights to them for a certain period of years. If a business uses information that is copyrighted without obtaining permission from the copyright holder, the business is violating copyright laws. Copyright infringement is a legal issue because businesses can be sued and required to pay a substantial penalty. Patent, trademark, and contract laws do not involve the use of information. SOURCE: NF:076 SOURCE: Tysver, D. (1996-2018). Copyright law in the United States. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from https://www.bitlaw.com/copyright/index.html Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27 "}, {"number": 72, "question": "What type of system synchronizes sales and marketing efforts? ", "choices": ["A. Customer relationship management", "B. Transaction processing", "C. Supply chain management", "D. Decision support"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Customer relationship management. Customer relationship management systems accumulate and track customer activities and allow for interactions between customers and businesses. Transaction processing systems collect data from user inputs and generate outputs that assist in the core operations of a business. Supply chain management systems allow companies to work with suppliers and partners to improve operations. Decision support systems give companies access to financial, marketing, and operational data that helps them make better decisions. SOURCE: NF:083 SOURCE: Davoren, J. (2018, June 27). Types of information systems in an organization. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/types-information-systemsorganization-43097.html "}, {"number": 73, "question": "Which of the following is a computer-based time-management tool that helps employees keep track of their appointments and activities: ", "choices": ["A. Perpetual calendar", "B. Electronic task organizer", "C. Instant-messaging program", "D. Alarm clock"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Electronic task organizer. Electronic task organizers and calendars help employees keep track of their appointments and tasks, which help them be more efficient, organized, and productive workers. Spreadsheet software programs record and calculate numerical data. Instant-messaging programs allow Internet users to communicate in real time. Perpetual calendars and alarm clocks may not be computerbased. SOURCE: NF:005 SOURCE: Hein, R. (2013, April 18). 9 top iPhone and iPad productivity and time management apps. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from http://www.networkworld.com/article/2357942/smb/96495-9-Top-iPhone-and-iPadProductivity-and-Time-Management-Apps.html "}, {"number": 74, "question": "What is the first step in designing a multi-table query? ", "choices": ["A. Determine the criteria.", "B. Pinpoint exactly what you want to know.", "C. Locate the correct tables.", "D. Set the correct join direction."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Pinpoint exactly what you want to know. In order to create a successful multi-table query, the first step is figuring out exactly what question you want the database to answer. If you aren't exactly sure what you want to know, the database cannot provide you with the information you need. Determining the criteria for the query, locating the correct tables, and setting the correct join direction are all important steps to take before creating the query, but none of them will be successful unless the exact question has been determined first. SOURCE: NF:124 SOURCE: GCF LearnFree.org. (1998-2018). Access 2013: Designing a multi-table query. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from https://www.gcflearnfree.org/access2013/designing-a-multitablequery/1/ "}, {"number": 75, "question": "Businesses may review invoices to evaluate their customers' ", "choices": ["A. storage needs.", "B. business plans.", "C. purchasing habits.", "D. selling policies."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Purchasing habits. An invoice is the formal, printed record of a sale that includes all necessary information as to the buyer, the seller, items purchased, amounts, prices, delivery date, credit or discount terms, etc. By analyzing past sales records such as invoices, a business can determine what its customers are buying, when they are buying, and how much they are buying. This helps a business forecast future sales and to be prepared to offer the products that customers want. Businesses do not review invoices to evaluate their customers' business plans, storage needs, or selling policies. SOURCE: NF:002 SOURCE: Entrepreneur. (2018). Sales records. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from https://www.entrepreneur.com/encyclopedia/sales-records "}, {"number": 76, "question": "Philippe wants to find out the average length of time that visitors spend on his business's website. Which of the following data would be most useful to Philippe: ", "choices": ["A. Receiving data", "B. External data", "C. Clickstream data", "D. Qualitative data"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Clickstream data. Clickstream data are information about the number of people who visit a particular website, how long they spend on the website, and what they do while visiting the website (e.g., browsing, reading reviews, purchasing products, etc.). External data are facts and figures available outside the business. Philippe needs internal data, not external data. Receiving data are information about shipments of goods received by the business. Qualitative data are facts and figures based on opinions and personal interpretations. Philippe needs quantitative data containing specific numerical facts and figures, not qualitative data. SOURCE: NF:014 SOURCE: Sentance, R. (2017, September 11). Using clickstream data to know your customer's entire online journey. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from https://www.clickz.com/usingclickstream-data-to-know-your-customers-entire-online-journey/112816/ Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28 "}, {"number": 77, "question": "The Halifax Retail chain uses computer applications to track its inventory and order goods from its vendors. What form of technology is the company using to streamline its purchasing processes? ", "choices": ["A. Customer relationship management (CRM)", "B. Global positioning system (GPS)", "C. Electronic data interchange (EDI)", "D. Territorial routing application (TRA)"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Electronic data interchange (EDI). EDI systems allow businesses to transmit information to and from their suppliers. EDI applications can track a business's inventory and determine when the business should reorder, which increases the purchasing function's efficiency. GPS technology involves guiding and tracking vehicles en route to a destination. CRM technology is used to monitor customer data and build ongoing customer relationships. Sales departments use territorial routing software to develop efficient sales-call patterns. SOURCE: OP:191 SOURCE: Bozarth, C.C., & Handfield, R.B. (2013). Introduction to operations and supply chain management (3rd ed.) [p. 368]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Education Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 78, "question": "The most important reason why workplace accidents which do not result in injuries should be reported to supervisors is because ", "choices": ["A. the next accident could result in an injury.", "B. this is required by state law.", "C. the report prevents future liability.", "D. this is an OSHA requirement."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The next accident could result in an injury. The fact that one accident does not result in an injury does not ensure that the next accident will have the same results. An accident that does not cause an injury should be reported to a supervisor so that the circumstances causing the accident can be corrected if possible. This may save someone else from injury. Government regulations vary from state to state and for different industries. Reporting an uninjurious accident does not prevent future liability. SOURCE: OP:009 SOURCE: Clark, B., Basteri C.G., Gassen, C., & Walker, M. (2014). Marketing dynamics (3rd ed.) [pp. 565-566]. Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Co. "}, {"number": 79, "question": "What should you do when creating a schedule for your project? ", "choices": ["A. Break down the work into specific activities and tasks.", "B. Figure out exactly when you will get each part of the project done.", "C. Determine when certain parts of the project are due.", "D. Identify the risks that could affect your schedule."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Determine when certain parts of the project are due. When you are creating a schedule for your project plan, you should determine when certain parts of the project are due and make sure your schedule accounts for it. You cannot figure out exactly when you will get each part of the project done, but you can make estimates. Breaking down the work into specific activities and tasks happens before the schedule is created. Identifying risks happens after you create your schedule. SOURCE: OP:519 SOURCE: LAP-OP-519\u2014Plan On It! (Planning Projects) "}, {"number": 80, "question": "In which stage of project management does risk analysis take place? ", "choices": ["A. Closing", "B. Initiation", "C. Execution", "D. Planning"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Planning. A risk analysis takes place in the planning stage of project management. Project managers analyze risk in an effort to prepare to minimize its effects as much as possible. In the initiation phase, the idea for the project is assessed and a statement of work and project charter are drafted. In the execution phase, the work of the project is completed. In the closing phase, project managers deliver the final product and tie up any loose ends. SOURCE: OP:158 SOURCE: LAP-OP-158\u2014Projected To Win (Nature of Project Management) "}, {"number": 81, "question": "Determining project costs involves taking the information gained from assessing needed resources and ", "choices": ["A. asking the client for at least twice as much funding.", "B. using it for scheduling purposes.", "C. adjusting the project purpose as necessary.", "D. translating it into a realistic budget."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Translating it into a realistic budget. Determining project costs involves taking the information gained from assessing needed resources and translating it into a realistic budget, with the client\u2019s input. It shouldn\u2019t be necessary to ask the client to double the project\u2019s funding at this point in the planning process. Cost information shouldn\u2019t be necessary for creating a project schedule. The project purpose shouldn\u2019t be dependent on costs; rather, costs and budget should fit with project purpose. SOURCE: OP:001 SOURCE: LAP-OP-001\u2014Chart Your Course (Developing a Project Plan) "}, {"number": 82, "question": "Comparing the prices offered by different vendors for the same goods and services is what part of the purchasing process? ", "choices": ["A. Price fixing", "B. Bid analysis", "C. Invoice payment", "D. Receipt of goods"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Bid analysis. Businesses compare the prices offered by different vendors for the same goods and services in order to decide from whom to make the purchase. Analyzing the bids allows businesses to find out which vendor is offering the best price. Price fixing involves businesses agreeing on prices of their products resulting in little choice for the consumer. Receipt of goods is the arrival of the order at its destination. Invoice payment is paying for the goods once they have been received. SOURCE: OP:015 SOURCE: LAP-OP-002\u2014Buy Right (Purchasing) Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29 "}, {"number": 83, "question": "What can you do to help your company control expenses? ", "choices": ["A. Focus strictly on how much work you can get done.", "B. Follow company policies and procedures.", "C. Handle sales transactions as quickly as possible.", "D. Carry out research and development activities."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Follow company policies and procedures. Most businesses have specific policies that provide guidelines for the ways in which employees are expected to carry out their tasks. Following these guidelines can save the business money. For example, some company policies limit the time during which customers can return purchases. When employees follow this rule, the company avoids losing money on products it can neither return to the vendor nor sell to other customers. Although you should try to work as efficiently as possible, it's not a good idea to focus strictly on how much work you can get done. The quality of the work is often more important than the quantity. Instead of handling customer transactions as quickly as possible, it's better to focus on accuracy. Handling sales transactions correctly is a great opportunity to save the company money. Carrying out research and development activities is one of the effects of expense control, not a way an employee can help his or her company with expense control. SOURCE: OP:025 SOURCE: LAP-OP-025\u2014Buck Busters (Employee Role in Expense Control) "}, {"number": 84, "question": "Which of the following is a benefit of putting your goals in writing: ", "choices": ["A. Clarifies the goals", "B. Develops your perseverance", "C. Makes the goals attainable", "D. Provides a challenge"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Clarifies the goals. Writing out your goals helps you clarify them. It makes the goals real, and it also serves as a reminder. Writing out your goals does not make the goals attainable or provide a challenge. Perseverance is the ability to keep at something until it is finished, and you must develop that on your own. SOURCE: PD:018 SOURCE: LAP-PD-016\u2014Go for the Goal (Goal Setting) "}, {"number": 85, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about creativity: ", "choices": ["A. Creativity is primarily demonstrated through entertainment and the arts.", "B. Only people born with a natural gift can display creativity.", "C. Creativity is a skill we only use on special occasions.", "D. People show creativity in a variety of ways."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "People show creativity in a variety of ways. People show creativity in a variety of ways, not just through entertainment and the arts. Creativity is a skill we use all the time. You don't have to be born with it\u2014 anyone can enhance and develop her/his creativity. SOURCE: PD:012 SOURCE: LAP-PD-012\u2014Imagine That (Demonstrating Creativity) "}, {"number": 86, "question": "If a question on a job application does not apply to you, how should you respond? ", "choices": ["A. Leave it blank", "B. Make up a response", "C. Write \u201cdoes not apply\u201d", "D. Write \u201ccannot answer\u201d"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Write \u201cdoes not apply.\u201d Writing \u201cdoes not apply\u201d lets the employer know you read and completed the entire application. Making up a response is deceptive and inappropriate. If the question is left blank, the employer might think you forgot to answer the question. If you write \u201ccannot answer,\u201d the employer might think you are hiding something because you are not willing to answer the question. SOURCE: PD:027 SOURCE: Littrell, J.J., Lorenz, J.H., & Smith, H.T. (2012). School to career (9th ed.) [p. 343]. Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox. "}, {"number": 87, "question": "Why will it benefit you to learn as much as possible about a prospective employer before you go for a job interview? ", "choices": ["A. It prepares you to ask good questions.", "B. It shows that you do a lot of reading.", "C. It ensures that you'll be considered for the job.", "D. It gives you something to discuss during the interview."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "It prepares you to ask good questions. As a job applicant, you should find out as much as possible about the business before a job interview so that you are prepared to ask intelligent questions about the company. This does not ensure that you'll be considered for the available job, but it does indicate your interest in the company and the job. It does not necessarily indicate that you have done a lot of reading, since you may have obtained information about the company from other sources such as current employees or television news. It is not necessary for you to have something to discuss with the interviewer as the interviewer decides what will be discussed. SOURCE: PD:028 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G. (2012). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 90-91). Columbus, OH: McGrawHill Education. Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 30 "}, {"number": 88, "question": "What should job applicants offer to do in the closing paragraph of an interview follow-up letter? ", "choices": ["A. Send an appropriate gift", "B. Work for a reduced salary", "C. Provide further information", "D. Accept any available job"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Provide further information. By offering to provide further information, applicants are indicating their interest in the job without stating it directly. They are reinforcing their desire to be hired. Interviewers usually take this type of offer to mean that the applicant wants to be seriously considered for the position. Applicants have applied for a specific job and should not offer to take anything that is available. The job they have applied for has a specific salary range, and it would be inappropriate to offer to work for less. Applicants are not expected to send gifts of any type to interviewers. SOURCE: PD:029 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G. (2012). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 90-91). Columbus, OH: McGrawHill Education. "}, {"number": 89, "question": "Bobbi, who works for an insurance company, is responsible for calculating the risk of loss, establishing premium rates, and designing insurance policies to cover risk. Bobbi works as a(n) ", "choices": ["A. underwriter.", "B. agent.", "C. accountant.", "D. financial analyst."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Underwriter. The work of underwriters is important to the insurance industry. Underwriters are responsible for calculating the risk of loss, establishing premium rates, and designing policies to cover risk. Many choose to specialize in life insurance, health insurance, or property and casualty insurance. Insurance agents are responsible for selling insurance policies and other financial services. Accountants are responsible for preparing, analyzing, and verifying a variety of financial data. Financial analysts evaluate companies and industries and make recommendations to buy, sell, or hold certain securities. Financial analysts are also known as securities analysts or investment analysts. SOURCE: PD:152 SOURCE: LAP-PD-020\u2014Career Opportunities in Finance "}, {"number": 90, "question": "Which of the following statements regarding corporate governance is true: ", "choices": ["A. Corporate governance makes a firm's shareholders accountable to its managers.", "B. Corporate governance emphasizes individual goals over group goals.", "C. Corporate governance aligns the interests of individuals, corporations, and society.", "D. Corporate governance is only used to protect the interests of the shareholders."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Corporate governance aligns the interests of individuals, corporations, and society. Corporate governance aligns the interests of all stakeholders and emphasizes group goals. It makes a firm's managers accountable to the shareholders and protects the interests of all stakeholders. SOURCE: PD:213 SOURCE: Klazema, A. (2014, May 14). The importance of corporate governance. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from https://blog.udemy.com/importance-of-corporate-governance/ "}, {"number": 91, "question": "One way that organizations can achieve their corporate governance objectives is by ", "choices": ["A. encouraging employee participation at board meetings.", "B. preventing stakeholders from viewing financial information.", "C. allowing senior managers to serve on the board of directors.", "D. releasing an annual report detailing their failures and losses."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Encouraging employee participation at board meetings. Achieving corporate governance objectives requires the participation of all people involved with a company. It is especially important for an organization's employees to be actively engaged in corporate governance. Employees should be encouraged to participate in board meetings to raise questions or concerns that they may have about the company's actions. Preventing stakeholders from viewing financial information, allowing senior managers to serve on the board of directors, and releasing an annual report detailing their failures and losses are not appropriate steps companies should take to achieve corporate governance objectives. SOURCE: PD:301 SOURCE: Safetrac. (2015, January 19). Achieving good corporate governance. Retrieved September 13, 2018, from http://www.safetrac.com.au/achieving-good-corporate-governance/ "}, {"number": 92, "question": "Internal audits are used by __________, while external audits are used by __________. ", "choices": ["A. management; stakeholders", "B. stakeholders; employees", "C. creditors; management", "D. employees; competitors"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Management; stakeholders. Internal audits are performed for management within a company to analyze practices and examine risks. External audits are done by outside firms and are used by stakeholders such as investors, creditors, and lenders. External audits are generally not used by employees, management, or competitors. Internal audits are not used by stakeholders or creditors. SOURCE: PD:214 SOURCE: Bragg, S. (2017, December 24). The difference between internal and external audits. Retrieved September 12, 2018, from http://www.accountingtools.com/questions-andanswers/the-difference-between-internal-and-external-audits.html Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 31 "}, {"number": 93, "question": "Which of the following serves as an organization's conscience during decision-making: ", "choices": ["A. The public", "B. The \u201cC-Suite\u201d (CEO, CFO, etc.)", "C. Employees", "D. Board of directors"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Board of directors. The board of directors guides the organization during the decision-making process so that the organization continues to accomplish its mission in an efficient and ethical way. It would not be appropriate for the C-Suite, an organization's employees, or the public to act as an organization's conscience during decision-making. SOURCE: PD:303 SOURCE: Management Study Guide. (n.d.). Corporate governance - definition, scope and benefits. Retrieved September 16, 2018, from http://www.managementstudyguide.com/corporategovernance.htm "}, {"number": 94, "question": "To build professional relationships, Brynn serves on several trade association committees, co-authors articles with other finance professionals to publish in the local newspaper, and treats business contacts to dinner or golf. These activities are forms of ", "choices": ["A. advertising.", "B. cooperating.", "C. networking.", "D. up-selling."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Networking. Networking involves connecting with individuals who might help accomplish career and professional goals. By serving on trade association committees, co-authoring articles for publication, and treating business contacts to dinner or golf, Brynn creates situations in which she has the opportunity to get to know other professionals and possibly build relationships that will be beneficial for everyone involved. Cooperating with others shows a willingness to work together to resolve differences or achieve common goals. Although Brynn is cooperating with others while carrying out these activities, her ultimate goal is to build a network of business professionals who can help her achieve her career goals. Advertising is any paid form of nonpersonal presentation of ideas, images, goods, or services. Up-selling is a sales technique in which a salesperson suggests a higher priced product than the one originally requested by the customer. SOURCE: PD:153 SOURCE: Hoban, S. (n.d.). Building business relationships. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from http://www.ccim.com/cire-magazine/articles/building-business-relationships "}, {"number": 95, "question": "How can management reduce the business's level of risk associated with ethics? ", "choices": ["A. Advise employees that following business ethics depends on the situation.", "B. Allow employees to follow their own set of ethics.", "C. Assume employees know what constitutes ethical behavior.", "D. Train employees about expectations in relation to workplace ethics."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Train employees about expectations in relation to workplace ethics. Employees must clearly understand the business's ethical standards and expectations. Offering ethics training can help employees understand the business's rules and ethical standards. Employees who do not have a clear understanding of the business's expectations in relation to ethical behavior put the business at risk. Employees who do not follow the business's ethics guidelines may cross a legal line without knowing they have done so. Because employees' experiences and beliefs often vary and because there are many gray areas in the business world, the business should not allow employees to follow their personal set of ethics or assume that the employees know what the business considers ethical behavior. Ethics are a set of principles that do not vary by situation. SOURCE: RM:041 SOURCE: Queensland Government. (2018). Costs and benefits of holding stock. Retrieved September 14, 2018, from https://www.business.qld.gov.au/running-business/finances-cash-flow/stockcontrol/costs-benefits "}, {"number": 96, "question": "A business can protect its computerized financial data from losses associated with fire, flood, and electrical outages by ", "choices": ["A. changing passwords and encryption techniques periodically.", "B. installing intrusion detection systems.", "C. performing backup procedures on a regular basis.", "D. implementing a manual filing system."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Performing backup procedures on a regular basis. Backing up the computer system and storing the backup information off-site can reduce financial losses due to uncontrollable circumstances such as electrical outages or fire. Businesses that do not perform backup procedures on a regular basis may lose the data for good or take a lot of time and money to replace if a disaster harms its computer systems. Computer systems help make businesses operate more efficiently than manual systems do. Different types of intrusion detection systems (e.g., firewalls) are designed to protect the business's computer systems from unauthorized access. Passwords and encryption are additional techniques used to secure access to computer information. SOURCE: RM:042 SOURCE: Patterson, T. (2015, September). The use of information technology in risk management. Retrieved September 16, 2018, from https://www.aicpa.org/InterestAreas/FRC/AssuranceAdvisoryServices/DownloadableDocume nts/ASEC_Whitepapers/Risk_Technology.pdf Test 1184 FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 32 "}, {"number": 97, "question": "When businesses in a particular industry carry risks that commercial insurance companies typically do not cover, they often form __________ to __________ risk. ", "choices": ["A. captive insurance companies; transfer", "B. insurance rating companies; avoid", "C. insurance brokerage firms; assume", "D. independent life insurance agencies; minimize"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Captive insurance companies; transfer. Organizations (i.e., corporations, industry/professional/trade associations) often form their own insurance companies, which are known as captive insurance companies. The founding organizations control their captive insurance companies' underwriting processes, premium rates, and claims-processing policies. This is an advantage to the founding companies because a primary reason they form their own insurance companies is they often carry risks that commercial insurance companies do not cover. For example, mining companies tend to carry more risk due to the dangerous nature of the mining process. When businesses purchase insurance, they are minimizing risks by transferring them to another entity; therefore, in these situations, businesses are not avoiding or assuming risks. Organizations do not form insurance rating companies, insurance brokerage firms, or independent life insurance agencies to transfer unusual types of risks. SOURCE: RM:043 SOURCE: Wallace, O., & Foster, N. (2014, November 6). What is captive insurance? Retrieved September 13, 2018, from http://www.wisegeek.com/what-is-captive-insurance.htm "}, {"number": 98, "question": "Why is the choice of a risk measure for internal and external risk of great practical importance? ", "choices": ["A. It determines the maximum number of clients that can be served effectively by a financial\ninstitution.", "B. It determines the minimum reserve requirements in financial trading.", "C. It identifies the types of risks that the financial institution will encounter.", "D. It designates the audience that will receive the resulting financial reports."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "It determines the minimum reserve requirements in financial trading. Different measures can result in a lower or higher minimum reserve requirement, which results in a lower or higher profit for the financial institution. Although it does not designate the audience that will receive the resulting financial reports, some financial measures should be used for internal purposes while other measures are more appropriate for external audiences. The number of clients to serve and the types of risks to be encountered are not aspects of selecting a risk measure. SOURCE: RM:058 SOURCE: Ingram, D. (n.d.). External and internal factors of financial risk. Retrieved September 18, 2018, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/external-internal-factors-financial-risk-4563.html "}, {"number": 99, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement regarding enterprise risk management (ERM): ", "choices": ["A. All risks considered in ERM are negative.", "B. ERM focuses on the combined impact of all risks.", "C. ERM can make achieving goals more difficult.", "D. Risks usually relate to relationships between employees."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "ERM focuses on the combined impact of all risks. Enterprise risk management takes into account all of the risks that an organization may face and looks at their combined impact. Not all risks are negative; risks can be positive, and positive risks must be considered as well as negative risks. Enterprise risk management does not make it more difficult to achieve goals; in fact, it can help an organization achieve its goals. Risks are not usually related to relationships between employees; there are many types of risks related to all aspects of an organization. SOURCE: RM:062 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2018). What is enterprise risk management and why is it important? Retrieved September 13, 2018, from http://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/031715/whatenterprise-risk-management-and-why-it-important.asp "}, {"number": 100, "question": "Setting the overall goals for a business, guiding the activities of the business, and keeping the business moving toward its goals are part of the role of ", "choices": ["A. employees.", "B. managers.", "C. consultants.", "D. supervisors."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Managers. Managers are responsible for setting the overall goals and motivating their employees to work toward accomplishing them so the business can be successful. Employees are responsible for working toward the goals of the business, but they are not responsible for setting goals. Consultants do not set goals for businesses other than their own. Supervisors guide employees in carrying out the activities of the business. SOURCE: SM:001 SOURCE: LAP-SM-003\u2014Manage This! (Concept of Management"}], "2014-FIN-CORE": [{"number": 1, "question": "One reason businesses usually are unable to enter into legally binding contracts with minors is because those under the legal age ", "choices": ["A. do not have sufficient funds to make payments.", "B. may not understand the consequences of their actions.", "C. are unable to make basic decisions.", "D. cannot make promises to do something for others."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "May not understand the consequences of their actions. Businesses usually are prevented from entering into legally binding contracts with certain groups of people because these people are not considered to have the capacity to understand the consequences of their actions. One of these groups includes minors, those people under the legal age. In most cases, minors cannot enter into legally binding contracts because they are not old enough to be responsible for the consequences. Minors often have part-time jobs and may have sufficient funds to make payments. Minors are able to make basic decisions, and can promise to do something for others. Therefore, these are not reasons why businesses usually are unable to enter into legally binding contracts with minors. SOURCE: BL:002 SOURCE: McAdams, T., Neslund, N., & Neslund, K. (2007). Law, business, and society (8th ed.) [pp. 210, 222]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin.  "}, {"number": 2, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a voluntary debtor-creditor relationship: ", "choices": ["A. Receiving a monetary gift ", "B. Obtaining a loan from a bank ", "C. Requiring specific information", "D. Owing punitive damages"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Obtaining a loan from a bank. The debtor is the individual or business that owes money to another individual or business, which is the creditor. A business that obtains a loan from a bank is entering into a voluntary debtor-creditor relationship. It is voluntary because the business (debtor) is seeking to obtain funds from the bank (creditor) by going through a loan-application process. A monetary gift is given without expectations of repayment. A monetary gift and a request for information are not examples of debtor-creditor relationships. In tort cases, the court can order one party to pay punitive damages to the other party. This is an example of an involuntary debtor-creditor relationship. SOURCE: BL:071 SOURCE: Business Owners Toolkit. (2012, May 24). Understanding the debtor-creditor relationship. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://www.bizfilings.com/toolkit/sbg/run-abusiness/assets/understanding-debtor-creditor-relationship.aspx  "}, {"number": 3, "question": "The Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 is legislation that was passed in response to recent ", "choices": ["A. collection activities. ", "B. investment options. ", "C. tax settlements.", "D. accounting scandals."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Accounting scandals. The Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 is federal legislation that was passed in response to recent major corporate and accounting scandals. These scandals include Enron and WorldCom, which resulted in a loss of public trust in current accounting and reporting procedures. The law established new and improved accounting procedures for public companies and accounting firms. The Sarbanes-Oxley Act was not passed in response to recent investment options, tax settlements, or collection activities. SOURCE: BL:133 SOURCE: Rouse, M. (2007, September). Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX). Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://searchcio.techtarget.com/definition/Sarbanes-Oxley-Act  "}, {"number": 4, "question": "Which of the following mutual funds is most likely to be tax inefficient: ", "choices": ["A. A fund with a high portfolio turnover rate", "B. A fund with a low portfolio turnover rate", "C. A fund that concentrates on a specialized sector", "D. A fund that attempts to match a broad market index"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "A fund with a high portfolio turnover rate. Regardless of fund type, a fund with a high portfolio rate replaces a high percentage of its investments every year. Every time that the fund sells one item in its portfolio and purchases another, a capital gain or loss is being realized. Because these capital gains or losses occur so frequently, it is difficult for fund investors to successfully time the realizations and manage their overall tax obligations effectively. Specialized sector funds focus on a certain industry, and index funds attempt to match broad market indices. SOURCE: BL:134 SOURCE: Loth, R. (n.d.). Fund I-Q no..5: Portfolio turnover ratio. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://www.investopedia.com/university/quality-mutual-fund/chp7-fund-activity/fund-iq"}, {"number": 5, "question": "Which of the following quality management approaches is often used in the finance industry to sustain regulatory compliance: ", "choices": ["A. Crisis management ", "B. Just-in-Time ", "C. Reassurance", "D. Six Sigma"], "answer": "sp", "reasoning": "  5. D Six Sigma. Aspects of the Six Sigma approach to quality management are applied in the finance industry to sustain regulatory compliance. Specifically, Six Sigma's closed-loop control principles (definemeasure-analyze-improve-control) are often incorporated in compliance processes and procedures. Justin-Time, reassurance, and crisis management are not quality management approaches. SOURCE: CC:003 SOURCE: Oversight Systems, Inc. (2008, August). Turn SOX compliance into cash: Link SarbanesOxley requirements to business improvement. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from hhttp://productdatamanagement.knowledgestorm.com/ksproductdatamgmt/search/viewabstr act/99003/index.jsp SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 12  "}, {"number": 6, "question": "After identifying a potential compliance issue, a virtual auditor should ", "choices": ["A. manually load questionable transactions into a spreadsheet for analysis.", "B. delete all exceptions and questionable transactions from the system.", "C. enter all questionable transactions into the operational financial system.", "D. link all related questionable transactions for further investigation."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Link all related questionable transactions for further investigation. After detecting a potential compliance issue, compliance technology such as a virtual auditor should identify and link all of the questionable transactions and entities that seem to be related in some way. Then, the data can be further analyzed and investigated. Rather than deleting all exceptions and questionable transactions from the system, a virtual auditor should document and link the data. To maintain the integrity of the compliance system, it must function independently of the operational financial system. Questionable transactions should not be entered in the operational system. In fact, data about the questionable transaction probably came from the operational system. While a human auditor might manually load questionable transactions into a spreadsheet for analysis, a virtual, computerized auditor would not need to do so. SOURCE: CC:004 SOURCE: VMWare. (2008). Achieving compliance in a virtualized environment. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://www.vmware.com/files/pdf/technology/compliance_virtualized_environment_wp.pdf  "}, {"number": 7, "question": "Which of the following statements contains the most relevant information to include in a business report about the specific market share of computer manufacturers during a particular time frame: ", "choices": ["A. In 2009, Hewett Packard held 29.1 percent of the market share, followed by Dell, which held 21.9\npercent.", "B. In 2009, Hewett Packard shipped more computers than Dell or Apple.", "C. Hewett Packard, Dell, Acer, Toshiba, and Apple sold more computers in 2009 than other\ncomputer manufacturers.", "D. Apple Computers held the fifth highest share of the computer market in 2009."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "In 2009, Hewett Packard held 29.1 percent of the market share, followed by Dell, which held 21.9 percent. This option provides the most detailed information about market share during a specific time frame because it provides specific percentage amounts in relation to one year. The ability to read information and extract the most important facts is an important skill to possess. Businesspeople often need to extract the most important content from various documents and articles to analysis reports, complete projects, and make business decisions. SOURCE: CO:055 SOURCE: Schall, J. (n.d.). Integrating source material. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from https://www.e-education.psu.edu/styleforstudents/c5_p6.html  "}, {"number": 8, "question": "Successful communication depends upon the ", "choices": ["A. listener's knowledge of and comfort with the topic.", "B. speaker's ability to speak loudly and the listener's interest in the topic.", "C. speaker and the listener.", "D. speaker's professional qualifications."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Speaker and the listener. Successful communication depends on active participation of the speaker and the listener, each playing a vital role in the process. Communication can take place even if the speaker is not speaking loudly. Communication is not dependent upon the listener's knowledge of or comfort with the topic, nor is it dependent on the speaker's professional qualifications. SOURCE: CO:017 SOURCE: QS LAP 1\u2014Listen Up  "}, {"number": 9, "question": "Strategic management is demonstrated in which of the following phrases: ", "choices": ["A. Obtaining funds for business projects ", "B. Recruiting appropriate employees ", "C. Planning and organizing for the future", "D. Regularly updating business processes"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Planning and organizing for the future. Strategic management involves planning and organizing for the future. It does not involve obtaining funds. That is part of financial analysis. Recruiting appropriate employees is part of human-resources management and regularly updating business processes is part of operations. SOURCE: EC:071 SOURCE: EC LAP 19\u2014Strictly Business (Business Activities)  "}, {"number": 10, "question": "Which of the following is a legitimate response for an employee to provide to a customer regarding an inquiry about product pricing: ", "choices": ["A. If you can wait a moment, I'll check for the price in the computer.", "B. I'm not sure what the pricing is.", "C. You'll need to contact the appropriate person to get the price.", "D. I'm pretty sure that the item costs $39.65."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "If you can wait a moment, I'll check for the price in the computer. Businesses receive inquiries from customers on a regular basis. In some situations, an employee may not know the answer to a customer's question. To provide good customer service, the employee should take the appropriate steps to obtain the requested information. This may involve verifying the price in the computer system or transferring a customer's telephone call to the sales department. Guessing the price, stating that s/he does not know the price, and telling the customer to contact another person are not legitimate responses to inquiries and do not provide customers with good customer service. SOURCE: CO:060 SOURCE: Lesikar, R.V., & Flatley, M.E. (2005). Basic business communication: Skills for empowering the Internet generation (10th ed.) [pp. 119-121]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 13  "}, {"number": 11, "question": "An effective technique to use to clarify information when giving verbal directions involves ", "choices": ["A. speaking in a loud voice. ", "B. taking notes. ", "C. demonstrating a procedure.", "D. limiting questions."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Demonstrating a procedure. If possible, it is always useful to demonstrate a procedure when giving verbal directions. The visual demonstration reinforces the verbal explanation and makes it easier for employees to understand. This might include an actual demonstration, a video of a demonstration, or diagrams that explain the procedure. The goal is to increase understanding, particularly if the directions are detailed, or the procedure is new or complicated. Taking notes often helps employees to understand and follow directions. Speaking in a loud voice will not help to clarify information. It is effective to encourage questions rather than to limit them. SOURCE: CO:083 SOURCE: Bock, W. (2006, September 20). How to give better instructions. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://ezinearticles.com/?How-to-Give-Better-Instructions&id=305933  "}, {"number": 12, "question": "What is the main form of written communication between companies? ", "choices": ["A. Telephone calls ", "B. Memorandums ", "C. Meetings", "D. Business letters"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Business letters. Business letters are the most common form of written communication used by businesses to exchange information with other organizations or with customers. Memorandums are informal letters or notes between a company's employees. They are the main form of written communication within a business. Telephone calls and meetings are not forms of written communication. SOURCE: CO:016 SOURCE: Leskiar, R.V., & Flatley, M.E. (2005). Basic business communication: Skills for empowering the Internet generation (10th ed.) [pp. 94-95]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin.  "}, {"number": 13, "question": "Anna, a new employee with Turbo Electronics, must write a letter to a customer. Because Anna does not know which letter format to use, she should ", "choices": ["A. develop the letter in several formats and send the letter that her supervisor likes best.", "B. select the block format because it is the mostly widely used.", "C. select the simplified format because it is impersonal.", "D. ask her supervisor which letter format the company uses."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Ask her supervisor which letter format the company uses. Companies may prefer that their employees format business correspondence in a specific way to ensure consistency within the organization. To save time and effort, Ann should ask her supervisor which letter format the company uses, such as the block format or simplified format. Developing the letter in a variety of formats is an inefficient use of time. SOURCE: CO:088 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. A-10 - A-12]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall.  "}, {"number": 14, "question": "Because Caroline does not have enough time to read an entire 400-page business report, what section of the report should she review to obtain an overview of the most important content? ", "choices": ["A. Table of contents ", "B. Executive summary ", "C. Appendices", "D. Conclusions"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Executive summary. The executive summary provides an overview of the entire report and contains the most important information included in the body of the report. When businesspeople have time constraints, they often read the executive summary of a lengthy report. The table of contents is the portion of the report in which the various report sections are listed with their page numbers for easy access. The appendices are segments that are added to the end of the report and provide supporting information. The conclusion section of the report summarizes results and in some reports, this section includes recommendations for a certain course of action. SOURCE: CO:091 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. 456, 461, 474]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall.  "}, {"number": 15, "question": "Employees who always keep their commitments to customers are building positive relationships with those customers by being ", "choices": ["A. dependable. ", "B. assertive. ", "C. creative.", "D. sociable."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Dependable. Employees who are dependable do what they say they will do and keep their commitments to customers. When employees offer to do something for customers, they must live up to the terms of the commitment in order to build positive relationships. Customers appreciate dependable employees and often return to a specific business because of them. Assertive employees stand up for their rights. Sociable employees are friendly. Creative employees develop unique ideas and solutions to problems. These are good characteristics for employees to have, but they do not involve keeping commitments. SOURCE: CR:003 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (p. 258). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 14  "}, {"number": 16, "question": "One way to show respect for foreign clients' cultural and social differences is to ", "choices": ["A. always speak in your native language. ", "B. pronounce their names correctly. ", "C. use slang and idioms frequently.", "D. embrace cultural stereotypes."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Pronounce their names correctly. One way to show respect for foreign clients, their families, and their cultures is to learn to say their names properly. If you mispronounce a client's name, you might insult the person or hurt his/her feelings. If you can speak a client's native tongue, converse with that client in her/his language, rather than always speaking in your own native language. Especially if your clients' knowledge of the English language is limited, you should avoid using slang and idioms\u2014your clients may not understand what you really mean by such words and phrases. When communicating with clients of different cultures, do not base your actions on cultural stereotypes. SOURCE: CR:019 SOURCE: Ngomsi, E. (2003-2009). Factors that affect cross-cultural interactions in the workplace. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://www.yan-koloba.com/articles.html  "}, {"number": 17, "question": "Whatever action must be taken in handling a customer complaint, the salesperson should respond in a(n) __________ manner. ", "choices": ["A. abrupt ", "B. skeptical ", "C. formal", "D. concerned"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Concerned. The salesperson's concerned attitude should put the customer in a good frame of mind. If a customer complaint is handled improperly, a valuable customer may be lost. If the salesperson is skeptical or abrupt, this may alienate the customer. It is not necessary to respond in a formal manner; however, professionalism is important. SOURCE: CR:010 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 241-242). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 18, "question": "Jonathan, an insurance agent, explains both the pros and cons of his products to all of his customers to help them decide which policies to purchase. Hank, also an insurance agent, explains to his customers why they should purchase his products, but he doesn't talk about anything negative before making a sale. Based on this information, which agent is more likely to retain and grow his client base? ", "choices": ["A. Jonathan, because he gives his customers too much information.", "B. Jonathan, because his customers feel that they can trust him.", "C. Hank, because he doesn't scare his customers away.", "D. Hank, because he is a very optimistic, upbeat person."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Jonathan, because his customers feel that they can trust him. Jonathan educates his customers about his products, explaining the positives as well as the negatives. By doing so, Jonathan presents himself as a truthful, trustworthy individual. Customers are much more likely to return to Jonathan and refer others to him because they see him as a person they can trust. There is no indication that Jonathan provides his customers with too much information. Hank is not likely to retain and grow his client base simply because he is optimistic. And, while customers appreciate an upbeat salesperson, they are likely to get angry with Hank if something goes wrong that Hank could have warned them about. Angry, displeased customers are unlikely to return to Hank or refer others to him in the future. SOURCE: CR:012 SOURCE: Hoffman, K.D., & Bateson, J. (2006). Services marketing: Concepts, strategies, & cases (3rd ed.) [p. 400]. Mason, OH: Thomson South-Western.  "}, {"number": 19, "question": "What customer-relationship-management analytic would be most suitable for sorting clients based on how likely they are to repurchase a particular product? ", "choices": ["A. Profitability analysis ", "B. Account personalization ", "C. Event monitoring", "D. Customer segmentation"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Customer segmentation. Customer-relationship-management (CRM) analytics can be used to analyze and evaluate customer data in many different ways. For example, a business can use CRM technology to segment its customers into groupings based on each client's likelihood of purchasing or repurchasing a particular product. Personalization allows a business to market to specific customers based on data in the CRM system. Event monitoring helps businesses to identify when a customer reaches a specific dollar amount of purchasing or requests an excessive number of refunds. Profitability analysis helps businesses to identify their most profitable customers. SOURCE: CR:024 SOURCE: TechTarget. (2007, June 27). CRM analytics. Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://searchcrm.techtarget.com/definition/CRM-analytics  "}, {"number": 20, "question": "Items that are used to produce goods and services are ", "choices": ["A. economic resources. ", "B. natural resources. ", "C. capital goods.", "D. human resources."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Economic resources. An item becomes an economic resource when it is used to produce a good or a service. Economic resources include natural resources, human resources, and capital goods. SOURCE: EC:003 SOURCE: EC LAP 14\u2014Be Resourceful (Economic Resources) SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15  "}, {"number": 21, "question": "Which of the following is a component of verbal communication between individuals: ", "choices": ["A. Body posture ", "B. Listening ", "C. Facial expression", "D. Eye contact"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Listening. Listening involves not only hearing what the speaker is saying but making appropriate verbal responses. It is an essential component or part of verbal communication. Facial expressions, eye contact, and body posture are examples of nonverbal communications. SOURCE: CO:147 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 192-193). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 22, "question": "Which of the following elements of a business is not structured by organizational design: ", "choices": ["A. Competitors ", "B. People ", "C. Information", "D. Technology"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Competitors. Organizational design (also called organizational structure) is the process of structuring a business's people, information, and technology to enable the business to achieve its goals and to be successful. A business isn't able to structure its competitors. SOURCE: EC:103 SOURCE: EC LAP 23\u2014Designed to Work (Organizational Design)  "}, {"number": 23, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about breaking the law: ", "choices": ["A. It is acceptable in most industries.", "B. It will make a company more popular.", "C. It is necessary for business success.", "D. It may have different consequences than breaching ethics."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "It may have different consequences than breaching ethics. Breaching business ethics and breaking the law may have different consequences. For example, breaching business ethics alone could result in loss of customers, while breaking the law could result in fines or jail time. Both breaching business ethics and breaking the law are unacceptable practices in most industries, are not necessary for business success, and will not make a company more popular. In fact, doing so will hurt a company's public image. SOURCE: EC:106 SOURCE: EC LAP 21\u2014On the Up and Up (Business Ethics)  "}, {"number": 24, "question": "A country that has a socialistic command economic system is ", "choices": ["A. Great Britain. ", "B. the United States. ", "C. Switzerland.", "D. Japan."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Great Britain. Socialism is a modified command economic system in which government owns the basic means of production but there is private ownership of businesses as well. Socialism is characterized by freedom of choice, limited competition, high taxes, some government control, and welfare programs for citizens. Japan, Switzerland, and the United States have capitalistic economic systems. SOURCE: EC:007 SOURCE: EC LAP 17\u2014Who's the Boss? (Economic Systems)  "}, {"number": 25, "question": "Which of the following is most likely to reduce risk: ", "choices": ["A. Dividends ", "B. Bonds ", "C. Insurance", "D. Stocks"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Insurance. Businesses transfer the risk factor to some other person or business when they purchase insurance. An insurance policy is a contract between a business and an insurance company in which the insurance company agrees to provide protection against insurable losses which may occur. Stocks are shares of ownership in a business. Municipal bonds are sold by municipalities to raise funds for their use. Dividends are monies paid to individuals or companies which own stock in a business. SOURCE: EC:011 SOURCE: EC LAP 3\u2014Lose, Win, or Draw (Business Risk)  "}, {"number": 26, "question": "If each citizen in the United States increased the amount s/he spent on U.S. consumer goods, the gross domestic product (GDP) would probably ", "choices": ["A. increase. ", "B. decrease. ", "C. stay the same.", "D. not be affected."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Increase. Personal consumption expenditures, a GDP component, represent all of the consumer goods sold during the year. An increase in the sale of consumer goods will result in an increase in GDP unless there is a drop in one of the other GDP components such as government purchases, private investment, or net exports. SOURCE: EC:017 SOURCE: Pride, W. M., Hughes, R. J., & Kapoor, J. R. (2008). Business (9th ed.) [pp. 19-20]. Boston: Houghton Mifflin. SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16  "}, {"number": 27, "question": "Which of the following is a factor that often enables certain countries to trade successfully with each other: ", "choices": ["A. Equal governmental systems ", "B. Same religious institutions ", "C. Similar business subcultures", "D. Identical language traits"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Similar business subcultures. The business subculture of each country has its own unique beliefs, values, and ways of conducting business. The business subcultures of some countries are very similar to those of other countries. For example, the United States and the United Kingdom have similar business subcultures, which means that the businesspeople in these countries understand each other and conduct business in similar ways. Because of this, they trade successfully with each other. Countries that have different business subcultures may not be able to trade as successfully with each other because their businesspeople have different ways of doing business and may not understand each other as well. Different countries have different language traits, religious institutions, and governmental systems which may make it difficult for them to trade with each other. SOURCE: EC:045 SOURCE: EC LAP 24\u2014On Top of the World (Impact of Culture on the Global Environment)  "}, {"number": 28, "question": "Which of the following is a benefit to you as an individual of setting high personal standards for honesty and fairness: ", "choices": ["A. You will not need to be bonded by your employer.", "B. The business will have a good image.", "C. The number of mistakes you make will decrease.", "D. You will have increased self-respect."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "You will have increased self-respect. Knowing that you always try to be honest and fair bolsters your selfrespect. When you respect yourself, it is easier to respect others as well. Having high standards for honesty and fairness will not decrease the number of mistakes you make. If your job involves handling money, the business might choose to bond you to protect itself from possible loss, even though you are honest. Improving the business's image is a benefit to the business. SOURCE: EI:019 SOURCE: EI LAP 3\u2014Opt for Optimism  "}, {"number": 29, "question": "How does self-control help you to think clearly? ", "choices": ["A. By helping you to deal with criticism ", "B. By helping you to be defensive ", "C. By helping you to be objective", "D. By helping you to deal with coworkers"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "By helping you to be objective. Self-control helps you to think clearly by enabling you to keep your emotions under control. This helps you to be open-minded and objective. Self-control helps you to deal with criticism without becoming defensive, but that is not part of clear thinking. Self-control helps you to deal with coworkers by helping you to think before you speak. SOURCE: EI:025 SOURCE: EI LAP 14\u2014Control Yourself! (Demonstrating Self-Control)  "}, {"number": 30, "question": "Negative feedback makes many individuals uncomfortable because it ", "choices": ["A. is so rare. ", "B. involves so many people. ", "C. points out their shortcomings.", "D. occurs so regularly."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Points out their shortcomings. Negative feedback makes many individuals uncomfortable because it points out their weaknesses, faults, and shortcomings. The frequency of the feedback\u2014whether it occurs regularly or is rare\u2014has little to do with making individuals uncomfortable. Negative feedback should not involve a lot of people. In fact, constructive criticism is best shared in private. SOURCE: EI:003 SOURCE: EI LAP 15\u2014Grin and Bear It (Using Feedback for Personal Growth)  "}, {"number": 31, "question": "One of the ways that empathy benefits a business's employees directly is by helping them to ", "choices": ["A. get along with their coworkers. ", "B. focus on people's differences. ", "C. plan effectively for the future.", "D. move quickly up the career ladder."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Get along with their coworkers. Today's workplace is more diversified than ever before. We may not fully understand our coworkers because of the differences in our backgrounds. Empathy helps in this situation because it motivates us to look for similarities instead of focusing on differences. Empathy is not a factor in effective planning or career advancement. SOURCE: EI:030 SOURCE: EI LAP 12\u2014Have a Heart (Empathy)  "}, {"number": 32, "question": "Managers are more likely to be able to persuade employees to follow new procedures if the managers have ", "choices": ["A. self-motivation. ", "B. organizational skills. ", "C. enthusiasm.", "D. credibility."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Credibility. Credibility is believability. If employees believe what managers are saying, they are more likely to be persuaded to do what the managers want them to do. Managers develop credibility by always being truthful with employees. As a result, employees often like and trust managers who are credible and, therefore, are willing to follow their instructions. Having organizational skills, enthusiasm, or selfmotivation does not necessarily mean that managers will be able to persuade employees. SOURCE: EI:012 SOURCE: QS LAP 10\u2014Win Them Over SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17  "}, {"number": 33, "question": "Why might group members prefer to use an informal method of consensus building? ", "choices": ["A. Group members wish to avoid arguing. ", "B. The subject matter is controversial. ", "C. It allows for face-to-face interaction.", "D. There is more paperwork involved."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "It allows for face-to-face interaction. Group members might prefer to use an informal method of consensus building because it allows for face-to-face interaction. Some people consider this kind of give and take to be an essential ingredient in successful consensus building. When the subject matter is controversial or when group members wish to avoid arguing, a formal consensus-building method is more appropriate. A formal method also involves more paperwork. SOURCE: EI:011 SOURCE: EI LAP 19\u2014It's a Group Thing (Consensus Building)  "}, {"number": 34, "question": "When determining if a personal vision is realistic, a person must determine if the vision will have ", "choices": ["A. permanent results. ", "B. limited resources. ", "C. few setbacks.", "D. measurable goals."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Permanent results. Personal vision is the future that you want to create. It involves creating positive change through hard work over the long term. For example, Martin Luther King, Jr. had a vision in which his children would have equal rights with all Americans. His vision was to end racism, and he took many steps to make his vision come true. Due to his efforts, peoples' attitudes changed and laws were established to protect and ensure all peoples' rights, which created permanent results from his vision. When working toward a personal vision, a person may experience setbacks and challenges, such as limited resources. Not all of the results of visions can be measured because they often affect others on a personal and intangible level. SOURCE: EI:063 SOURCE: QS LAP 11\u2014Picture This!  "}, {"number": 35, "question": "Which of the following is the first step in the coaching process: ", "choices": ["A. Identify the problem. ", "B. Get a response. ", "C. Agree on goals.", "D. Plan for improvement."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Identify the problem. Identifying the problem is the first step in the coaching process. You must identify the problem before you can get a response from your coachee, agree on goals, or form a plan for improvement. SOURCE: EI:041 SOURCE: QS LAP 7\u2014Bring Out the Best  "}, {"number": 36, "question": "Jeremy is basically healthy, but he works with another employee who suffers from various chronic illnesses. Jeremy and his coworker differ in what way? ", "choices": ["A. Age ", "B. Physical condition ", "C. Ethnic heritage", "D. Education"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Physical condition. Jeremy and his coworker differ in physical condition (their basic health). They may or may not differ in age (the number of years lived), ethnic heritage (cultural background), or education (amount of learning acquired). SOURCE: EI:036 SOURCE: EI LAP 20\u2014Fair and Square (Treat Others Fairly at Work)  "}, {"number": 37, "question": "Which of the following is an example of legal tender issued by the federal government: ", "choices": ["A. Bank notes ", "B. Corporate bonds ", "C. Mutual funds", "D. Municipal bonds"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Bank notes. Bank notes are currency. Currency is the paper or metal (coin) money that individuals and businesses use to buy and sell goods and services. Paper money and coins are issued by a country's government. Corporate bonds are bonds issued by corporations to fund operating expenses. A mutual fund is a collection of shareholders' money that is invested by professional fund managers in an assortment of different securities, such as stocks and bonds. A bond is a piece of paper (real or virtual) that says the governing body or corporation will borrow your money at a particular interest rate for a particular period of time. Municipal bonds are issued by local governments. SOURCE: FI:059 SOURCE: McMahon, M. & Harris, B. (2003-2012). What is a bank note? Retrieved September 10, 2013, from http://www.wisegeek.com/what-is-a-bank-note.htm  "}, {"number": 38, "question": "An amount of money borrowed by an individual or a business simply by signing a promissory note is obtaining a(n) ", "choices": ["A. secured loan. ", "B. regular credit account. ", "C. unsecured loan.", "D. travel and entertainment card."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Unsecured loan. To obtain an unsecured loan, the borrower does not pledge anything s/he owns as security to guarantee that the loan will be repaid. Instead, the borrower signs a written promise to repay the loan. Secured loans require borrowers to guarantee repayment by pledging collateral. Regular credit accounts and travel and entertainment cards are used to purchase goods and services rather than to borrow money. In addition, these credit users agree to the terms for payment, credit limits, and interest as specified by the credit provider. SOURCE: FI:002 SOURCE: FI LAP 2\u2014Give Credit Where Credit is Due (Credit and Its Importance) SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18  "}, {"number": 39, "question": "Brandon is developing a financial plan, and one of his goals is to save enough money to buy a new car in two years. Has Brandon set a SMART goal? ", "choices": ["A. Yes, his goal is time-bounded and measureable.", "B. No, his goal is not attainable or results-oriented.", "C. No, his goal is not specific or measurable.", "D. Yes, his goal is attainable and specific."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "No, his goal is not specific or measurable. A financial goal is a short- or long-term objective that is measured in terms of money. Effective financial goals are SMART goals\u2014specific, measurable, attainable, results-oriented, and time-bounded. The goal is time-bounded because Brandon wants to save money to buy a car two years from now. It is results-oriented because Brandon will have something to show for his effort in two years\u2014a car. However, the goal is not specific or measurable because Brandon has not indicated how much he wants to save for the car. Also, Brandon has not indicated how he plans to save for the car, such as placing 15% of his weekly paycheck in a special savings account. There is not enough information to determine if the goal is attainable because it is not specific. SOURCE: FI:065 SOURCE: QS LAP 31\u2014Set Yourself Up  "}, {"number": 40, "question": "When you use money to make money, you are ", "choices": ["A. investing. ", "B. saving. ", "C. rationing.", "D. reimbursing."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Investing. Using money to make money is called investing. Saving is setting aside part of your current income for future use. Rationing is a function of relative prices that determines who gets the goods and services produced\u2014it is determining how scarce resources will be distributed. Reimbursing involves paying back or refunding money that someone has spent. SOURCE: FI:270 SOURCE: QS LAP 30\u2014Supersize Your Money  "}, {"number": 41, "question": "Incorrect information on an individual's credit report may hinder his/her ability to ", "choices": ["A. withdraw money from a savings account. ", "B. obtain a bank loan. ", "C. pay monthly credit-card balances.", "D. earn interest on stock holdings."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Obtain a bank loan. Banks obtain credit reports to make decisions about providing loans; therefore, it is important for individuals to periodically review the accuracy of their credit reports. By obtaining copies of their credit reports from an authorized credit agency, individuals can identify problems and take corrective action. Information presented in a credit report does not affect an individual's ability to withdraw money from a savings account, pay monthly credit-card balances, or earn interest on stock holdings. SOURCE: FI:072 SOURCE: Nolo. (2013). Your credit report can make or break your application. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/free-books/renters-rightsbook/chapter1-3.html  "}, {"number": 42, "question": "How do finance companies commonly raise capital? ", "choices": ["A. Issuing notes, bonds, and other obligations", "B. Investing funds from premium payments", "C. Investing deposits from savers", "D. Establishing mutual funds and investment banks"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Issuing notes, bonds, and other obligations. Finance companies, also known as credit companies, are a type of financial institution. Finance companies raise capital by issuing notes, bonds, and other obligations. They use this capital to provide loans to businesses and consumers. Insurance companies raise capital by investing funds from premiums and offering loans to clients. Deposit-taking institutions accept funds from savers and use those funds to offer loans to borrowers. Investment institutions, not finance companies, establish mutual funds and investment banks. SOURCE: FI:336 SOURCE: MBA Research and Curriculum Center. (2009). Introduction to finance course guide (pp. 5-19). Columbus, OH: Author.  "}, {"number": 43, "question": "Debt markets buy and sell ___________, and equity markets buy and sell _________. ", "choices": ["A. grain, gold ", "B. corporate stock, certificates of deposit ", "C. government bonds, corporate stock", "D. gold, government bonds"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Government bonds, corporate stock. Investors buy debt securities, such as government bonds and certificates of deposit, through debt markets. The issuers of debt securities pay investors at a certain time (maturity date) and at a specific interest rate. All levels of government sell debt securities to fund various projects and initiatives. Equity markets trade financial instruments such as corporate stock through exchanges or over-the-counter markets. The stock does not have a maturity date, and can be bought or sold at any time for a gain or loss. Grain and gold are sold through commodities markets. SOURCE: FI:337 SOURCE: The Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco. (2005, October). What are the differences between debt and equity markets? Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.frbsf.org/education/publications/doctor-econ/2005/october/debt-equity-market SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19  "}, {"number": 44, "question": "A primary advantage to consumers of convergence and consolidation in the finance industry is ", "choices": ["A. guaranteed earnings. ", "B. easier decision making. ", "C. one-stop shopping.", "D. liquid capital."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "One-stop shopping. Convergence is the merging of financial providers from different financial sectors, and consolidation is the merging of financial providers within the same institutional category. An advantage to consumers of the convergence and consolidation in the finance industry is the creation of \"one-stop\" shopping, which reduces the need to go to different financial providers for different financial products. Convergence and consolidation do not always make decision making easier for consumers, nor do they guarantee earnings on their investments. Convergence and consolidation usually provide more liquid capital for the financial institutions rather than for consumers. SOURCE: FI:573 SOURCE: MBAResearch and Curriculum Center. (2009). Introduction to finance course guide (pp. 5-106, 5-107). Columbus, Ohio: Author.  "}, {"number": 45, "question": "Which of the following is most likely to have a negative effect on financial markets: ", "choices": ["A. Interest rates fluctuate daily. ", "B. Business expansion slows quickly. ", "C. Unemployment rates stabilize steadily.", "D. Consumer spending increases consistently."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Business expansion slows quickly. Slower business expansion is one factor that indicates an economic recession. When business productivity slows, there is less work for laborers. When there is less work for laborers, businesses tend to lay off employees, causing unemployment rates to rise. Unemployment leads to less consumer spending because the displaced workers do not have income available to buy goods and services, including financial products. Fluctuating interest rates do not always indicate problems with financial markets because slight daily fluctuations are normal. Increased consumer spending usually indicates that the economy is rebounding, that people are working, and that people have more money to invest in the financial markets. SOURCE: FI:574 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 220). South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 46, "question": "Which of the following has accelerated the globalization of financial markets: ", "choices": ["A. A decrease in foreign access to domestic markets", "B. An expansion of protectionism practices", "C. The movement toward fixed exchange rates", "D. The reduction of government regulations"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "The reduction of government regulations. Liberalization and deregulation have enabled capital to flow more freely across national borders. Reducing the limits (e.g., quotas, tariffs) on foreigners' access to domestic markets encourages international investment and trade. Globalization has encouraged the movement toward floating exchange rates. Protectionism refers to government policies that are designed to protect domestic industries and businesses against foreign competition. SOURCE: FI:575 SOURCE: MBAResearch and Curriculum Center. (2009). Introduction to finance course guide (pp. 5-156-5-158). Columbus, OH: Author.  "}, {"number": 47, "question": "Marcus wants to invest a portion of his money in long-term securities to finance his son's college education and his own retirement. To help him make the best investment decisions, Marcus should obtain the services of a ", "choices": ["A. credit-union representative. ", "B. loan officer. ", "C. licensed tax accountant.", "D. certified financial planner."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Certified financial planner. Financial planners help clients develop investment plans and prepare for the future. Financial planners recommend and sell financial products such as mutual funds, stocks and bonds, insurance, etc. When selecting a financial planner, it is important to make sure that s/he has the appropriate training and certification to provide financial services. Tax accountants, loan officers, and credit-union representatives do not usually have the credentials to provide in-depth financial advice and select appropriate investments for clients. SOURCE: FI:075 SOURCE: Ryan, J.S. (2010). Managing your personal finances (6th ed.) [p. 251]. Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 48, "question": "What does an income statement show about a company over a period of time? ", "choices": ["A. Liabilities ", "B. Reliability ", "C. Equity", "D. Profitability"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Profitability. The income statement shows a company's profitability over a period of time. Reliability, equity, and liabilities are not part of the income statement. SOURCE: FI:274 SOURCE: QS LAP 36\u2014The Source Is With You SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20  "}, {"number": 49, "question": "While Chase was reviewing his stock performance, he saw that his commodities investment dropped .002 points from Monday's close to Tuesday's close. This drop is called the ", "choices": ["A. net change. ", "B. true value. ", "C. net worth.", "D. true yield."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Net change. Newspapers, business publications, and websites publish a securities or stock table, which is a format used to list stock quotes. The table helps investors monitor the performance of their stocks. The net change is a column in the table that indicates the difference between a stock's closing price and the previous day's price, which may increase or decrease (drop). True value, net worth, and true yield are not terms that describe the difference between a stock's closing price and the previous day's price. SOURCE: FI:275 SOURCE: QS LAP 37\u2014Table Talk (Reading Stock Tables)  "}, {"number": 50, "question": "The stock table column that tells you how many shares were traded that day is labeled ", "choices": ["A. DIV. ", "B. NET CHG. ", "C. YLD %.", "D. VOL."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "VOL. VOL is short for Volume (sometimes called Sales). It records how many shares were traded that day. NET CHG stands for Net Change, or the difference between the closing price and the previous day's price. DIV is short for dividend, which is a portion of a company's profits, paid to shareholders each year. YLD% stands for Yield Percentage, which is determined by dividing the dividend into the current stock price. SOURCE: FI:275 SOURCE: QS LAP 37\u2014Table Talk  "}, {"number": 51, "question": "An example of an internal financial risk is ", "choices": ["A. consumer buying power. ", "B. foreign exchange rate changes. ", "C. improper budgeting practices.", "D. credit downgrades."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Improper budgeting practices. Financial risks are possible events or situations that directly impact a company's cash flow. In some cases, financial risks prevent a company from having sufficient funds to meet its financial obligations. Improper budgeting practices are an example of an internal financial risk. External financial risks include foreign exchange rate change, consumer buying power, and credit downgrades. SOURCE: FI:084 SOURCE: FI LAP 8\u2014Prepare for the Worst; Expect the Best (Nature of Risk Management)  "}, {"number": 52, "question": "Why would a bank examine a business's balance sheet? ", "choices": ["A. To determine whether the company qualifies for additional credit", "B. To determine whether to declare the company bankrupt", "C. To meet its oversight responsibilities of the business community", "D. To recognize its most profitable customers"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "To determine whether the company qualifies for additional credit. By examining the balance sheet, banks determine what a business owns as well as what it owes. If the business does not have sufficient assets, the bank will probably avoid loaning it money. Businesses, not banks, declare themselves in bankruptcy. Banks do not have oversight responsibilities of the business community. A bank would examine a company's income statement to determine profitability. SOURCE: FI:093 SOURCE: AccountingCoach.com (n.d.). Balance sheet. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.accountingcoach.com/online-accounting-course/05Xpg01.html  "}, {"number": 53, "question": "What do many businesses develop to encourage ethical behavior in finance? ", "choices": ["A. Penalties ", "B. Punishments ", "C. Sanctions", "D. Standards"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Standards. Ethical standards are unwritten rules that govern your behavior. Many businesses develop ethical standards that they expect employees to follow, particularly in finance. Finance is the process of obtaining funds and using them to achieve the goals of the business. Ethical issues may arise in the process of managing money, and having ethical standards to follow helps employees make the right decisions. There may be consequences for failing to abide by ethical standards, but businesses usually do not develop specific punishments, sanctions, or penalties. SOURCE: FI:355 SOURCE: Megginson, W.L. & Smart, S.B. (2006). Introduction to corporate finance (pp. 31-32). Mason, OH: Thomson South-Western.  "}, {"number": 54, "question": "Why it is important for businesses to keep accurate accounts-receivable information? ", "choices": ["A. To evaluate interest rates ", "B. To forecast sales ", "C. To classify stocks", "D. To monitor aging accounts"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To monitor aging accounts. The accounts receivable\u2014all the monies owed to a firm by its customers\u2014 should be monitored carefully because they affect the business's cash flow and its ability to pay its employees and creditors. To collect the monies owed to them, the business should implement follow-up procedures to contact customers with delinquent or aging accounts. Businesses do not monitor accountsreceivable information to forecast sales, classify stocks, or evaluate interest rates. SOURCE: FM:002 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 342). South-Western Cengage Learning. SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21  "}, {"number": 55, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a businessperson exhibiting unethical behavior in relation to a business's financial information: ", "choices": ["A. An auditor verifies the accuracy of a corporation's financial statements.", "B. An unauthorized employee reviews a client's financial information.", "C. A banker requests financial information from a business to process a loan.", "D. A manager examines the business's financial records to develop a budget."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "An unauthorized employee reviews a client's financial information. Businesses have an ethical duty to protect their clients' financial information. Businesses must develop and implement procedures that reduce the risk of theft or unauthorized access to confidential financial information by internal and external sources. Verifying the accuracy of financial statements, requesting financial information to process a loan, and examining financial records to develop a budget are necessary and ethical practices. SOURCE: FM:003 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 339). Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 56, "question": "Why has online technology's use increased in financial-information management? ", "choices": ["A. Recognition that the security of transactions is no longer an issue", "B. Removal of electronic information exchange procedures", "C. Passage of laws that recognize electronic documents as legally binding", "D. Protection of customers' right to privacy"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Passage of laws that recognize electronic documents as legally binding. As businesses have become more comfortable with the use of electronic information, their willingness to accept electronic documents as legally binding contracts has also increased. This has been buoyed by the passage of laws recognizing electronic documents and signatures as legally binding. Electronic information exchange procedures have not been removed. These procedures provide a way for people to exchange information electronically. Security remains an issue for online financial-information management. Although the customers' right to privacy is an issue, it has not contributed to the increased use of online technology in financial-information management. SOURCE: FM:011 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 338-339). South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 57, "question": "What must a business do before deciding which data-mining technique to use? ", "choices": ["A. Filter the raw data ", "B. Acquire the desired results ", "C. Determine the research question", "D. Analyze product usage patterns"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Determine the research question. Data mining is the process of searching computer databases to look for patterns and relationships among data. Businesses use data mining to find answers to questions. For example, a bank might ask the question, \u201cWhich customers tend to visit the bank between noon and 5 p.m. on Tuesdays?\u201d Before the bank can answer this question, it must identify what types of data it will need to answer the question, and then set appropriate computer queries to obtain the data. After determining the research question, the business can filter the data and analyze the results, which may or may not include product usage patterns. The data may or may not provide the results that the business desired. SOURCE: FM:012 SOURCE: Hair, J.F., Bush, R.P., & Ortinau, D.J. (2009). Marketing research in a digital information environment (4th ed.) [pp. 98-100]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin.  "}, {"number": 58, "question": "Which of the following questions would be the least difficult to answer using data mining techniques: ", "choices": ["A. What makes some customers a better credit risk than others?", "B. When will this customer place his/her next order?", "C. Why did this customer move her/his checking account to another bank?", "D. What product will a particular customer order next?"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "What makes some customers a better credit risk than others? Data mining is frequently used to classify groups of people or things. For example, data mining could help us to understand what makes customers who are a better credit risk different from the customers who are not. However, data mining is not as effective when trying to pinpoint information about one particular customer. Because a customer's decisions are based on many factors that a database cannot capture, it is difficult to determine that specific person's actions. Therefore, a database would not be an efficient tool to use to predict when the customer will place his/her next order, to learn why s/he moved a checking account to another bank, or to determine what product s/he will order next. Probability models are more successful in predicting what a customer will do and why. SOURCE: FM:012 SOURCE: Alter, A. (2007, June 13). What data mining can and can't do. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.cioinsight.com/c/a/Past-News/What-Data-Mining-Can-and-Cant-Do/ SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22  "}, {"number": 59, "question": "If you were using a computer spreadsheet to track your small-business's budget, which of the following should you categorize as investment income: ", "choices": ["A. Dividends ", "B. Cash sales ", "C. Credit sales", "D. Interest on debt"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Dividends. A budget is an estimate of income and expense for a specific period of time. Income is the money received by a business from outside sources. Businesses generate income from product sales (cash and credit), interest earned, and investments. Dividends are income earned on stock investments. Interest on debt (e.g., a bank loan) is a business expense. SOURCE: FM:013 SOURCE: Peavler, R. (2009). Business budget worksheet. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://bizfinance.about.com/od/businessbudgeting/a/budget_wksheet.htm  "}, {"number": 60, "question": "Which of the following questions should the user of financial analysis applications be able to answer: ", "choices": ["A. Why are products being added to the company's product mix?", "B. Which projects are business priorities?", "C. What will the company's actual amount of profit margin be next year?", "D. What is the change in the company's liquidity?"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "What is the change in the company's liquidity? By using financial analysis applications, a business gains insight into its financial health, such as the company's liquidity. These applications also are useful in helping to identify trends. The applications cannot accurately forecast a business's actual amount of profit margin; however, they help to identify trends impacting the profit margin. These applications cannot identify project priorities or tell why products are being added to the product mix. They report financial data. SOURCE: FM:014 SOURCE: MicroStrategy.com. (n.d.). Financial analysis. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://latam.microstrategy.com/financial-analysis/  "}, {"number": 61, "question": "The purpose of using the locking function for a database is to ", "choices": ["A. set queries to retrieve data from specific data fields.", "B. allow users to import data from external programs.", "C. develop reports and summarize various data.", "D. ensure that only one person can edit data fields."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Ensure that only one person can edit data fields. Many databases allow users to view the same information at the same time. The locking function prevents more than one person at a time from making changes to the database. The import function allows users to import data from external programs. The primary purpose of the locking function is not to develop reports, summarize data, or set queries. SOURCE: FM:015 SOURCE: Berry, D. (2000-2013). Concurrency control and locking. Retrieved October 30, 2009, from http://www.service-architecture.com/database/articles/concurrency_control_and_locking.html  "}, {"number": 62, "question": "Investment firms must accurately report their financial position because ", "choices": ["A. they are trusted to maintain an accurate accounting of people's revenue and expenses.", "B. others rely on the information when making credit and/or investment decisions.", "C. they maintain both brick-and-mortar and virtual businesses for trading.", "D. people know that investment firms would not take advantage of them."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Others rely on the information when making credit and/or investment decisions. It's important for investment firms to share their actual financial situation rather than manipulate the numbers to present the most desired financial situation. Accountants, rather than investment firms, maintain an accurate accounting of people's revenue and expenses. Having both brick-and-mortar and virtual businesses would not impact the accuracy of investment firms' reporting. Unfortunately, most people understand that not all people are honest. Therefore, they need to know enough about investing to make good choices. SOURCE: FM:004 SOURCE: Accounting and Compliance International. (n.d.). Accurate accounting for broker-dealers. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.finraexamsupport.com/accurate-accounting  "}, {"number": 63, "question": "Which of the following establishes the guidelines for the way that a publicly owned company reports its financial position: ", "choices": ["A. The federal government ", "B. The board of directors ", "C. The accounting department", "D. The stockholders"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The federal government. Governments require businesses to provide certain types of financial information to regulatory agencies and shareholders. Public corporations are required to provide financial information that has been verified by an independent auditor to shareholders (owners of the company) and prospective investors. The board of directors and the accounting department perform activities to ensure that the corporation is in compliance. SOURCE: FM:004 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 114-115). South-Western Cengage Learning. SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23  "}, {"number": 64, "question": "Which of the following statements regarding accounting and finance is correct: ", "choices": ["A. Accounting is much broader than finance, which focuses on investments.", "B. Accounting focuses on the past, while finance focuses on the future.", "C. Financial managers typically report to the vice president of accounting.", "D. The finance department focuses on assets, while accountants track liabilities."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Accounting focuses on the past, while finance focuses on the future. Accountants are responsible for tracking and analyzing financial transactions to determine a client's or business's financial performance. Individuals in finance use the information that accountants prepare to predict and plan for the future. Finance, which focuses on money and capital markets, investments, and financial management, is broader than accounting. Private accountants typically report to a controller who reports to an executive within the finance department, such as the vice president of finance or chief financial officer. Financial managers and accountants focus on both assets and liabilities, not one or the other. SOURCE: FM:005 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 102-103). South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 65, "question": "What type of accounting system is used for internal decision making, is not governed by generally accepted accounting principles, and emphasizes the future? ", "choices": ["A. Managerial ", "B. Tax ", "C. Financial", "D. Double entry"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Managerial. Managerial accounting systems are used primarily to aid managers with their decision making, planning, and controlling. Businesses are not required by law to have managerial accounting systems; therefore, there is less emphasis on the precision of data. These systems also do not have to meet generally accepted accounting principles. Tax and financial accounting are governed by generally accepted accounting principles, and they emphasize the business's past financial performance. These systems are designed to provide financial information to external audiences. A double entry accounting system is an accounting concept requiring every accounting transaction to be recorded in two accounts: in one, the transaction is a debit, while in the other account, the transaction is a credit. SOURCE: FM:006 SOURCE: Shanker, S. (n.d.). Objectives of internal managerial accounting systems. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/objectives-internal-managerialaccounting-systems-20945.html  "}, {"number": 66, "question": "If a trend indicates that a business is making more money, the business is most likely to have identified the trend by comparing its __________ from previous time periods. ", "choices": ["A. advertising budgets ", "B. profitability ratios ", "C. interest rates", "D. payroll records"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Profitability ratios. Profitability ratios measure the business's ability to generate profit. By comparing the profitability ratios from consecutive time periods (e.g., quarterly), the business can determine if it is generating profits. If profits tend to increase, then it is likely that the business is generating more revenue or making money. Advertising budgets, interest rates, and payroll records do not provide information about the business's profitability. SOURCE: FM:008 SOURCE: Peavler, R. (n.d.). What are the five categories of financial ratios and what do they measure? Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://bizfinance.about.com/od/financialratios/f/finratioanal2.htm  "}, {"number": 67, "question": "Before approving a loan application, a bank is likely to analyze the applicant's ", "choices": ["A. brand preferences. ", "B. inflation rate. ", "C. debt ratio.", "D. performance goals."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Debt ratio. To reduce the risk of nonpayment or default on a loan, a bank reviews the loan applicant's debt ratio before approving the loan. The debt ratio indicates the applicant's current level of debt in relation to his/her current assets (e.g., income, home). If the applicant has a high level of outstanding debt and few liquid assets, the applicant is more likely to default on the loan. In this situation, the applicant would most likely be denied the loan. The bank may consider the economy's inflation rate in relation to the applicant's debt ratio when evaluating the loan application. The bank is not likely to consider the applicant's brand preferences or performance goals. SOURCE: FM:009 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 266-270). South-Western Cengage Learning. SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24  "}, {"number": 68, "question": "An automotive parts supplier must decide whether to extend a credit line to a new business customer. Before approving or denying credit for the new customer, what should the supplier do? ", "choices": ["A. Analyze the customer's credit application, credit report, bank information, and financial\nstatements", "B. Contact company shareholders and ask for permission to extend credit to the customer", "C. Discuss the customer's request for credit with the supplier's financial accountants", "D. Evaluate the qualifications and work histories of the customer's management team"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Analyze the customer's credit application, credit report, bank information, and financial statements. Businesses commonly analyze their customers' financial information when determining whether or not to extend credit to these customers. At the very least, a business such as the automotive parts supplier should analyze a customer's credit application, credit report, bank information, and financial statements before approving or denying credit for the customer. It is not feasible for the supplier to contact its shareholders and ask for permission to extend credit to its customers. The supplier's financial accountants are not likely to discuss the customer's request for credit; the company's credit analyst(s) would make the decision. While learning the qualifications and work histories of the customer's management team could be helpful, it is much more important to analyze the customer's financial information prior to approving or denying credit for the customer. SOURCE: FM:009 SOURCE: Dennis, M.C. (2011). Evaluating financial health. Retrieved March 7, 2012, from http://www.encyclopediaofcredit.com/Evaluating-Financial-Health  "}, {"number": 69, "question": "Which of the following sources of financial data might a manager use to analyze expense variances: ", "choices": ["A. Cash receipts ", "B. Customer invoices ", "C. Payroll reports", "D. Productivity reports"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Payroll reports. A variance is a discrepancy or difference between what was planned and what actually occurred. Financial managers often use financial data to analyze variances\u2014to determine what caused actual results to differ from the projected results. A manager might analyze expense variances to determine why a business's expenses were either higher or lower than budgeted. Payroll reports indicate the flow of funds out of a firm to its employees. Therefore, payroll reports provide information about a business expense. Customer invoices and cash receipts, on the other hand, focus on company revenue, not expenses. Productivity reports are often used to analyze operational results, but they are seldom used in expense variance analysis. SOURCE: FM:010 SOURCE: Microsoft. (2013). Analyze variance effectively. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://office.microsoft.com/en-us/excel/HA011562881033.aspx  "}, {"number": 70, "question": "Making sure a company follows laws and regulations describes the HR management activity of ", "choices": ["A. staffing. ", "B. compliance. ", "C. compensation and benefits.", "D. employee relations."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Compliance. Compliance is an HR management activity that ensures a company is following all applicable laws and regulations. Staffing is an HR management activity that ensures a company has appropriate employees available and ready to work. Compensation and benefits is an HR management activity that ensures a company's employees are paid. Employee relations is an HR management activity that ensures a company's employees have positive working relationships. SOURCE: HR:410 SOURCE: HR LAP 35\u2014People Pusher (Nature of Human Resources Management)  "}, {"number": 71, "question": "Businesses should keep promises to customers in both personal interactions with employees and ", "choices": ["A. advertising. ", "B. newspaper articles. ", "C. coworker interactions.", "D. future products."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Advertising. Keeping promises to customers involves both personal interactions and advertising. Companies must make good on their promises, no matter what method they use to make them to their customers. These promises don't usually come from newspaper articles, coworker interactions, or future products. SOURCE: MK:015 SOURCE: MK LAP 2\u2014Act Now (Employee Actions)  "}, {"number": 72, "question": "While researching information for a business report, Tara reads the following statement in an online newspaper article: \"Although unemployment has dropped slightly over the past few months, many politicians have indicated that they believe the government has done enough to get our country out of this recession.\" This is an example of information that contains ", "choices": ["A. statistics. ", "B. historical facts. ", "C. criticism.", "D. poll data."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Criticism. When assessing information, it is important to discern fact from opinion and criticism. The example is a statement of disapproval, which is criticism. It is based on opinion or beliefs rather than facts. Facts contain information or data that are indisputable and true. SOURCE: NF:077 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J. V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 17]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25  "}, {"number": 73, "question": "ChemTech International plans to build a new research facility, which is to be completed in two years. As an employee with ChemTech, your supervisor has requested that you produce a detailed document to send to potential vendors and contractors that outlines how they should submit bids to perform work for the new facility. The document is to contain instructions about the type of information the potential vendors should provide in their bids, and the format in which the information should be presented. What type of document are you preparing? ", "choices": ["A. Summary of qualifications ", "B. Request for proposal ", "C. Executive summary", "D. Business plan"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Request for proposal. Complex projects often require the expertise of external resources. Building a new facility requires skills from architects, construction companies, electricians, etc. And because these types of projects are expensive, companies want to obtain bids from the potential vendors or contractors to determine which one is best suited to perform the work. A request for proposal (RFP) is an invitation for potential vendors to present bids to obtain a contract and perform the work. Because the work is complex, the RFP must include specific information and provide detailed instructions about the way the proposal should be written. Often, an RFP will require potential vendors to provide a summary of qualifications as a section of the proposal. A business plan is a company's blueprint for success\u2014its business model. An executive summary is an element of a business plan and provides an overview of the most important information. SOURCE: NF:080 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. 413-414]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall.  "}, {"number": 74, "question": "If a company is managing its information effectively, the data should be accurate and ", "choices": ["A. encrypted. ", "B. relevant. ", "C. anonymous.", "D. positive."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Relevant. In order to make business decisions, companies access, store, maintain, and evaluate a variety of information (facts, data). To make appropriate decisions, companies need to make sure the information that they are basing their decisions upon is accurate and relevant. For example, information from an employee's performance review will not help the business determine how to price its products. Information from an anonymous source may be incorrect and could lead to poor decisions and undesirable outcomes. Encryption is the process of transforming information into a secret code so that only the recipient can read it. Not all information needs to be encrypted. While positive information about the company is nice, it is more important that the information is honest, accurate, and relevant. SOURCE: NF:110 SOURCE: Ivancevich, J.M., & Duening, T.N. (2007). Business principles, guidelines, and practices (2nd ed.) [pp. 483-484]. Mason, OH: Thomson.  "}, {"number": 75, "question": "JavaScript, BETA, AppleScript, and Ubercode are examples of computer ", "choices": ["A. service providers. ", "B. search engines. ", "C. programming languages.", "D. disk drives."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Programming languages. A computer programming language is the language or code that instructs a computer to carry out specific actions in relation to certain keystrokes. Computer programmers use various types of computer programming languages to develop computer hardware and software programs. Search engines are computer programs that crawl the Web looking for information. Service providers provide access to a service, such as the Internet. A disk drive is a component of a computer that reads data from and writes data to removable computer disks. SOURCE: NF:084 SOURCE: Answers.com. (2013). Programming language. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.answers.com/topic/programming-language#  "}, {"number": 76, "question": "An upscale department store tracks customer purchases made with store credit cards and then tailors promotional messages and merchandise offers to specific clients based on their purchases. What software allows the retailer to manage this strategy? ", "choices": ["A. Spreadsheet ", "B. Word processing ", "C. Database", "D. Systems tools"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Database. Database software allows companies to collect, store, and organize customer information. This information can be used to maintain, analyze, and combine customer information in order to send certain messages to specific customers. Spreadsheet and word-processing software do not perform the functions required by the retailer. Systems tools are used to maintain the computer. SOURCE: NF:009 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 658). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 77, "question": "How long are businesses required to keep their records? ", "choices": ["A. On a seasonal basis ", "B. Varies greatly ", "C. Indefinitely", "D. One year"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Varies greatly. The length of time that businesses use and store their records can vary greatly. Some businesses will use certain records indefinitely, while other businesses might maintain information on a seasonal basis or for only one year. The law often determines how long certain records must be maintained. SOURCE: NF:001 SOURCE: Burrow, J.L. (2012). Marketing (3rd ed.) [p. 349]. Mason, OH: South-Western, Cengage Learning. SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26  "}, {"number": 78, "question": "What type of information should a company's marketing department review to make sure that enough products are available to meet customer demand for an upcoming sales promotion? ", "choices": ["A. Performance ", "B. Financial ", "C. Operations", "D. Inventory"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Inventory. Companies keep many types of records about their various business activities. Management and employees use the records to make decisions about day-to-day and future actions. The goal of a sales promotion is to stimulate short-term sales. A company that is planning a sales promotion featuring specific products needs to make sure that there are enough products available at the right time to meet the anticipated increases in customer demand. By reviewing inventory reports, employees can see how much stock is available and how much they need to order to ensure stock is available during the sales promotion. Accounting, operations, and performance data do not provide enough information to make an informed decision about inventory issues. SOURCE: NF:014 SOURCE: Burrow, J.L. (2006). Marketing (2nd ed.) [pp. 120-121]. Mason, OH: South-Western.  "}, {"number": 79, "question": "Warehousing and shipping methods are operations considerations related to ", "choices": ["A. scheduling. ", "B. logistics. ", "C. maintenance needs.", "D. expense control."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Logistics. Operations are the day-to-day activities for continued business functioning. Logistics refers to the function of operations that manages the flow of goods and services from production to consumption. Logistics includes all the people, information, and processes involved in storing (e.g., type of warehouse) and transporting goods (e.g., shipping method). Scheduling is the production activity that establishes the timetable to be followed in production. Maintenance needs refer to the routine maintenance and repair of business facilities and equipment. The operations function controls many activities within the business, which means that this function encounters a lot of expenses incurred by the business. Therefore, expense control is an important operations activity because it focuses on efficiency and keeping the business's costs low for its day-to-day activities. SOURCE: OP:189 SOURCE: OP LAP 3\u2014Smooth Operations (Nature of Operations)  "}, {"number": 80, "question": "What does the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) require all companies to have available for use? ", "choices": ["A. Emergency generator units ", "B. Replacement office equipment ", "C. Adequate first-aid supplies", "D. Back-up power sources"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Adequate first-aid supplies. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) requires companies of all sizes to have adequate first-aid supplies available for use. Employees should find out where these supplies are located before an accident has the chance to happen. It would also be beneficial for employees to know how to use the first-aid supplies. OSHA does not require companies to have back-up power sources, replacement office equipment, or emergency generator units. SOURCE: OP:009 SOURCE: University of Wyoming. (2010, April). First Aid Kit Basics: OSHA 1910.51. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.uwyo.edu/ehs/_files/docs/factsheets/firstaidkitbasics.pdf  "}, {"number": 81, "question": "What do you need to identify if there are complicated jobs that members of the group are unable to perform? ", "choices": ["A. Support services ", "B. Alternative tasks ", "C. Technical equipment", "D. Replacement items"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Support services. Support services are the technical or complicated activities that project members cannot do themselves. After you decide what type of additional help you might need to complete the project, you should identify the other people, organizations, and businesses that need to be involved in the project. Maybe you need the help of trained professionals to use complex equipment or different types of transportation. While determining the type of work that needs to be done, you might identify technical equipment. However, it is possible that a member of the group knows how to use this equipment. In many cases, it will not be possible to identify alternative tasks or replacement items. Then, it will be necessary to locate support services. SOURCE: OP:003 SOURCE: QS LAP 19\u2014Get What You Need SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27  "}, {"number": 82, "question": "What is an important activity that businesses should include in project planning to improve the chances of the project being successful? ", "choices": ["A. Orientation ", "B. Communication ", "C. Negotiation", "D. Compensation"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Communication. Communication is an exchange of information, which is an important part of project planning. In order for a project to succeed, everyone involved in developing and carrying out the project needs to know the goals, strategies, and expected outcomes of the project. Sufficient information needs to be communicated during all phases of planning in order for those involved to be able to provide input and to perform their assigned tasks. Orientation is job preparation or induction training for new employees. Compensation is wages, incentives, and benefits offered to an employee. Negotiation involves compromise in order to resolve a problem or dispute. SOURCE: OP:001 SOURCE: Portny, S., Mantel, S. J., Meredith, J. R., Shafer, S. M., & Sutton, M. M. (2008). Project management: Planning, scheduling, and controlling projects (p. 357). Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley & Sons.  "}, {"number": 83, "question": "What do managers often use to evaluate project results? ", "choices": ["A. Standards ", "B. Techniques ", "C. Resources", "D. Activities"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Standards. Standards are specifications or statements that are used as a basis for making comparisons or judgments. Managers often use standards as the basis for evaluating project results. For example, one standard might be financial, such as to increase sales by a certain amount. Then, the manager compares the results with the standard to determine if the project was effective. Techniques are methods or activities that might be used to carry out the project. Resources are items that are needed to complete a project. SOURCE: OP:159 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 258). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 84, "question": "An important aspect of a quality culture in the workplace is the belief that ", "choices": ["A. change is unnecessary. ", "B. management has the best ideas. ", "C. there are ways to improve.", "D. individual performance is most important."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "There are ways to improve. When a business has a quality culture, its employees share the common belief that all functions of the business must consistently achieve the established standards of excellence and that employees must continuously look for ways to improve those standards. Employees with a quality-culture mindset are always looking for ways to increase personal work efficiency, streamline processes, maximize creativity, and improve products and customer-service levels. A business with a quality culture believes that each employee has valuable ideas, that changes are necessary for improvement, and that teamwork and cooperation are important for achieving the business's goals. SOURCE: OP:019 SOURCE: Burrow, J.L., & Kleindl, B. (2012). Business management (13th ed.) [p. 99]. Mason, OH: South-Western, Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 85, "question": "Why is it important for a business to keep its selling area neat and clean? ", "choices": ["A. To please vendors ", "B. To satisfy inspectors ", "C. To attract customers", "D. To interest employees"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To attract customers. Customers usually prefer to shop at businesses that are clean and neat. Keeping the selling area in good condition promotes an image that appeals to customers and encourages them to buy. Customers are more likely to be attracted to clean businesses, which often leads to an increase in sales. Businesses do not keep their selling areas neat and clean in order to satisfy inspectors, please vendors, or interest employees. SOURCE: OP:032 SOURCE: Berman, B., & Evans, J.R. (2013). Retail management: A strategic approach (12th ed.) [p. 328]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Education, Prentice Hall.  "}, {"number": 86, "question": "A man comes to pick up his order at the office where Courtney works. When she tells him his order hasn't arrived yet, he seems a little upset. She asks for his order number again so she can double-check it and find out where it is. Which step of the seven-step problem-solving method does this situation illustrate? ", "choices": ["A. State and check assumptions ", "B. Collect information ", "C. Define the problem", "D. Evaluate the solution"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Collect information. Courtney is collecting information about the man's order so she can find out why it hasn't arrived on time. The problem has already been defined\u2014the man's order is missing. Courtney isn't stating assumptions by asking for this information. And she can't evaluate the solution yet because she hasn't chosen one at this point. SOURCE: PD:077 SOURCE: PD LAP 17\u2014No Problem (Problem Solving) SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28  "}, {"number": 87, "question": "To allow your ideas to flow freely when trying to be creative, you should avoid being ", "choices": ["A. determined. ", "B. independent. ", "C. self-critical.", "D. curious."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Self-critical. Few things stop creativity like criticism. Censoring your ideas limits the number of ideas you have and often limits the quality of those that do appear. Independence, curiosity, and determination are traits that creative people often have in common. SOURCE: PD:012 SOURCE: Rieck, D. (n.d.). 8 bad habits that crush your creativity and stifle your success. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.copyblogger.com/creativity-killers/  "}, {"number": 88, "question": "Which of the following items might show up on a daily \"to-do\" list: ", "choices": ["A. Marketing department meeting at 1:30 ", "B. Research at least five career paths ", "C. Move to New York City", "D. Read 20 articles in BusinessWeek"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Marketing department meeting at 1:30. A marketing department meeting at 1:30 is an item that belongs on a daily \"to-do\" list. Researching five career paths and reading 20 articles from BusinessWeek are items that belong on a weekly or monthly \"to-do\" list. Moving to New York City is a goal, not an item for a \"to-do\" list. SOURCE: PD:019 SOURCE: PD LAP 1\u2014About Time (Time Management)  "}, {"number": 89, "question": "Which of the following is a technique for effectively beginning an employment interview: ", "choices": ["A. Give name clearly ", "B. Tell a joke ", "C. Speak loudly", "D. Take the initiative"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Give name clearly. Effectively beginning the interview is very important because first impressions are often long-lasting. One technique for getting off to a good start is to smile and give your name clearly when you greet the interviewer. This sends a positive signal to the interviewer and creates a good impression. It is inappropriate to tell jokes because the applicant probably does not know the interviewer personally. Interviewees should speak in a normal tone of voice. The interviewer should take the initiative. SOURCE: PD:028 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 136-137). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 90, "question": "Under which of the following circumstances is it appropriate for applicants to prepare interview follow-up letters: ", "choices": ["A. Before they agree to pre-employment testing", "B. When they are no longer interested in the job", "C. After they have submitted application forms", "D. In order to send information with r\u00e9sum\u00e9s"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "When they are no longer interested in the job. One of the reasons for sending follow-up letters is to be courteous and thank interviewers for their time. Applicants who have interviewed with a business should send follow-up letters even if they are no longer interested in the job, because that will help to build a positive relationship. At some point in the future, applicants may want to be considered for other positions with that company, and their courteous behavior in the past will be remembered. Follow-up letters are not submitted with application forms, sent with r\u00e9sum\u00e9s, or before agreeing to pre-employment testing. SOURCE: PD:029 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed) [pp. 71-72]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 91, "question": "Which of the following is usually the most effective way of developing career opportunities: ", "choices": ["A. Interviewing ", "B. Networking ", "C. Mentoring", "D. Counseling"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Networking. Networking involves communicating with all of the people an individual knows who might be able to help with career opportunities. Research indicates that more people get jobs and advance in their careers through networking than through any other way of finding employment. Individuals who network regularly often are able to obtain the positions they want and move up the career ladder. Counseling is an oral communication method in which a supervisor and an employee discuss the employee's problem, and the supervisor tries to motivate the employee to find a solution. Interviewing involves meeting with a prospective employer in the anticipation of being offered a position. Mentoring involves an experienced worker acting as a guide to new employees. SOURCE: PD:037 SOURCE: Wallace, H.R., & Masters, L.A. (2006). Personal development for life & work (9th ed.) [p. 419]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29  "}, {"number": 92, "question": "Which of the following jobs involves determining the value of property: ", "choices": ["A. Real estate appraiser ", "B. Underwriter ", "C. Real estate agent", "D. Actuary"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Real estate appraiser. A real estate appraiser determines the value of a specific property. A real estate agent or broker assists buyers and sellers in the process of purchasing or selling property. An underwriter works in the insurance industry and calculates the risk of loss, establishes premium rates, and designs policies to cover risk. An actuary assesses risk using statistical analysis. SOURCE: PD:152 SOURCE: QS LAP 51\u2014Careers in the Money (Careers in Financial Services)  "}, {"number": 93, "question": "If you wanted to pursue a career that specializes in helping corporations and governments issue securities, you would work in ", "choices": ["A. a brokerage house. ", "B. a stock exchange. ", "C. investment banking.", "D. financial planning."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Investment banking. Investment banks trade securities, help businesses and governments issue securities, and handle the financial side of mergers and acquisitions. Financial planners help individuals make financial and investment decisions. They may also buy and sell certain financial products, such as securities, retirement plans, and insurance policies. A brokerage house is the most common type of firm that specializes in trading securities for clients. A stock exchange is where security trading is conducted by professional stockbrokers. SOURCE: PD:152 SOURCE: QS LAP 51\u2014Careers in the Money  "}, {"number": 94, "question": "A primary aspect of Bridget's job is to evaluate her company's internal financial information and the external factors that affect the company's financial well-being. Bridget synthesizes her findings and makes financial recommendations to the company's officers. Which of the following certifications is Bridget most likely to have: ", "choices": ["A. Chartered Life Underwriter (CLU) ", "B. Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) ", "C. Certified Loan Officer (CLO)", "D. Certified Annuity Specialist (CAS)"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA). Finance professionals can enhance their professional standing and career-advancement opportunities by obtaining various certifications and licensures. The CFA certification is a comprehensive certification that requires participants to pass three levels of exams. The CFA certification is beneficial to finance professionals who focus on the long-range financial well-being of businesses and organizations. Insurance underwriters obtain the Chartered Life Underwriter (CLU) certification. Loan officers obtain a CLO certification. Finance professionals who specialize in annuities obtain the Certified Annuity Specialist (CAS) certification. SOURCE: PD:082 SOURCE: Kolakowski, M. (n.d.). CFA: Chartered Financial Analyst. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://financecareers.about.com/od/cfa/a/cfa.htm  "}, {"number": 95, "question": "Which of the following provides an opportunity for building professional, finance-oriented relationships: ", "choices": ["A. Market segmentation ", "B. Product development ", "C. Brainstorming", "D. Networking"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Networking. Networking is the exchange of information with others for the purpose of professional or business development or advancement. Because the financial-services marketplace is very competitive, financial-services professionals and businesses need to communicate with other individuals and businesses to build clientele and promote their products. By participating in groups and speaking with other professionals, financial-services professionals can build new business relationships, obtain referrals, and acquire leads to increase clientele. Product development is the process of creating new goods and services. Brainstorming is a creative-thinking technique. Market segmentation is dividing a large market into small markets. SOURCE: PD:153 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Entering the world of work (p. 186). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 96, "question": "How do ethics relate to risk management? ", "choices": ["A. Risk management is insurance for lapses in business ethics.", "B. Risk management is all about the ethical treatment of customers.", "C. The best form of risk management is adherence to business ethics.", "D. The best form of business ethics is risk management."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "The best form of risk management is adherence to business ethics. Every breach of business ethics represents a potential risk for businesses. The best thing businesses can do to overcome most risks is to do the right thing\u2014practice business ethics. Risk management includes the ethical treatment of customers as well as a variety of other factors. Insurance is one way to overcome business risks; however, risk management is much more than insurance. SOURCE: RM:041 SOURCE: Lawrence, M. (n.d.). Business ethics as risk management. Retrieved November 14, 2011, from http://www.allbusiness.com/finance/insurance-risk-management/577644-1.html SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 30  "}, {"number": 97, "question": "Which of the following is a method that businesses use to reduce the risk of unauthorized access to confidential computer data: ", "choices": ["A. Groupware applications ", "B. Decryption software ", "C. Passwords", "D. Spooling"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Passwords. Businesses must take precautions to secure their confidential information. To reduce the risk of unauthorized access to confidential information, businesses often assign computer passwords to allow authorized employees to view secured information. This reduces the risk of confidential information getting into the wrong hands. Encryption, rather than decryption, is a way to protect information. Encryption is the process of transforming information into a secret code so that unauthorized users are not able to read it. Groupware applications are software programs that allow several computer users to access the same information from different locations. Spooling is the process of transferring computer data to a temporary location so the data can be retrieved and processed through a different computer program. SOURCE: RM:042 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 358-359). South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 98, "question": "Which of the following is a risk associated with management's failure to follow business regulations: ", "choices": ["A. Effective reporting methods ", "B. Lower insurance premiums ", "C. Expected customer-satisfaction levels", "D. Financial losses in relation to lawsuits"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Financial losses in relation to lawsuits. Risk management is a business activity that involves the planning, controlling, preventing, and procedures to limit business losses. An important aspect of risk management involves complying with laws. If a business does not comply with laws, then it may face a lawsuit. If the business loses the lawsuit, it may be required to pay money to the plaintiff. For example, if an employee is severely injured on the job, s/he might decide to file a lawsuit against the business for negligent behavior. If the court finds that the business acted negligently because it didn't follow safety regulations, then the business may be required to pay the employee, which is costly to the business. Acquiring insurance that offers lower premiums saves the business money and is not always related to business regulations. Customer-satisfaction levels are not always related to the business's compliance issues. Businesses that develop and implement effective reporting methods can minimize their risk in relation to compliance. SOURCE: RM:043 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., Thill, J. V., & Mescon, M.H. (2007). Excellence in business (3rd ed.) [pp. 524-526, A-13]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall.  "}, {"number": 99, "question": "What can businesses do to reduce risks associated with noncompliance? ", "choices": ["A. Allocate operating funds ", "B. Evaluate competitors ", "C. Obtain customer feedback", "D. Monitor regulations"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Monitor regulations. Risk management is a business activity that involves the planning, controlling, preventing, and procedures to limit business losses. If a business does not comply with laws, the government may fine the business, which could result in substantial financial losses. Therefore, it is important for a business to continuously monitor government regulations to ensure that it is in compliance, and make changes, if necessary, to become compliant. Evaluating competitors, obtaining customer feedback and allocating operating funds are not actions that will reduce risks associated with noncompliance. SOURCE: RM:043 SOURCE: BankersOnline.com. (n.d.). Compliance risk. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://www.bankersonline.com/tools/riskmgt_compliancerisk.doc  "}, {"number": 100, "question": "Why is the choice of a risk measure for internal and external risk of great practical importance? ", "choices": ["A. It determines the minimum reserve requirements in financial trading.", "B. It determines the maximum number of clients that can be served effectively by a financial\ninstitution.", "C. It identifies the types of risks that the financial institution will encounter.", "D. It designates the audience that will receive the resulting financial reports."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "It determines the minimum reserve requirements in financial trading. Different measures can result in a lower or higher minimum reserve requirement, which results in a lower or higher profit for the financial institution. Although it does not designate the audience that will receive the resulting financial reports, some financial measures should be used for internal purposes while other measures are more appropriate for external audiences. The number of clients to serve and the types of risks to be encountered are not aspects of selecting a risk measure. SOURCE: RM:058 SOURCE: Eling, M. & Tibiletti, L. (2008, August 20). Internal vs. external risk measures: How capital requirements differ in practice. Retrieved September 11, 2013, from http://web.econ.unito.it/tibiletti/docs/TCM-TCE%202008-08-20.pd"}], "2015-FIN-CORE": [{"number": 1, "question": "Business A's failure to keep an agreement to supply Business B with a certain good or service is an example of a situation that is covered by __________ law. ", "choices": ["A. trade", "B. antitrust", "C. contract", "D. property"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Contract. A contract is an agreement between two or more businesses stating that one party is to do something in return for something provided by the other party. Contract law recognizes contracts as voluntary promises that must be fulfilled. If Business A fails to honor its agreement to supply Business B with a good or service, Business A is in breach of contract. This is a situation that is covered by contract law, and Business B would be able to appeal to the legal system to enforce the contract. Trade law deals with transactions between nations. Antitrust laws deal with restraint of trade. Property law deals with real property. SOURCE: BL:001 SOURCE: Miller, R.L., & Jentz, G.A. (2008). Fundamentals of business law (6th ed.) [p. 274]. Mason, OH: Thomson/South-Western.  "}, {"number": 2, "question": "A debtor-creditor relationship exists when ", "choices": ["A. interest is charged.", "B. a sale is paid in full.", "C. a contract is invalidated.", "D. stocks are liquidated."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Interest is charged. When an individual or business charges interest on money that another individual or business borrows, a debtor-creditor relationship exists. An invalid contract and a sale that is paid in full at the time of transaction do not establish a debtor-creditor relationship. In some situations, a debtor may liquidate stocks to pay a creditor; however, this does not always occur. SOURCE: BL:071 SOURCE: Encyclopedia Britannica. (2014). Debtor and creditor. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/1362624/debtor-and-creditor  "}, {"number": 3, "question": "Walt purchased stock based on false information from an online message board. The scammers who posted the information had purchased the stock and hyped it up on the Internet to encourage unsuspecting investors to buy it and drive up its price. After the price went up, the scammers sold off their stock. The price of the stock then fell, leaving Walt with worthless stock. Walt was the victim of ", "choices": ["A. pump and dump.", "B. a pyramid scheme.", "C. affinity fraud.", "D. phishing."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Pump and dump. Pump and dump is an investment scam that takes place mostly online. Scammers buy a small stock and then hype it up to other investors, causing its price to rise. When the price is high, the scammers sell their stock, leaving the victims to deal with the rapid price decline afterwards. A pyramid scheme is an illegal form of multi-level marketing in which emphasis is placed on collecting initial fees from as many people as possible. Affinity fraud is an investment scam in which the scammer claims to be a member of the group s/he is targeting. Affinity fraud often takes the form of a Ponzi or pyramid scheme. Phishing is an online identity-theft scam that fools its victims into believing they are submitting sensitive, personal information (such as credit card numbers or bank passwords) to a legitimate website. SOURCE: BL:133 SOURCE: QS LAP 50\u2014Play By the Rules  "}, {"number": 4, "question": "Last year, Mr. McKinney gave a portion of his wages to a local charity and was not required to pay taxes on the amount of his donation. This is an example of a(n) ", "choices": ["A. estate allocation.", "B. tax deduction.", "C. tax-deferred investment.", "D. investment disbursement."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Tax deduction. The government does not require individuals and businesses to pay tax on income under certain circumstances, such as charitable contributions. Estate allocation involves dividing or designating a person's assets among his/her beneficiaries. Tax-deferred investments are financial products that are taxed at the time of disbursement. SOURCE: BL:134 SOURCE: Perez, W. (n.d.). Tax deductions for charity donations. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://taxes.about.com/od/deductionscredits/a/CharityDonation.htm  "}, {"number": 5, "question": "After finding several inconsistencies with its financial data, the MSV Company hired a compliance officer to monitor its financial processes and to ensure that the company is complying with regulations. What type of internal control has the business implemented? ", "choices": ["A. Product", "B. Preventative", "C. Corrective", "D. Conditional"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Corrective. Corrective controls are initiatives taken to fix a problem that has already been detected. Hiring a compliance officer to monitor financial processes is a corrective action because someone had already detected data inconsistencies. Preventative controls involve actions to keep something from happening before it occurs. Product controls are activities the business uses to manage the processes, quality, and quantity of goods and services. Conditional controls allow certain actions to occur within a specific set of circumstances. SOURCE: CC:003 SOURCE: Internal controls: Notes 2. (n.d.). Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://intraweb.stockton.edu/eyos/internal_audit/content/docs/icnote2.pdf  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15  "}, {"number": 6, "question": "To be most effective, continuous-inspection compliance technology should have access to transactional information ", "choices": ["A. at its source.", "B. biweekly.", "C. samples.", "D. liquidity ratios."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "At its source. To prevent an intermediary from tampering with transactional data, continuous-inspection compliance technology such as a virtual auditor must have access to the information at its source. Because continuous-inspection technology works continually to identify errors and violations, it needs access to transactional information as the transactions actually occur, not biweekly. Rather than reviewing samples of transactional information to verify compliance, the technology must have access to all transactional data. Liquidity ratios are not relevant to a conversation about continuous-inspection compliance technology. SOURCE: CC:004 SOURCE: Marks, N. (2010, March 8). The difference between continuous controls monitoring and the continuous inspection of transactions. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://normanmarks.wordpress.com/2010/03/08/the-difference-between-continuous-controlsmonitoring-and-the-continuous-inspection-of-transactions/  "}, {"number": 7, "question": "Tyrone is writing a research paper for his business class. What question should Tyrone ask as he looks for valid sources? ", "choices": ["A. Do I agree with the viewpoint of this author?", "B. Is this material interesting and easy to read?", "C. Does this source provide relevant graphic aids?", "D. Is the information in this source up to date?"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Is the information in this source up to date? It's important for Tyrone to find information that's recent. This isn't always important, but in a field like business, an article from 20 years ago probably won't be very beneficial. Although it's certainly helpful if the information is interesting and easy to read, it's not necessary. Likewise, relevant graphic aids might be nice, but Tyrone should be more concerned with the information he finds in the source. Tyrone should be looking for information that's factually correct; he shouldn't let his personal biases affect which sources he includes. SOURCE: CO:054 SOURCE: Long Island University. (n.d.). Library workshop manual: Section 4-evaluating information. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www2.liu.edu/cwis/cwp/library/workbook/evaluate.htm  "}, {"number": 8, "question": "Theresa's supervisor gives her written directions for an assignment. Theresa carefully completes the task as the directions specify. As she finishes the last step, she realizes that her work in step two may not be exactly right. What should she do? ", "choices": ["A. Ask her supervisor to clarify the directions", "B. Turn in her work quickly so her supervisor can identify the needed corrections", "C. Restart the assignment working off her new thought for step two", "D. Email her work to three coworkers to get their opinions"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Ask her supervisor to clarify the directions. If there is any concern about the assignment directions, Theresa needs to clear those up by speaking to her supervisor. Even though talking with her supervisor may delay the completion of the project, it is better to finish the assignment correctly than turn in work that doesn't meet the supervisor's intent. Theresa should submit accurate work and not expect her supervisor to fix mistakes. Restarting the assignment without clarifying the directions may lead to work that doesn't meet the supervisor's intent. Instead of emailing coworkers, Theresa needs to get clarification from the person who wrote the directions. Any input the coworkers give is simply their opinions. SOURCE: CO:056 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (p. 175). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 9, "question": "Jack says to Wendi, \u201cIf I understand you correctly, you are saying that you want to change the format of the inventory report so it will be easier for the managers to analyze.\u201d What communication technique is Jack using to clarify Wendi's suggestion? ", "choices": ["A. Passive listening", "B. Expressing an opinion", "C. Paraphrasing", "D. Quoting"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Paraphrasing. Message recipients use many techniques to encourage and indicate their understanding of a speaker's message. In the example, Jack is paraphrasing to verify his understanding of Wendi's statement. Paraphrasing involves restating a message in other words to confirm the message recipient's understanding. To use paraphrasing effectively, the message recipient must actively listen to the speaker's message. Paraphrasing does not involve expressing an opinion. Quoting involves reciting or writing a thought, idea, or statement using the speaker's exact words. SOURCE: CO:082 SOURCE: Mind Tools. (1996-2014). Active listening. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.mindtools.com/CommSkll/ActiveListening.htm  "}, {"number": 10, "question": "What is the purpose of developing and using graphics in business reports? ", "choices": ["A. To communicate information", "B. To entertain the audience", "C. To fill up the page layout", "D. To highlight reference material"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "To communicate information. The purpose of developing and using graphics in business reports is to communicate information. In most cases, graphics are used to explain complex information or to highlight information that is of the most importance. The use of graphics often adds interest and makes the information easier to understand. Graphics are not used to entertain the audience, fill up the page layout, or highlight reference material. SOURCE: CO:087 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 362]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall.  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16  "}, {"number": 11, "question": "Which of the following is a formatting characteristic of a full-block business letter: ", "choices": ["A. Indented first paragraph", "B. Double-spacing within the paragraph", "C. No paragraph indents", "D. All paragraphs use right justification."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "No paragraph indents. Many businesses use the full-block method to format business letters. All components of the letter (date, address, greeting, body, closing, signature block) use left justification, which means all text is aligned on the left side of the margin. Writers using the full-block format do not indent the first sentence of each paragraph. Other formatting characteristics of full-block letters are the use of single-spacing within the paragraphs and the use of double-spacing between the paragraphs. SOURCE: CO:088 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. A-11]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall.  "}, {"number": 12, "question": "Which of the following is an example of persuasive messages that businesses write: ", "choices": ["A. Electronic mail", "B. Collection letter", "C. Handwritten note", "D. Interoffice memo"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Collection letter. A collection letter is a type of persuasive message that many businesses write to customers who are delinquent in making payments on their accounts. The purpose of the collection letter is to persuade customers to send payment or to contact the business to make some type of arrangement. Collection letters should not offend customers but should convince them to respond immediately. Many businesses write electronic mail, handwritten notes, and interoffice memos, but these types of messages are not necessarily persuasive. SOURCE: CO:031 SOURCE: Hyden, J.S., Jordan, A.K., Steinauer, M.H., & Jones, M.J. (2006). Communicating for success (3rd ed.) [pp. 306-307]. Mason, OH: Thomson South-Western.  "}, {"number": 13, "question": "A characteristic of a simple written report is that it usually is ", "choices": ["A. abstract.", "B. formal.", "C. short.", "D. detailed."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Short. A characteristic of a simple written report is that it usually is short and to the point. The purpose of writing simple reports is to present basic information in an abbreviated form so that the recipients can read it quickly and use the information in their decision making. Simple written reports are informal rather than formal. They should address the issue in simple terms rather than present abstract information. Simple written reports provide the basic points rather than detailed information. SOURCE: CO:094 SOURCE: Lehman, C., & DuFrene, D. (2011). Business communication (16th ed.) [p. 394]. Mason, OH: South-Western.  "}, {"number": 14, "question": "Three types of communication usually found in a business with a formal communication network are ", "choices": ["A. informational, official, and conversational.", "B. grapevine, informal, and standard.", "C. upward, horizontal, and diagonal.", "D. downward, upward, and lateral."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Downward, upward, and lateral. Communication in a business with a formal staff communication system usually moves in three directions\u2014up, down, and sideways. Upward communication is from employees to management, downward communication is from management to employees, and lateral is communication between staff members on the same level. Grapevine communication is unofficial information passed from one person to another in writing or through conversation. An informal communication system usually has an active grapevine. The other alternatives are not types of communication. SOURCE: CO:014 SOURCE: Lehman, C., & DuFrene, D. (2011). Business communication (16th ed.) [pp. 11-14]. Mason, OH: South-Western.  "}, {"number": 15, "question": "Which of the following is most likely to happen to employees who are discourteous to the business's customers: ", "choices": ["A. They may be promoted.", "B. They may be fired.", "C. They may win an award.", "D. They may lose their benefits."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "They may be fired. More people lose their jobs because they can't get along with other people than for any other reason. Establishing positive customer/client relations is very important to a business's success. Employees who damage customer relations are not likely to be promoted or given awards. Benefits cannot be taken away for misconduct. SOURCE: CR:003 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed.) [pp. 96, 120-121]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17  "}, {"number": 16, "question": "Businesses benefit when employees handle customer inquiries in an effective manner because ", "choices": ["A. customers feel the need to ask more questions.", "B. customers feel free to return products.", "C. customers' confidence in the business increases.", "D. customers' total purchases are reduced."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Customers' confidence in the business increases. Customers' confidence in a business grows when the business provides accurate answers to their product questions. They feel the sales staff are knowledgeable, which also gives customers more confidence in the products they buy. Customers are less likely to need to return products when their questions about those products have been answered, and their total purchases are more likely to increase than decrease. Customers may need to ask fewer questions when their inquiries are handled in an effective manner. SOURCE: CR:006 SOURCE: Clark, B., Basteri, C.G., Gassen, C., & Walker, M. (2014). Marketing dynamics (3rd ed.) [pp. 548-550]. Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Co.  "}, {"number": 17, "question": "What should help businesspeople adapt their communication styles to appeal to clients from other cultures? ", "choices": ["A. Being patient, flexible, and empathetic", "B. Being confident, biased, and manipulative", "C. Being sensitive, transparent, and demanding", "D. Being respectful, indifferent, and honest"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Being patient, flexible and empathetic. So that businesspeople don't do something that will offend their clients, they should adapt their communication styles with clients from different cultures. To develop positive relationships with international clients, businesspeople should try to learn as much as they can about their clients' cultures, customs, and social values. Adapting communication styles requires businesspeople to be patient, flexible, empathetic, respectful, confident (but not overly so), honest (transparent), and sensitive to their clients' cultures and customs. Projecting biased, demanding, manipulative, or indifferent attitudes may offend the clients. SOURCE: CR:019 SOURCE: Buckler, C., & Moore, K. (n.d.). Module 3: Cross-cultural communication. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://pdfcast.org/pdf/module-3-cross-cultural-communication  "}, {"number": 18, "question": "When providing services to clients, financial professionals have the responsibility to supply ", "choices": ["A. payment options.", "B. accurate information.", "C. credit counseling.", "D. bank statements."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Accurate information. Financial professionals often invest money for clients. As a result, they should provide clients with accurate information about the performance of possible investments. Some investments are more secure than others. Those clients who do not want to take risks should know which investment options are the safest. Financial professionals have this information and should supply it to clients. Financial professionals do not necessarily offer payment options. Not all financial professionals supply credit counseling. Financial professionals usually do not supply clients with bank statements. SOURCE: CR:012 SOURCE: CFP Board. (2014). Code of ethics & professional responsibility. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.cfp.net/for-cfp-professionals/professional-standards-enforcement/standardsof-professional-conduct/code-of-ethics-professional-responsibility  "}, {"number": 19, "question": "Customer Relationship Management (CRM) data are sometimes called \u201cperishable\u201d data because the data ", "choices": ["A. may be non-standardized or unformatted.", "B. are often duplicated.", "C. can become inaccurate over time.", "D. often contain junk or garbage."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Can become inaccurate over time. Customer Relationship Management (CRM) data are often referred to as \u201cperishable\u201d data because while the data are true at the time they are recorded, the data are likely to become inaccurate over time. For example, someone's address or phone number may change as the result of a move. CRM data are sometimes duplicated, non-standardized, unformatted, junk, or garbage, but those characteristics alone do not make them perishable. SOURCE: CR:024 SOURCE: ReadyContacts. (n.d.). CRM data cleansing & enrichment\u2014Data management best practices. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.readycontacts.com/crm-datacleansing-enrichment-data-management-best-practices/#  "}, {"number": 20, "question": "Which of the following statements about economic resources is true: ", "choices": ["A. All economic resources are limited.", "B. All natural resources can be replaced.", "C. Economic resources are considered consumer goods.", "D. Economic resources are the outputs of production."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "All economic resources are limited. Economic resources are items that can be used to produce goods and services, and they are in limited supply. The categories of economic resources are natural resources, human resources, and capital goods. Some natural resources, such as forests, can be replaced, but others, such as oil or coal, cannot. Consumer goods are products that are purchased and consumed by their ultimate users. Economic resources are the inputs of production. SOURCE: EC:003 SOURCE: EC LAP 14\u2014Be Resourceful (Economic Resources)  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18  "}, {"number": 21, "question": "Which of the following factors affecting the business environment is represented by the business's location: ", "choices": ["A. Cultural", "B. Environmental", "C. Economic", "D. Political"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Environmental. Access to raw materials, availability of natural resources, amount of pollution, and a business's location are examples of environmental factors affecting the business environment. Cultural factors involve customers' values, preferences, beliefs, etc. Economic factors relate to how people generate revenue to obtain desired goods and services. Government stability and laws are political factors that operate in the business environment. SOURCE: EC:105 SOURCE: EC LAP 26\u2014What's Shakin'? (Factors Affecting Business Environment)  "}, {"number": 22, "question": "In a market economy what consumers want and need helps to answer the basic economic question of ", "choices": ["A. how products will be produced.", "B. who will do the production.", "C. what products will be produced.", "D. how products will be allocated."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "What products will be produced. Some of the factors that affect the decision as to what will be produced include which items are profitable, what consumers want and need, and what resources are available. Who will do the production and how products will be produced are not basic economic questions. How products will be allocated depends upon the type of economic system. SOURCE: EC:007 SOURCE: EC LAP 17\u2014Who's the Boss? (Economic Systems)  "}, {"number": 23, "question": "What exists when a market is legally controlled by one supplier and there are no substitute goods/services readily available? ", "choices": ["A. Price discrimination", "B. Regulated monopoly", "C. Price competition", "D. Nonprice competition"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Regulated monopoly. These companies are allowed to exist when legislators believe that one large company can more efficiently serve consumers than several small ones. Price discrimination is an illegal activity in which a business charges customers different prices for similar products. Price competition occurs when businesses use prices to attract scarce customer dollars. Nonprice competition occurs when businesses compete on a basis other than price. SOURCE: EC:012 SOURCE: EC LAP 8\u2014Ready, Set, Compete! (Competition)  "}, {"number": 24, "question": "What type of tax are businesses required to pay on the profits they earn? ", "choices": ["A. Sales", "B. Excise", "C. Income", "D. Property"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Income. Income tax is a tax on profit. When businesses earn a profit from supplying goods and services to consumers, they pay a certain percentage of that profit to the government. The tax that businesses pay on the profits they earn is not an example of excise or sales tax. Property tax is a tax on material goods rather than on profit. SOURCE: EC:072 SOURCE: EC LAP 27\u2014Pay Your Share (Business Taxes)  "}, {"number": 25, "question": "What usually decreases as the rate of inflation increases? ", "choices": ["A. Interest rates", "B. Purchasing power", "C. Export quotas", "D. Money supply"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Purchasing power. Purchasing power is a consumer's ability to purchase goods and services. The rate of inflation, the percentage of change in price levels, has a major effect on purchasing power because when inflation is high, a dollar will not buy as much. For example, if the rate of inflation increases from last year to this year, $1.00 will buy less this year than it did last year. If inflation increases and incomes stay the same, people will lose purchasing power and not be able to buy the same amount of goods and services. Money supply is the total quantity of money that exists at one time in a nation. The interest rate is the percentage figure used in calculating interest charges. Export quotas are the restrictions on the quantity of goods that can move out of a country. SOURCE: EC:083 SOURCE: EC LAP 28\u2014Up, Up, and Away (Inflation)  "}, {"number": 26, "question": "Which of the following is an internal factor that has an effect on business cycles: ", "choices": ["A. Inventory levels", "B. Political changes", "C. New discoveries", "D. Foreign conflicts"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Inventory levels. Some factors that affect business cycles are considered internal because they take place within the economic system itself. One internal factor is inventory levels because major changes in inventory levels can create changes in business cycles. When producers are optimistic about business activity, they increase their inventory levels in order to be prepared for the increase in demand. This action expands economic activities. However, if producers are concerned that consumers will not buy the goods in inventory, they cut back on production. This action causes the economy to contract. Political changes, new discoveries, and foreign conflicts are considered external factors because they take place outside the economic system. SOURCE: EC:018 SOURCE: EC LAP 9\u2014Boom or Bust (Impact of Business Cycles)  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19  "}, {"number": 27, "question": "The French-Canadian culture relies heavily on nonverbal communication to get messages across. This means it is a(n) ", "choices": ["A. ethnocentric culture.", "B. religious culture.", "C. corrupt culture.", "D. high-context culture."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "High-context culture. Since the French-Canadian culture relies heavily on nonverbal communication to get messages across, it is a high-context culture. A low-context culture is one in which people speak more directly. Relying on nonverbal communication does not make a culture more religious, more corrupt, or more ethnocentric (believing their culture is superior). SOURCE: EC:045 SOURCE: EC LAP 24\u2014On Top of the World (Impact of Culture on Global Trade)  "}, {"number": 28, "question": "John is generally a good worker, except that he lacks the ability to see what needs to be done without being told. What personal trait is John lacking? ", "choices": ["A. Empathy", "B. Honesty", "C. Initiative", "D. Creativity"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Initiative. Initiative is willingness to act without having to be told to do so and sometimes includes willingness to accept/seek additional or unpleasant duties. A person with initiative is ready, willing, and able to think and act on his/her own. Creativity is the ability to generate unique ideas, approaches, and solutions. Empathy is the ability to put oneself in another person's place. Honesty is acting in a truthful, fair manner. SOURCE: EI:024 SOURCE: EI LAP 2\u2014Hustle! (Taking Initiative at Work)  "}, {"number": 29, "question": "Employees who never discuss confidential or personal business information with other employees are demonstrating their ", "choices": ["A. ability to communicate.", "B. honesty and integrity.", "C. intelligence and initiative.", "D. orderly and systematic behavior."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Honesty and integrity. Employees demonstrate their honesty and integrity when they refuse to violate the trust a company places in them. Many employees have access to some confidential information and should discuss it only as dictated by company policy. Intelligence is the individual's ability to learn, and initiative is the willingness to act without having to be told to do so. Orderly and systematic behavior results from being organized and following a plan. Communicating involves exchanging information. SOURCE: EI:022 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 236). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 30, "question": "In order to benefit from criticism, you must take an objective look at it and decide how much of it is ", "choices": ["A. too difficult to worry about.", "B. short term versus long term.", "C. from someone you dislike.", "D. valid and based on fact."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Valid and based on fact. In order to benefit from criticism, you must take an objective look at it and decide how much of it is valid and based on fact. If it is relevant feedback and points out areas that truly need improvement, work on them. It is not necessary to determine how much of the criticism is short term or long term. In order to benefit from criticism, you need to look past the person who gave you the criticism to the validity of the criticism itself. It is possible to receive valid criticism from someone whom you don't like. If the criticism is difficult to understand, ask your supervisor, coworkers, or others around you for specific suggestions on what to do or how to change. SOURCE: EI:003 SOURCE: EI LAP 15\u2014Grin and Bear It (Using Feedback for Personal Growth)  "}, {"number": 31, "question": "Which of the following is a way to demonstrate empathy: ", "choices": ["A. Give advice to people in need.", "B. Develop a good imagination.", "C. Use tact when speaking.", "D. Ignore a coworker who is different."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Use tact when speaking. Tact is the ability to do or to say the right thing in any circumstance. Empathy is the ability to put yourself in another person's place. Using tact is one way to demonstrate empathy. Developing a good imagination is a way to develop empathy. Empathetic individuals refrain from criticizing or giving advice. Ignoring a coworker because s/he is different is prejudicial. Empathetic people are not prejudiced. SOURCE: EI:030 SOURCE: EI LAP 12\u2014Have a Heart (Showing Empathy for Others)  "}, {"number": 32, "question": "Melanie dressed for her job interview at a local bank in a pair of old, comfortable jeans, a sweatshirt, and well-worn Nikes. Which of the following messages is Melanie sending to the interviewer through her choice of clothes: ", "choices": ["A. I care a lot about the outcome of this interview.", "B. I would really like to be hired for this job.", "C. I consider my own comfort my first priority.", "D. I'm someone who will support the image of the bank."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "I consider my own comfort my first priority. The clothing that people choose to wear sends a message to other people and is considered a form of nonverbal communication, or body language. An individual who does not dress appropriately for a job interview is sending a clear message that s/he did not consider the interview important. In this situation, Melanie dressed for her own comfort, rather than dressing in a professional manner. The interviewer is likely to interpret Melanie's nonverbal message to be that she would not like to be hired for the job, does not care about the outcome of the interview, and would not support the bank's image. SOURCE: EI:007 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (p. 134). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20  "}, {"number": 33, "question": "What is one factor that determines a manager's credibility with employees? ", "choices": ["A. Reputation", "B. Creativity", "C. Patience", "D. Aptitude"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Reputation. A manager who has the reputation of being knowledgeable and experienced usually has credibility with employees. Credibility is believability, and employees are more likely to believe a manager who has the appropriate background and ability. Managers who have a reputation of being unethical or poorly informed often have difficulty persuading employees because the managers lack credibility. Aptitudes are natural talents for learning specific skills. Creativity is the ability to generate unique ideas, approaches, or solutions. Patience is the ability to endure life's aggravations and difficulties calmly. SOURCE: EI:012 SOURCE: Hyden, J.S., Jordan, A.K., & Steinauer, M.H. (2006). Communicating for success (3rd ed.) [p. 326]. Mason, OH: Thomson South-Western.  "}, {"number": 34, "question": "Which of the following statements is true about determining your personal vision for the future: ", "choices": ["A. It involves following a step-by-step plan.", "B. It depends more on emotion than logic.", "C. It requires facts and concrete goals.", "D. It is risk free and time bound."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "It depends more on emotion than logic. A vision is the future you wish to create. Often, a vision begins with an abstract idea that is based on emotion rather than logic. Because a vision is abstract (indefinite), you must have or develop the tolerance for dealing with abstract terms and ideas rather than facts. For this reason, a step-by-step plan does not always work when a person is working toward a vision for the future. Working toward and achieving a vision requires the willingness to take risks over a long period of time. SOURCE: EI:063 SOURCE: QS LAP 11\u2014Picture This!  "}, {"number": 35, "question": "When making a plan for improvement, the coachee's job is to ", "choices": ["A. give constructive criticism.", "B. use questioning skills.", "C. provide motivation.", "D. take personal responsibility for making the changes."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Take personal responsibility for making the changes. When making a plan for improvement, the coachee's job is to take personal responsibility for making the changes. Nothing you say or do to motivate the coachee will be effective if s/he hasn't taken ownership of the need to improve. It's the job of the coach to use questioning skills, provide motivation, and give constructive criticism. SOURCE: EI:041 SOURCE: EI LAP 24\u2014Bring Out the Best (Coaching Others)  "}, {"number": 36, "question": "Why are there no specific rules for workers to follow in treating others fairly? ", "choices": ["A. Businesses object to having rules.", "B. Every workplace is different.", "C. Workers know how to be fair.", "D. Rules are difficult to remember."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Every workplace is different. There are no hard-and-fast rules for treating coworkers with fairness and respect because every workplace is different, and each group of workers is different. Businesses would not object to having fairness rules, but since this is not feasible, they often set policies for employees to follow. Fairness rules would not necessarily be difficult to remember. Workers need training or policies to follow since most people do not automatically know how to be fair. SOURCE: EI:036 SOURCE: EI LAP 20\u2014Fair and Square (Treat Others Fairly at Work)  "}, {"number": 37, "question": "When Matthew receives a check four times a year for income he has earned on his stock investments, he is receiving ", "choices": ["A. deposits.", "B. credit.", "C. dividends.", "D. cash."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Dividends. A dividend is a sum of money that a corporation pays to a stockholder as earnings on an investment. The corporation usually pays dividends by check to stockholders on a quarterly basis. The stockholder can deposit the dividend check into a savings or checking account or convert it to cash. Credit, deposits, and cash are not forms of income that are earned by owning stock. SOURCE: FI:061 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 212). South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 38, "question": "Choosing to buy an item at the check-out counter is often an example of ", "choices": ["A. smart shopping.", "B. poor use of credit.", "C. financial self-control.", "D. impulsive spending."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Impulsive spending. Choosing to buy an item at the check-out counter is a classic example of impulsive spending. Poor use of credit may or may not be involved. Choosing not to buy the item would illustrate financial control and would be a good example of smart shopping. SOURCE: FI:065 SOURCE: QS LAP 31\u2014Set Yourself Up  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21  "}, {"number": 39, "question": "Which of the following is a financial want rather than a financial need: ", "choices": ["A. Food", "B. Education", "C. Clothing", "D. Shelter"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Education. Education is a financial want rather than a financial need. Financial needs are the basics that are necessary for survival. Food, clothing, and shelter are necessary for survival, but education isn't. SOURCE: FI:270 SOURCE: QS LAP 30\u2014Supersize Your Money  "}, {"number": 40, "question": "Melissa writes checks to pay for her rent, utilities, and groceries, and she keeps a record of all these transactions in her check register. Keeping an accurate check register helps Melissa ", "choices": ["A. determine when she needs to add funds to her savings account.", "B. track the amount of money she has spent.", "C. understand the checking account's restrictions and fees.", "D. decide when to order new checks."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Track the amount of money she has spent. A check is a negotiable instrument or bank draft made payable to a specific party for a specific amount of money. A check serves as a written promise to the check bearer that money is available in the issuer's bank account. Checks are a common form of financial exchange. Both individuals and businesses use checks to pay for goods and services such as rent, utilities, food, and supplies. When writing a check, an individual or business keeps a check register that records information about the transaction. This information includes the date the check is written, to whom the check is made payable, the amount of the check, and the check number. The register is a central location to record and track all of the checks written and the amount of money spent. Check registers do not help the check issuers determine when to add funds to a savings account, understand the checking account's restrictions and fees, or decide when to order new checks. SOURCE: FI:069 SOURCE: Kapoor, J.R., Dlabay, L.R., & Hughes, R.J. (2009). Personal finance (9th ed.) [p. 159]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin.  "}, {"number": 41, "question": "Why is it important for individuals to periodically validate their credit histories? ", "choices": ["A. To avoid being denied credit", "B. To understand credit laws", "C. To find out about different types of credit", "D. To protect themselves from slander"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "To avoid being denied credit. Individuals should periodically validate their credit histories to make sure that the information is correct. In some cases, inaccurate or false information may appear in a credit history, which will result in an individual being denied credit. To make sure this doesn't happen, individuals should review the information and contact the credit bureau to change or remove inaccurate information. Individuals do not validate their credit histories to understand credit laws, find out about different types of credit, or protect themselves from slander. SOURCE: FI:072 SOURCE: Kapoor, J.R., Dlabay, L.R., & Hughes, R.J. (2009). Personal finance (9th ed.) [pp. 182-184]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin.  "}, {"number": 42, "question": "Henry is a professional banker. Only certain people\u2014\"members\"\u2014may save at or borrow money from his deposit-taking financial institution. Henry most likely works for a(n) ", "choices": ["A. mortgage company.", "B. credit union.", "C. insurance company.", "D. CPA firm."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Credit union. Credit unions are essentially cooperatives providing financial products and services to a group of individuals who work for the same employer or share some other common interest or characteristic. Only members may save at or borrow from a credit union. Credit unions offer many different types of accounts, including interest-bearing checking accounts, also called share-draft accounts. Mortgage companies, insurance companies, and Certified Public Accounting (CPA) firms are not deposit-taking financial institutions. SOURCE: FI:336 SOURCE: Cady, D.F. (2008). 2008 Field guide to financial planning (p. 56). Erlanger, KY: The National Underwriter Company.  "}, {"number": 43, "question": "Thad is investing in a money market, which buys and sells products such as ", "choices": ["A. agricultural goods.", "B. shares of stock.", "C. treasury bills.", "D. technology."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Treasury bills. A financial market is an organized effort or exchange that facilitates the buying and selling of financial assets. There are many types of financial markets, including money markets. Money markets involve the buying and selling of short-term, low-risk financial products such as treasury bills, which are issued by the government. Stock, agricultural goods (soft commodities), and technology are often highrisk investments. SOURCE: FI:337 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2014). Money markets: Treasury bills. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.investopedia.com/university/moneymarket/moneymarket2.asp  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22  "}, {"number": 44, "question": "Which of the following is not a factor contributing to financial convergence and consolidation: ", "choices": ["A. Desire for illiquid assets", "B. Technological advances", "C. Financial deregulation", "D. Desire for lower costs"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Desire for illiquid assets. Liquid assets are financial assets such as stocks that can easily be converted into cash. Illiquid assets, therefore, are assets that cannot be easily converted into cash or sold without a significant drop in their value. Subprime mortgage assets, for example, became illiquid assets during the recent financial crisis. Financial firms don't merge because they want illiquid assets that are worth very little. Instead, financial convergence and consolidation may be driven by financial companies' desire to acquire more liquid capital. Technological advances, financial deregulation, and a desire for lower costs have also contributed to financial convergence and consolidation. SOURCE: FI:573 SOURCE: MBA Research and Curriculum Center. (2009). Introduction to finance course guide (pp. 5-106, 5-107). Columbus, Ohio: Author.  "}, {"number": 45, "question": "Under what circumstances would stock prices increase? ", "choices": ["A. When consumer spending increases", "B. During times of high unemployment", "C. When interest rates increase", "D. During a bear market period"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "When consumer spending increases. Increased consumer spending usually indicates that the economy is growing and unemployment is low. Because more people are working, they have more money to invest in the financial markets. Higher interest rates make it more expensive for businesses to obtain the funds they need to expand their operations and typically causes stock prices to decrease. A bear market exists when stock prices decrease, and a bull market exists when the stock prices increase. SOURCE: FI:574 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 220). South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 46, "question": "Certain health and safety regulations require many types of businesses to ", "choices": ["A. offer exercise programs.", "B. purchase new machinery.", "C. routinely inspect equipment.", "D. install security cameras."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Routinely inspect equipment. Some businesses operate equipment that may present a safety hazard if the equipment is not operating properly. As a result, certain health and safety regulations require these businesses to routinely inspect equipment to make sure it is safe. In some cases, government inspectors routinely visit the business to inspect equipment. If the inspectors find that the equipment is malfunctioning, they have the authority to force the business to stop using the equipment until it has been repaired and inspected again. Health and safety regulations do not require businesses to purchase new machinery, offer exercise programs, or install security cameras. SOURCE: OP:004 SOURCE: Canadian Centre for Occupational Health and Safety. (2009, March 1). Effective workplace inspections. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.ccohs.ca/oshanswers/prevention/effectiv.html  "}, {"number": 47, "question": "Financial globalization tends to cause an increase in ", "choices": ["A. taxes on international transactions.", "B. investors' exposure to business cycle risks.", "C. herd behavior among investors.", "D. limits on foreigners' access to domestic markets."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Herd behavior among investors. Although financial globalization tends to increase investors' access to many different financial markets, financial globalization also seems to increase the risks of speculative bubbles and herd behavior among investors. Herd behavior involves individuals who act together as a group without any planned direction. It is usually irrational and driven by emotions. In good times, investors hurry to join others in a buying frenzy. But, in bad financial times, fearful investors join others in a rush to get out of risky markets. By diversifying their funds in many different countries, investors are able to diversify their risk and reduce their exposure to business cycle risks. To enable capital to flow more freely across their national borders, many countries have lowered their taxes on international financial transactions. SOURCE: FI:575 SOURCE: MBA Research and Curriculum Center. (2009). Introduction to finance course guide (pp. 5-156-5-158). Columbus, OH: Author.  "}, {"number": 48, "question": "A mutual fund's total liabilities are $5,600,000, and its assets total $7,950,000. There are currently 31,000,000 shares outstanding. What is the net asset value of the fund? ", "choices": ["A. 7.58%", "B. 6.45%", "C. 7.29%", "D. 8.06%"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "7.58%. The net asset value of a mutual fund is the dollar value for one share of its stock. To find the net asset value, first subtract the total liabilities from the total assets to calculate the fund's total value ($7,950,000 - $5,600,000 = $2,350,000). Then, divide the fund's total value by the number of shares outstanding ($2,350,000 \u00f7 31,000,000 = 0.0758 = 7.58%). SOURCE: FI:274 SOURCE: Brechner, R. (2009). Contemporary mathematics for business and consumers: Annotated instructor's edition (5th ed.) [pp. 758-759]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23  "}, {"number": 49, "question": "According to today's stock quotation table, the current price of Macy's stock is $18.99 per share. Last year, the company paid investors a dividend of $0.20 per share. What is the current yield on Macy's stock? ", "choices": ["A. 3.80%", "B. 2.00%", "C. 1.05%", "D. 4.95%"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "1.05%. A stock's current yield is a measure of the amount of last year's dividend as a percentage of the stock's current price. To calculate the current yield on Macy's stock, divide last year's dividend per share by the current price per share ($0.20 \u00f7 $18.99 = 0.0105318 = 1.05%). SOURCE: FI:275 SOURCE: Brechner, R. (2009). Contemporary mathematics for business and consumers: Annotated instructor's edition (5th ed.) [pp. 737-740]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 50, "question": "A severe storm blows down trees that fall on a business and collapse the roof and break windows. This type of damage results from ___________ risks. ", "choices": ["A. financial", "B. human", "C. economic", "D. natural"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Natural. Natural risks are chances of loss that result from natural phenomena, such as a severe storm. Human risks are chances of loss caused by human weakness and unpredictability, such as dishonesty. Economic risks are risks caused by changes in the market that force a lowering of prices, a change of product, or failure of a business\u2014such as competition. Financial risks involve the money of the business\u2014the capital. Financial risks are the basic risk in marketing. SOURCE: FI:084 SOURCE: FI LAP 8\u2014Prepare for the Worst; Expect the Best (Nature of Risk Management)  "}, {"number": 51, "question": "When Alana prepares a report so that all of the financial data is clearly disclosed, she is ensuring that the information is ", "choices": ["A. flexible.", "B. relevant.", "C. timely.", "D. transparent."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Transparent. When financial information is fully disclosed and is presented in a clear, understandable way, it is transparent. Transparent information is not buried in a document or presented in a way that deliberately confuses the reader. Relevant information consists of data that are helpful to users of the information. Timely information is current or up to date. Flexible data are often used in or applicable to different situations. Alana's report may or may not contain flexible, relevant, or timely information. SOURCE: FI:579 SOURCE: FI LAP 9\u2014By the Numbers (The Need for Financial Information)  "}, {"number": 52, "question": "Calculate a business's total cash receipts for one month if it had cash sales of $6,500, credit sales of $2,450, cost of goods sold of $2,725, and total expenses of $1,980. ", "choices": ["A. $6,500", "B. $8,900", "C. $6,225", "D. $4,245"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "$6,500. Total cash receipts is the total of all of the sources of income that the business lists under cash receipts. Total cash receipts includes cash sales. Only collected money, not monies owed to the business from credit sales, is recorded under cash receipts. In this example, only cash sales of $6,500 is part of total cash receipts. Total cash paid out includes cost of goods sold and all other business expenses. SOURCE: FI:091 SOURCE: FI LAP 6\u2014Count the Cash (Cash Flow Statements)  "}, {"number": 53, "question": "Businesses use budgets to estimate how they will ", "choices": ["A. file their taxes.", "B. spend their money.", "C. calculate their assets.", "D. depreciate their assets."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Spend their money. A budget estimates how a business will earn and spend its money. Businesses use budgets to estimate how they will spend the money they earn as income. Businesses have expenses, and budgets help businesses plan how to allocate income in order to pay those expenses. Businesses do not use budgets to calculate their assets, file their taxes, or depreciate their assets. SOURCE: FI:106 SOURCE: FI LAP 3\u2014Money Tracks (Nature of Budgets)  "}, {"number": 54, "question": "A financial-information management system can help a financial manager to make which of the following types of decisions: ", "choices": ["A. Employee scheduling", "B. Capital budgeting", "C. Vendor selections", "D. Adding/dropping products"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Capital budgeting. A financial-information management system is a set of processes, people, and equipment used to gather, store, organize, and provide financial information to decision makers. A financial manager might use a financial-information management system to make capital budgeting decisions. Capital budgeting involves developing a plan to acquire and finance long-term business assets. Financial managers would not use a financial-information management system to schedule employees. Although a financial-information management system might be useful when selecting vendors or adding/dropping products, those decisions would not be made by financial managers. SOURCE: FM:002 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 341). South-Western Cengage Learning.  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24  "}, {"number": 55, "question": "By protecting financial information from tampering, loss, and unauthorized use, a financial-information management professional acts as a(n) __________ of that financial information. ", "choices": ["A. agent", "B. interpreter", "C. analyst", "D. steward"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Steward. Financial-information management's stewardship function involves protecting financial data from tampering, loss, unauthorized access, and unauthorized use. While a financial-information management professional's job responsibilities might include interpreting or analyzing financial data, those are not the functions that s/he is carrying out when protecting the financial information. An agent is an intermediary who assists in the sale and/or promotion of goods and services but does not take title to them. SOURCE: FM:003 SOURCE: Bloomfield, R. (2009, October 28). Stewardship, financial reporting, and investment. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.fasri.net/index.php/2009/10/stewardshipfinancial-reporting-and-investment/  "}, {"number": 56, "question": "An advantage to businesses that use master data management applications is the ___________ of the data. ", "choices": ["A. complexity", "B. variation", "C. replication", "D. consistency"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Consistency. Master data management involves the collection, storage, accessibility, and maintenance of the business's nontransactional data (e.g., product, employee). Effective master data management involves providing consistent, accurate data for all employees who use the data throughout the organization. An important aspect of master data management is ensuring that the organization uses one rather than several versions of a particular computer application. Effective master data management applications reduce the replication of data records. Master data management applications often handle complex data; however, if the complex data are not consistent, the data are not useful to the employees who use it. SOURCE: FM:011 SOURCE: Wolter, R., & Haselden, K. (2006, November). The what, why, and how of master data management. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://msdn.microsoft.com/enus/library/bb190163.aspx  "}, {"number": 57, "question": "A business wants to determine which customers are most likely to buy $100,000 in products from them in the next year, so it uses its computer system to search for customers who meet a set of criteria related to sales. What process is the business using to obtain the desired financial information? ", "choices": ["A. Accounting", "B. Data mining", "C. Surveying", "D. Industry forecasting"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Data mining. Data mining is the process of searching computer databases to look for patterns of information and correlations among information. Businesses use the information they obtain from data mining to make business decisions, such as analyzing and determining the customers who possess the highest buying potential. By having this type of information available, businesses can target their marketing efforts to these customers. Accounting is the process of keeping and interpreting financial records. Surveying is a marketing research technique that involves asking customers questions to learn their opinions and the reasons behind those opinions. Industry forecasting involves making predictions of the future prospects for entire industries (e.g., housing, retailing). SOURCE: FM:012 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 172-173]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 58, "question": "A business owner is concerned that some of his employees may be using their company credit cards to make personal purchases. Which data-mining technique should the owner use to review the employees' credit card transactions each month to identify questionable transactions? ", "choices": ["A. Artificial neural networks", "B. Decision trees", "C. Nearest-neighbor method", "D. Dashboards"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Artificial neural networks. Three common data mining techniques are artificial neural networks, decision trees, and the nearest-neighbor method. An artificial neural network is a data-mining technique often used to review financial records to identify possible errors and questionable entries. Decision trees, on the other hand, are commonly used to classify data and build models. The nearest-neighbor method classifies data records according to similar historical data. A dashboard is a data-mining tool that summarizes a business's financial data and presents that information in easy-to-read charts and/or tables. SOURCE: FM:012 SOURCE: Silltow, J. (2006, August 1). Data mining 101: Tools and techniques. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from https://iaonline.theiia.org/data-mining-101-tools-and-techniques  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25  "}, {"number": 59, "question": "Which of the following budgeting software applications tracks a business's cash, interest, and dividends: ", "choices": ["A. Revenue recognition", "B. Workflow management", "C. Inventory planning", "D. Capital expenses"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Revenue recognition. The primary function of budgeting software is to help a business forecast and monitor income and expenses for all of its functions, including sales, promotion, production, payroll, etc. Advanced software can generate different types of reports by integrating financial data from a variety of sources (e.g., cash flows) to help the business make decisions about how to best manage its money. Because an important aspect of budgeting involves knowing how much money the business has at any given time, revenue recognition applications help the business track various sources of revenue. Analyzing the amount of revenue available helps the business determine how to allocate funds to cover its various cash outflows, such as capital expenses, inventory purchases, and operating (e.g., workflow) expenses. SOURCE: FM:013 SOURCE: Centage Corporation. (2001-2014). Compare Budget Maestro budgeting software products. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://centage.com/Products/Editions/Budget-MaestroCompare.asp  "}, {"number": 60, "question": "Lawrence's manager asked him to prepare a visual representation of key performance indicators, including cash flow, liquidity, profitability, and liability. Lawrence should use his company's analytic software to create a(n) ", "choices": ["A. operating agreement.", "B. profit-and-loss statement.", "C. cost standard.", "D. financial scorecard."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Financial scorecard. Many financial analysis applications include the capability to create financial scorecards containing key financial indicators and up-to-date financial information. Cash flow, liquidity, profitability, and liability are examples of metrics that are often included on a financial scorecard. Rather than simply listing data on the scorecard, business employees can use financial analysis applications to develop charts and graphs that present the data in much more readily understandable ways. A profit-andloss statement is a summary of business transactions that shows net profit before and after taxes by analyzing sales, purchases, cost of goods sold, and operating expenses for a specified period. While Lawrence's financial scorecard probably contains information that also appears on the company's profitand-loss statement, the financial scorecard presents additional financial metrics. Cost standards are established specifications used to measure how much a project or product costs. An operating agreement is a written document signed by members of a limited liability partnership or limited liability company that specifies the terms of the business arrangement. SOURCE: FM:014 SOURCE: iDashboards. (2004-2014). Scorecards. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.idashboards.com/Solutions/For-Your-Function/Scorecards.aspx  "}, {"number": 61, "question": "Yvonne is running a query to create, delete, or modify other database objects. What type of query is Yvonne running? ", "choices": ["A. Select", "B. Data-definition", "C. Crosstab", "D. Pass-through"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Data-definition. Running a query in a database is the equivalent of giving the database instructions for working with specific data. Data-definition queries tell the database to create, delete, or modify other database objects. Select and crosstab queries are used to retrieve specific data and present them in reports. A pass-through query tells the database engine to pass the query to a remote database server for processing. SOURCE: FM:015 SOURCE: Microsoft. (2014). Run a query. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://office.microsoft.com/en-us/access-help/run-a-query-HA010077157.aspx  "}, {"number": 62, "question": "Which of the following individuals is an internal user of a business's financial data: ", "choices": ["A. Creditor", "B. Investor", "C. Manager", "D. Tax collector"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Manager. Managers are internal users of a business's financial data. Managers use these data\u2014often in the form of custom-designed financial reports\u2014to control day-to-day operations and to make financial decisions and plans that affect the business. They rely on the data to help them make smart decisions, so it is imperative that the data are reported accurately. Investors, creditors, and government tax collectors also use a business's financial data, but they are all considered to be external users of the data because they do not work for the company. SOURCE: FM:004 SOURCE: Finance Maps of World. (2013, June 26). Users of financial statements. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://finance.mapsofworld.com/financial-report/statement/users.html  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26  "}, {"number": 63, "question": "The primary purpose of the accounting function is to prepare and present relevant financial information, while the primary purpose of the finance function is to ", "choices": ["A. adjust journal entries based on the information provided.", "B. modify accounts receivable based on the information provided.", "C. apply the information to calculate the business's equity.", "D. use the information to make financial decisions."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Use the information to make financial decisions. Accounting is the process of keeping and interpreting financial records. The finance function is responsible for obtaining funds and managing the business's money in ways that achieve the business's goals. The financial records that are maintained and prepared by the accounting function are analyzed by the finance function of the business, which uses the information to make decisions about how to achieve the business's goals. Adjusting journal entries, tracking accounts receivable, and calculating ratios (e.g., equity) are tasks carried out by a business's accounting department. SOURCE: FM:005 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 102-103). South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 64, "question": "Which of the following statements is true about accounting systems: ", "choices": ["A. The managerial accounting system is useful for planning and internal decision making.", "B. The financial accounting system focuses on segments of the company rather than the company\nas a whole.", "C. The government requires all businesses to use the managerial accounting system.", "D. The financial accounting system is used by external audiences, so reporting flexibility is an"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The managerial accounting system is useful for planning and internal decision making. Businesses use managerial accounting systems for internal use. These systems help managers plan, control resources, and make decisions for various segments of the company. For example, the managerial accounting system often involves obtaining financial information to determine if the business should order more goods for inventory or if it should hire additional production workers. The government requires businesses to use the financial accounting system to report their financial positions to external users. The financial accounting system involves reporting financial information in certain ways by applying the generally accepted accounting principles (GAAP). The government does not require businesses to use managerial accounting systems, so the ways in which managerial accounting systems obtain and use information are flexible. SOURCE: FM:006 SOURCE: Ahmed, S. (2014, March 20). Difference between financial and managerial accounting (financial accounting vs. managerial accounting). Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.accounting4management.com/financial_accounting_vs_managerial_accounting.h tm  "}, {"number": 65, "question": "In relation to recording business transactions, a primary difference between the cost and accrual accounting systems is ", "choices": ["A. timing.", "B. scope.", "C. frequency.", "D. complexity."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Timing. The cash accounting system involves recording transactions when the business receives or spends money. Businesses that use the accrual accounting system record their transactions at the time they occur\u2014regardless of when money is exchanged. Scope, frequency, and complexity are not primary differences between the cost and accrual accounting systems. SOURCE: FM:006 SOURCE: Nolo.com. (2014). Cash vs. accrual accounting. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/cash-vs-accrual-accounting-29513.html  "}, {"number": 66, "question": "Which of the following is a tool that enables financial managers to identify changes or trends in production costs by reviewing the same types of data from different periods of time: ", "choices": ["A. Comparative statement", "B. Frequency ratio", "C. Accounts-receivable summary", "D. Sales-transaction log"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Comparative statement. A comparative statement is a financial report that compares the same types of data from different periods of time (e.g., year to year). Comparative statements help businesses identify changes and trends in a business's production activities including production rates, raw-material costs, product quality, etc. Businesses also use comparative reports to evaluate other business activities such as sales, accounts-receivable, and payroll. Frequency is a quantitative measure of the average number of times a target consumer is exposed to an advertising message. SOURCE: FM:008 SOURCE: Tatum, M., & Harris, B. (2014, August 1). What is a comparative statement? Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.wisegeek.com/what-is-a-comparative-statement.htm  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27  "}, {"number": 67, "question": "A creditor carefully examines a business's financial information to determine whether the business has sufficient money to meet its short-term obligations when they come due. In this situation, the creditor is concerned about the business's ", "choices": ["A. profitability.", "B. liquidity.", "C. efficiency.", "D. investment return."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Liquidity. The creditor wants to know that the business has sufficient cash on hand to meet its obligations. If the creditor determines that the business is unable to meet its current short-term obligations, the creditor most likely will deny the credit request. Profitability is concerned with whether the business is making a profit and whether it's sufficient to maintain business operations. Efficiency focuses on whether the business is making the best use of its resources. Investment return lets investors and creditors know what return they can expect to get from a business. SOURCE: FM:009 SOURCE: Riley, J. (2012, September 23). Accounting ratios\u2014Introduction to ratio analysis. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://tutor2u.net/business/accounts/ratio_analysis.htm  "}, {"number": 68, "question": "Susan wants to obtain a loan to purchase business equipment. She calls different banks to obtain information about the interest rates and the types of loans available, so she can determine which bank is the best option. Susan is analyzing the financial information that she is collecting to ", "choices": ["A. correct inaccurate financial data.", "B. guide her decision making.", "C. determine business profitability.", "D. solve a business problem."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Guide her decision making. Many businesspeople analyze financial data to make business decisions, such as obtaining a loan with the best interest rates and payment plans. Susan is not analyzing the information to correct inaccurate data, nor is she trying to determine her business's profitability. There isn't enough information available to determine if Susan is trying to solve a business problem. SOURCE: FM:010 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (pp. 342-343). Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 69, "question": "The accounting treatment of capital expenditures should be __________ over multiple reporting periods. ", "choices": ["A. hedged", "B. flexible", "C. consistent", "D. callable"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Consistent. An accounting treatment is a set of rules that specifies how to handle specific accounts and transactions such as capital expenditures. The accounting treatment of like items should be consistent within each reporting period and from one reporting period to the next. If a company does not treat a particular account or type of transaction consistently from period to period or year to year, the data become incomparable, less meaningful, and possibly even useless to users of the company's financial information. If investors or financial experts analyze the company's financial data and discover that the accounting treatment of capital expenditures varies\u2014and if the company has no valid explanation for not treating these expenditures the same way during different reporting periods\u2014the investors and financial analysts may avoid investing in that particular company. Therefore, it is usually in a company's best interest to be consistent in its accounting treatment of different accounts and transactions. Accounting treatment of capital expenditures should not be flexible, hedged, or callable over multiple reporting periods. SOURCE: FM:010 SOURCE: Shanker, S. (n.d.). Capital expenditure accounting treatment. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.ehow.com/about_7285561_capital-expenditure-accounting-treatment.html  "}, {"number": 70, "question": "Group orientation sessions for new employees are very important because they ", "choices": ["A. explain the duties of each job.", "B. help to motivate employees.", "C. encourage organizational input.", "D. provide in-depth training."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Help to motivate employees. A good orientation program makes new employees feel welcome, gives them an overview of the business, and helps to motivate them to do their best. Orientation often includes giving the new workers a handbook so that they have a copy of the information being presented. The primary purpose of an orientation session is to provide general information; it is not used to discuss specific job duties, provide in-depth training, or solicit input about organizational processes. SOURCE: HR:360 SOURCE: Noe, R.A., Hollenbeck, J.R., Gerhart, B., & Wright, P.M. (2010). Human resource management: Gaining a competitive advantage (7th ed.) [pp. 333-335]. New York: McGrawHill/Irwin.  "}, {"number": 71, "question": "What does determining the target market's buying behavior involve? ", "choices": ["A. Finding out where the market is located", "B. Finding out what the market will purchase", "C. Finding out how the market is organized", "D. Finding out why the market exists"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Finding out what the market will purchase. One aspect of determining the target market's buying behavior involves finding out what the market will purchase. Businesses need to know what the market wants in order to provide those products. If the target market does not want or need a business's products, the market will not buy even if the products are readily available and competitively priced. Finding out where the market is located, how the market is organized, and why the market exists are part of determining the target market rather than the target market's buying behavior. SOURCE: MK:014 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 48, 302, 825). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28  "}, {"number": 72, "question": "Todd created a graphic organizer to illustrate his business's quality-control processes. He used a combination of pictures, graphs, and simple statements to sequentially present the information. What did Todd develop? ", "choices": ["A. Proposal", "B. Outline", "C. Draft", "D. Storyboard"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Storyboard. Business professionals sometimes use graphic organizers to illustrate certain processes or to describe a problem and its solution. A storyboard uses a combination of pictures, graphs, and simple statements to present information in a sequential order. An outline is a general plan giving only the main points of a topic. A draft is the preliminary version of a piece of writing. A proposal is a plan or suggestion. Outlines, drafts, and proposals are not graphic organizers. SOURCE: NF:080 SOURCE: Chandel, T. (n.d.). Business analysis tools: Storyboards. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://businessanalyst.tarunchandel.com/2008/09/business-analysis-tools-storyboards.html  "}, {"number": 73, "question": "Carson is a staff accountant, and he needs to look at last year's tax return. However, he can't find it anywhere. Which information management guideline is not being followed in this situation? ", "choices": ["A. Set and consistently follow organizational information management practices.", "B. Make sure that information is accurate.", "C. Make sure that information is retrievable.", "D. Prioritize information management needs according to business needs."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Make sure that information is retrievable. When Carson is unable to find last year's tax return when he needs it, information is not retrievable. This will slow down Carson's productivity on the job. The tax return may or may not be accurate. Setting and following organizational practices and prioritizing according to business needs may or may not relate to Carson's information not being retrievable. SOURCE: NF:110 SOURCE: NF LAP 3\u2014In the Know (Nature of Information Management)  "}, {"number": 74, "question": "What is the primary function of the Random Access Memory (RAM) component of a computer? ", "choices": ["A. Serves as a temporary holding area for files and programs", "B. Reads the computer code that provide visual effects", "C. Stores data and programs permanently", "D. Enables the user to apply point-and-click commands"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Serves as a temporary holding area for files and programs. Random Access Memory or RAM is a temporary workspace that stores data and programs that the user is actively using. A computer containing a lot of RAM enables users to open and work on several files and programs at one time. When the user has finished working with a file or program, s/he saves or stores the information permanently on the hard drive. The video card is a component of the system that converts code so the user can view items on the computer monitor. The computer mouse is a tool that enables computer users to enter commands. SOURCE: NF:084 SOURCE: Basic computer components. (n.d.). Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://basis-computerhardware-knowledge.blogspot.com/2009/01/basic-computer-components.html  "}, {"number": 75, "question": "Which of the following demonstrates the correct method to ensure that all words in a phrase are included in a web search: ", "choices": ["A. (Discipline is the most important part of success)", "B. [There is no tree that the wind has not shaken]", "C. 'To be or not to be'", "D. \"Confidence in itself is the secret of success\""], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "\"Confidence in itself is the secret of success.\" Many search engines eliminate common words (e.g., the, of, a) as the search is conducted because the words slow down the search process. In addition, the inclusion of common words generally does not improve search result accuracy. When it is necessary to include all words in a search, enclose the phrase in double quotation marks. Search engines do not generally recognize single quotation marks, brackets, or parenthesis as designations to include all words in a web search. SOURCE: NF:006 SOURCE: Google. (2014). Search operators. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from https://support.google.com/websearch/answer/136861  "}, {"number": 76, "question": "Most businesses maintain records about what customers are buying and how much they are spending in order to ", "choices": ["A. analyze the information.", "B. plan an inventory count.", "C. offer quality service.", "D. develop a quality environment."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Analyze the information. Most businesses maintain customer records that contain information about what customers are buying, when they are buying, and how much they are spending. By analyzing this information, businesses are able to plan future sales and obtain the products that will appeal to customers and encourage them to buy. Without this type of information, businesses might have no idea what customers will want to buy in the future, or how much they will be willing to spend. Businesses do not maintain records about what customers are buying and how much they are spending in order to plan an inventory count, offer quality service, or develop a quality environment. SOURCE: NF:002 SOURCE: Burrow, J.L. (2012). Marketing (3rd ed.) [pp. 128-130]. Mason, OH: South-Western, Cengage Learning.  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29  "}, {"number": 77, "question": "Which of the following is a business trend that affects all countries: ", "choices": ["A. Decreased inflation", "B. Socialism", "C. Increased regulation", "D. Globalization"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Globalization. A trend is the general direction in which people or events are moving. Globalization is the rapid and unimpeded flow of capital, labor, and ideas across national borders. Several factors influence globalization, including technological advancements (e.g., Internet) and the various trade agreements (e.g., NAFTA) that have decreased trade regulations. The opening of trade in countries, such as India and China, which has permitted more foreign businesses to operate within their borders, has also affected globalization. Socialism is an economic system rather than a trend. Inflation is an economic factor that often affects trends. SOURCE: NF:013 SOURCE: Gitman, L.J., & McDaniel, C. (2008). The future of business: The essentials (3rd ed.) [pp. 229-230]. Mason, OH; Thomson/South-Western.  "}, {"number": 78, "question": "A firm's environmental scan reveals that a country is on the brink of civil war, which would affect the firm's ability to do business in the country. This is an example of a(n) __________ consideration. ", "choices": ["A. political", "B. economic", "C. cultural", "D. regulatory"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Political. The purpose of an environmental scan is to determine what conditions are affecting the business environment. The environmental scan helps the business to determine what, if any, changes it needs to make, so it remains competitive in the marketplace. Political considerations are important because government changes, such as a civil war or the presidential elections, could indicate the possibility of other changes that might affect a specific country's business environment, including economic, cultural, and regulatory changes. SOURCE: NF:015 SOURCE: Kurtz, D. (2013). Contemporary marketing: 2013 edition (p. 65). Mason, OH: South-Western, Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 79, "question": "Which of the following forms of technology is most useful in operations: ", "choices": ["A. Smart phones", "B. E-readers", "C. Assistive technology", "D. Computer-aided design"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Computer-aided design. Computer-aided design is very useful in operations. Designing and testing products in the virtual world before trying them out in the real world can save companies a lot of time and money. Using computer software, a company can design, test, and redesign a product many times over until it's ready for production\u2014all without wasting unnecessary resources. Assistive technology is any device that enables people with disabilities to participate fully in the workplace. The term is too broad to determine whether it would be useful in operations. E-readers are devices that enable people to download electronic books. While smart phones might also be useful in operations, computer-aided design stands out as the most useful and specific technology to enhance this business function. SOURCE: OP:189 SOURCE: OP LAP 3\u2014Smooth Operations (Nature of Operations)  "}, {"number": 80, "question": "What do bond yields typically do during an economic expansion? ", "choices": ["A. Drop to near zero", "B. Gradually decrease", "C. Increase", "D. Remain unchanged"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Increase. During an economic expansion, production, employment, income, sales, the demand for money, and interest rates rapidly increase. As a result, businesses borrow more money (at higher rates) to expand their operations. And, when businesses borrow more at higher interest rates, bond yields go up. SOURCE: FI:574 SOURCE: Peter Dag and Associates, Inc. (n.d.). Profitable relationships between economic indicators and financial markets. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.peterdag.com/s_files/O0Yp4aNtyV9X.pdf  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 30  "}, {"number": 81, "question": "What is the advantage to a business that installs external surveillance cameras in prominent locations around its property? ", "choices": ["A. Eliminates the need to install alarms", "B. Reduces the risk of extortion", "C. Discourages attempted burglaries", "D. Prevents armed robberies"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Discourages attempted burglaries. When would-be burglars see surveillance cameras in several locations around a business, they are less likely to attempt to break in because they will be videotaped or photographed by the cameras. When the burglars' actions are taped, law enforcement agencies are more likely to identify and arrest them. Although surveillance cameras don't prevent all burglaries or robberies, they can often deter these activities. Most businesses use a combination of security measures to secure their facilities, including door and window locks and different types of alarm systems. Businesses need and use different types of alarm systems, such as fire alarms or smoke detectors, which are often required by law. Therefore, the use of surveillance cameras does not eliminate the need for alarm systems. Extortion is blackmail and would not necessarily be impacted by surveillance cameras. SOURCE: OP:013 SOURCE: Kimiecik, R.C., & Thomas, C. (2006). Loss prevention in the retail business (p. 56). Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley & Sons.  "}, {"number": 82, "question": "It is important for a business to evaluate the financial condition of a potential vendor during the vendorselection process to assess the ", "choices": ["A. risk levels of doing business with the vendor.", "B. reliability of the products that the vendor carries.", "C. vendor's levels of customer service.", "D. vendor's required lead times."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Risk levels of doing business with the vendor. If a vendor is not financially stable, there is a risk that the vendor may not have the resources to meet the business's needs. And, if the vendor's financial condition is extremely poor, the vendor may go out of business. A lack of financial resources may affect the vendor's products, its level of customer services, and its lead times. SOURCE: OP:161 SOURCE: Monczka, R.M., Handfield, R.B., Giunipero, L.C., & Patterson, J.L. (2009). Purchasing and supply chain management (4th ed.) [pp. 252-253]. South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 83, "question": "Which of the following is a production activity: ", "choices": ["A. Receiving", "B. Advertising", "C. Scheduling", "D. Marketing"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Scheduling. Scheduling is the production activity that establishes the timetable to be followed in production. Businesses establish schedules in order to have the necessary raw materials and the right number of employees on hand to produce the goods. Scheduling helps businesses to produce the goods that customers need and have those goods available when customers want them. Marketing is the process of planning and executing the conception, pricing, promotion, and distribution of ideas, goods, and services to create exchanges that satisfy individual and organizational objectives. Advertising is any paid form of nonpersonal presentation of ideas, goods, or services. Receiving is the acceptance of a shipment of goods. SOURCE: OP:017 SOURCE: OP LAP 4\u2014Can You Make It? (Nature of Production)  "}, {"number": 84, "question": "\u201cBig Q\u201d focuses on ", "choices": ["A. improving factory conditions.", "B. exceeding customer expectations.", "C. conforming to specifications.", "D. designing and developing products."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Exceeding customer expectations. \u201cBig Q\u201d focuses on ingraining quality into every aspect of the organization to meet and exceed customer expectations. \u201cLittle Q\u201d focuses on conforming to specifications. Neither approach to quality management specifically focuses on improving factory conditions or designing and developing products, although those may certainly be important goals of a quality-management system. SOURCE: OP:163 SOURCE: OP LAP 8\u2014Take Control (Quality-Control Measures)  "}, {"number": 85, "question": "One of the major functions of business maintenance is to ", "choices": ["A. prevent fraudulent behavior.", "B. motivate employees.", "C. create a favorable impression.", "D. guarantee the business's success."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Create a favorable impression. The overall impression customers receive as a result of a business's appearance influences their buying behavior. Therefore, performing routine housekeeping duties (e.g., dusting and vacuuming) and maintaining the condition of the equipment, furniture, displays, and fixtures help a business create a good impression. The primary reason for conducting maintenance activities is not to motivate employees or prevent fraudulent behavior. Performing maintenance activities cannot guarantee the success of the business. SOURCE: OP:032 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 433). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 31  "}, {"number": 86, "question": "An overall purpose of establishing goals is to increase your chances of ", "choices": ["A. achieving immediate success.", "B. satisfying your wants.", "C. enlarging your income.", "D. avoiding making mistakes."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Satisfying your wants. Clear, meaningful goals can also serve as guidelines and help you make better decisions. Enlarging your income might be a personal goal. Establishing goals cannot guarantee immediate success or the avoidance of mistakes. SOURCE: PD:018 SOURCE: PD LAP 16\u2014Go for the Goal (Goal Setting)  "}, {"number": 87, "question": "Which type of business is known for often being the most innovative? ", "choices": ["A. Old businesses", "B. Small businesses", "C. New businesses", "D. Large businesses"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Small businesses. Although many people assume that large businesses are more innovative, innovations often come from small businesses. In fact, some studies show that small entrepreneurial companies create twice as many innovations as large companies. The age of a business does not necessarily affect its innovative abilities. SOURCE: PD:126 SOURCE: PD LAP 18\u2014Ideas in Action (Innovation Skills)  "}, {"number": 88, "question": "The essence of time management is to ", "choices": ["A. eliminate the need to prioritize activities.", "B. control events in order to accomplish priorities.", "C. focus on spreading work over a period of time.", "D. set a fixed schedule and follow it."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Control events in order to accomplish priorities. All people need to learn how to manage their time. They need to maintain control over the events in their lives so that there is a balance among those events. This involves planning and organizing their personal and professional activities. Time management involves prioritizing activities, but it does not mean setting a fixed schedule and never deviating. Schedules should have some flexibility built in to take care of unexpected events. Time management focuses on making the best use of time rather than on spreading work over a period of time. SOURCE: PD:019 SOURCE: PD LAP 1\u2014About Time (Time Management)  "}, {"number": 89, "question": "Which of the following is an example of an employee who is meeting his/her employer's expectations: ", "choices": ["A. Tom spends the first half hour of the workday chatting with Kate.", "B. Allison focuses on her work tasks so she can meet her deadlines.", "C. Rachel sends a text message to her roommate during a meeting.", "D. Calvin tells a customer about his issues with a difficult coworker."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Allison focuses on her work tasks so she can meet her deadlines. Businesses have basic expectations regarding their employees' behavior in the workplace. Employers expect employees to arrive at work on time; perform their work accurately and efficiently; be honest; and exhibit respect for coworkers, customers, and company property. Because Allison is focused on her work and strives to meet her deadlines, she is meeting her employer's expectations. Engaging in idle chitchat and texting during a meeting are disrespectful actions that waste the company's time and money. Confiding in a customer about problems with coworkers is inappropriate behavior. SOURCE: PD:020 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed) [pp. 94-97]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 90, "question": "Job seekers can often find out about local employment opportunities by accessing a business's ", "choices": ["A. employee newsletter.", "B. website.", "C. online catalog.", "D. annual report."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Website. Many companies post their job openings on their websites. In most situations, a business has a set of procedures for applicants to follow when they apply for jobs online. Some businesses allow job seekers the ability to set up an account, so they can track and check the status of their applications and receive email updates about new job openings. Employee newsletters do not always contain information about current job openings. Online catalogs provide information about the business's goods and services. Annual reports do not contain information about job openings. SOURCE: PD:026 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (p. 117). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 91, "question": "After a job interview, an applicant should prepare a follow-up letter that ", "choices": ["A. is long and detailed.", "B. is short and typed.", "C. includes a r\u00e9sum\u00e9.", "D. contains a photo."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Is short and typed. A follow-up letter after a job interview should be short and to the point. The purpose is to briefly thank the interviewer. Typed letters are preferred. Follow-up letters do not contain a photo or another r\u00e9sum\u00e9. They should not be long and detailed. SOURCE: PD:029 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 199-201). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 32  "}, {"number": 92, "question": "Which of the following is an example of the impact of technology on the financial-services industry: ", "choices": ["A. Blurring the lines between banking, insurance, and investments", "B. More walk-in bank customers", "C. Greater demand for investment professionals", "D. Rising concern about fraud and identity theft"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Rising concern about fraud and identity theft. One of the impacts of technology on the financial-services industry is rising concern about fraud and identity theft since so many financial products and services are now bought and sold online. Encryption technology helps guard against fraud and theft. Banks have fewer walk-in customers when they offer online banking. Blurred lines between the banking, insurance, and investment industries is the result of deregulation. Greater demand for investment professionals is the result of changing demographics. SOURCE: PD:152 SOURCE: PD LAP 20\u2014Career Opportunities in Finance  "}, {"number": 93, "question": "After passing the General Securities Registered Representative Examination or the Canadian Securities Course exam, a businessperson obtains licensure or certification that allows him/her to work as a(n) ", "choices": ["A. estate planner.", "B. accountant.", "C. underwriter.", "D. stockbroker."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Stockbroker. Stockbrokers are required to obtain a license to trade securities. To obtain the license, stockbrokers must take and pass the General Securities Registered Representative Examination in the United States. In Canada, individuals must pass the Canadian Securities Course (CSC) exam to work as a stockbroker. Exam names vary by country, but in the United States, accountants obtain the Certified Public Accountant (CPA) certification; insurance underwriters obtain the Chartered Life Underwriter (CLU) certification; and estate planners obtain the Accredited Estate Planner (AEP) certification. SOURCE: PD:082 SOURCE: Morgan, E. (2006, August 21). How to become a stock broker. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://ezinearticles.com/?How-To-Become-A-Stock-Broker&id=275927  "}, {"number": 94, "question": "Which of the following would afford finance professionals the best opportunity to build long-lasting relationships with other finance professionals: ", "choices": ["A. Regularly attending trade shows for the finance industry", "B. Actively participating in a local professional association for the finance industry", "C. Occasionally auditing classes at a local postsecondary institution", "D. Actively attending meetings sponsored by the local chamber of commerce"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Actively participating in a local professional association for the finance industry. Active participation in a professional organization specific to the finance industry affords finance professionals the opportunity to serve on committees, hold offices, and attend seminars with other local finance professionals. This involvement may result in a long-term professional relationship for the participants. Regularly attending trade shows for the finance industry is more likely to result in short-term relationships. Insufficient information is provided to determine whether the audited classes are for professionals in finance. Actively attending chamber of commerce meetings gives finance professionals the opportunity to develop professional relationships with people employed in a variety of industries\u2014not necessarily with other finance professionals. SOURCE: PD:153 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed) [p. 265]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 95, "question": "To build professional relationships, Brynn serves on several trade association committees, co-authors articles with other finance professionals to publish in the local newspaper, and treats business contacts to dinner or golf. These activities are forms of ", "choices": ["A. networking.", "B. cooperating.", "C. advertising.", "D. up-selling."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Networking. Networking involves connecting with individuals who might help accomplish career and professional goals. By serving on trade association committees, co-authoring articles for publication, and treating business contacts to dinner or golf, Brynn creates situations in which she has the opportunity to get to know other professionals and possibly build relationships that will be beneficial for everyone involved. Cooperating with others shows a willingness to work together to resolve differences or achieve common goals. Although Brynn is cooperating with others while carrying out these activities, her ultimate goal is to build a network of business professionals who can help her to achieve her career goals. Advertising is any paid form of nonpersonal presentation of ideas, images, goods, or services. Up-selling is a sales technique in which a salesperson suggests a higher priced product than the one originally requested by the customer. SOURCE: PD:153 SOURCE: Hoban, S. (n.d.). Building business relationships. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://www.ccim.com/cire-magazine/articles/building-business-relationships  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 33  "}, {"number": 96, "question": "Which of the following risks might result from ethical misconduct: ", "choices": ["A. Decreased whistle-blowing", "B. Decreased company value", "C. Increased employee support of the company", "D. Increased positive publicity"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Decreased company value. Once word spreads about the business's unethical behavior, investors will probably withdraw their financial support of the business. This would cause the company's value to decrease. With unethical business behavior, the business can expect whistle-blowing to increase because employees have more activities that they could report. Employees' support for the company is likely to decrease, along with their productivity. The publicity that appears in the media will be negative, not positive. SOURCE: RM:041 SOURCE: Ebersole, G. (2007, January 23). Business ethics must be presented, preserved, and promoted. Retrieved August 14, 2014, from http://ezinearticles.com/?id=427951&BusinessEthics-Must-Be-Presented%2C-Preserved-and-Promoted=  "}, {"number": 97, "question": "To secure confidential financial data that are transmitted through the Internet, businesses often use ", "choices": ["A. cross-platform technology.", "B. encryption techniques.", "C. bots.", "D. debuggers."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Encryption techniques. Risk management is a business activity that involves implementing activities to limit business losses. One way that businesses control security risks is by using encryption to prevent unauthorized individuals (e.g., hackers) from obtaining confidential financial data. Encryption is the process of transforming information into a code so that only the recipient can read it. A bot is a program that scans the Web looking for information changes. Cross-platform technology refers to computer applications that can run on different platforms, such as Windows and Macintosh. Debuggers are computer programs that help programmers identify flaws or \"bugs\" in a computer program. SOURCE: RM:042 SOURCE: Miles, J.E., & Dolce, C. (2006). E-Commerce (pp. 125-126). New York: Glencoe/McGrawHill.  "}, {"number": 98, "question": "If an accounting firm deliberately conceals information about a client's financial status, the government may charge the business with ", "choices": ["A. expropriation.", "B. obstruction of justice.", "C. breach of contract.", "D. substantiation."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Obstruction of justice. Obstruction of justice is a legal penalty that applies to individuals or businesses that hide important information from law enforcement agencies, such as concealing a client's questionable financial data. If evidence indicates that unethical or illegal business practices have obstructed a criminal investigation, the business could be fined, and the employees concealing the information could face imprisonment. A public scandal could severely tarnish a business's reputation, as in the case of the Arthur Andersen accounting firm and its affiliation with Enron. Expropriation is the act of government taking over private property. Breach of contract involves breaking the terms of a legal agreement. Substantiate means to provide proof or evidence of something. SOURCE: RM:043 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., Thill, J.V., & Mescon, M.H. (2007). Excellence in business (3rd ed.) [pp. 524-526, 547]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson.  "}, {"number": 99, "question": "The primary reason that firms must take steps to control their levels of business risk is to ", "choices": ["A. increase their financial liability levels.", "B. increase their visibility in the market.", "C. contribute to the well-being of society.", "D. reduce the chance of financial losses."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Reduce the chance of financial losses. Because risk involves the possibility of loss, businesses must be diligent to control their levels of risk. Businesses can experience financial losses in all areas of the business\u2014from product recalls and poor hiring selections to poor credit policies and workplace injuries. Businesses can control their various risks by implementing appropriate business policies, training employees, and acquiring adequate insurance coverage. By controlling financial risk, businesses can limit their debt (liabilities). When businesses have low debt, they increase the potential to earn profit, which contributes to the well-being of society. Businesses increase their visibility in the market in different ways (positive and negative) and are not always related to controlling their levels of risk. SOURCE: RM:058 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 326). Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  SAMPLE FINANCE CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 34  "}, {"number": 100, "question": "Which of the following is an uninsurable external risk to businesses: ", "choices": ["A. Inventory", "B. Tax increases", "C. Personal injury", "D. Natural disasters"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Tax increases. Businesses cannot control when and by how much a government may increase taxes, which are uninsurable. A business's inventory is insurable. Liability insurance can be purchased to transfer the business's risks related to the potential injuries of its employees and customers. Natural disasters such as fire, tornados, and earthquakes are insurable risks. SOURCE: RM:058 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., Thill, J.V., & Mescon, M.H. (2007). Excellence in business (3rd ed.) [p. A-14]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall"}]}